<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Cinephile | HarveyNick]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/cinephile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-06T00:02:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A couple more...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/07/27/a-couple-more/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-27T22:02:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/07/27/a-couple-more</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Further to my last post, here's a couple more films which caught my eye, though one of them is a ways off yet.</p>

<p>Faster (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/independent/faster/">trailer</a>) - I will go and see Dwayne Johnson in any film which doesn't involve him wearing a tutu or fairy wings. Perhaps even then, and you can quote me on that. The guy has more charisma and physical presence than just about everyone else out there, and is (as far as I'm concerned) always good value for money, regardless of the quality of the actual film. Frankly, the guy should be a much bigger start than he is. That he's in an indie revenge flick makes me very happy indeed. Also: great trailer.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>Sucker Punch (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/wb/suckerpunch/">trailer</a>) - Zack Snyder is another one of those directors who's work I would go sight unseen. Though Watchmen wasn't quite the film I wanted it to be, I still enjoyed the hell out of it and I loved his two previous films (300 and Dawn of the Dead). This is a director who makes <em>cinema</em> and every frame of it is absolutely, stunningly beautiful. Evidence so far suggests that he actually works pretty well with actors and knows how to handle a plot, also, which is nice (Micheal Bay, take note). This is his first time working with an original property, so I guess we'll have to see how it goes. Oh yeah, it also seems to have nazis, dragons, sword wielding burlesque girls, Zeppelins, spaceships and mini gun toting giant samurai demons... and something tells me that's not the half of it...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking Forwards]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/07/18/looking-forwards/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-18T17:02:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/07/18/looking-forwards</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Cineworld unlimited card is a wonderful thing, especially given that I no longer have a student card (I am still a student, technically. Don't ask). It encourages you to take a much more "what the hell," type attitude to heading to the cinema, and I love me some cinema. That being the case, I thought I'd write a (probably) quick post covering the films coming out this year that I'm pretty certain I'll be going to see.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So, in particular order (aside from the one in which they occurred to me):</p>

<p>Inception (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/wb/inception/">trailer</a>) - There are some director's who pretty much guarente I'll go see a film. Christopher Nolan is one of them. Likewise, there are some actor's who pretty much guarente I'll go and see a film. Ellen Page is one of them. Also: this film look awesome.</p>

<p>The Social Network (<a href="http://movies.yahoo.com/premieres/20889647/standardformat">trailer</a>) - David Fincher is another one of the directors who almost guarantees I'll go see a film. Aaron Sorkin is a writer who pretty much guarantees I'll go see a film. I didn't think I was interested in a film about Facebook, but it turns out that I really, really am. Watch the trailer.</p>

<p>Machete (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/fox/machete/">trailer</a>) - I didn't think much of Death Proof, but I loved me some Planet Terror, and this looks like it's coming from the same headspace.</p>

<p>Tron Legacy (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/disney/tronlegacy/">trailer</a>) - I think I might have already mentioned this one.</p>

<p>The Town (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/wb/thetown/">trailer</a>) - Ben Affleck might be a genius. Perhaps you didn't know that. You might assume that it was Matt Daemon who did most of the heavy lifting when it came to writing Good Will Hunting. But did you go see Gone Baby Gone? Because he wrote (well, adapted) and directed that and it was <em>spectacular</em>. I'm hoping he's done it again.</p>

<p>The Expendables (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/lions_gate/theexpendables/">trailer</a>) - A cast made up almost entirely of action legends? Written and directed by the man who brought us Rambo? I'm there. If you didn't watch Rambo (the most recent one), perhaps you should. It is incredibly, unflinchingly violent. But it's a film about violence and you might be surprised by how much it has to say.</p>

<p>Scott Pilgrim vs. The World (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/universal/scottpilgrimvstheworld/">trailer</a>) - I love it. I love the style. I love the sense of humour. I love the ideas. I'll be very surprised I don't giggle with glee all the way through this one.<br/>
R.E.D. (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/summit/red/">trailer</a>) - I'm not even going to try explaining this one. Just watch the trailer.</p>

<p>Knight and Day (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/fox/knightandday/">trailer</a>) - I don't know about you, but I mostly go to the cinema to be entertained. This looks like it will be super entertaining. Side note: I might not like Tom Cruise on a person, but I don't think I've ever disliked him in a film.</p>

<p>The Green Hornet (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/sony_pictures/thegreenhornet/">trailer</a>) - This looks all kinds of silly. These ingredients (superhero + martial arts + star of Knocked Up + director of Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind) should not go together. But I bet the first person to eat a peanut butter and jam sandwich said the same thing.</p>

<p>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hollows (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/wb/harrypotterandthedeathlyhallows/">trailer</a>) - I expect to be disappointed by this one. I have been by every other one of these films. But that doesn't mean I didn't enjoy them (except the second one). I'm looking forward to the conclusion of the first set of adaptations of these books.</p>

<p>There are more, but that'll do for now. What do you guys think? Any of these look good? Any look great? Any look awful? Anything you're particularly looking forward to?</p>

<p>As a slight aside, I'm also HarveyNick on Tumblr and Twitter, and I'm thinking of moving the 15 words or less film review to Tumblr instead of here, as it seems to fit better. Can anyone think of a reason I shouldn't (it'll still get cross posted to Facebook).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
