<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: The Girl Who Played With Fire | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://harveynick.com/blog/tags/the-girl-who-played-with-fire/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-28T17:11:56+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Can't Recommend Highly Enough]]></title>
    <link href="http://harveynick.com/blog/2009/09/20/just-cant-recommend-highly-enough/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-20T18:25:45+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://harveynick.com/blog/2009/09/20/just-cant-recommend-highly-enough</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I finished &ldquo;The Girl Who Played With Fire&rdquo;, translated by Reg Keeland from the swedish book of the same name by Stieg Larsson. It&rsquo;s the sequel to &lsquo;The Girl With the Dragon Tattoo" (which is called &ldquo;Men Who Hate Women&rdquo; in the original swedish), and I really can&rsquo;t recommend the pair of them highly enough (as you might have guessed from the title of this blog post).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I picked the first book up as the combination of the titular character being described as &ldquo;an expert computer hacker&rdquo; and the synopsis on the back cover put me in mind of Neil Stephenson&rsquo;s &ldquo;Cryptonomicon&rdquo;, not only one of my favourite books but also an outright work of genius, in my opinion. I would describe "Cryptonomicon" as recommended reading if you&rsquo;re the sort of person who breaths oxygen and walks upright, if you work with computers I&rsquo;d say it verges on being <em>required</em> reading. Since Stephenson lost the plot more recently (in my opinion, that is; I didn&rsquo;t make it more than half way through &ldquo;Quicksilver&rdquo; before giving up in pained frustration) there has been a rather large cyber-fiction based hole in my world. &ldquo;&hellip;Dragon Tattoo&rdquo; seems as though it might be poised to fill it.</p>

<p>In fact it did not. It&rsquo;s a different beast all together. A slow burning and wonderful one, written (and translated) with great skill and care. Both books are very powerful reads, laced with a hatred of misogyny and criticism of a system which doesn&rsquo;t do nearly enough to prevent it. It&rsquo;s also a ripping great yarn of a mystery, full of strong male <em>and</em> female characters. Nominally, the books are the first two parts of a trilogy. In fact Larsson planned ten books and left an unfinished fourth manuscript together with outlines for books five and six when he died. I&rsquo;m waiting with bated breath for the release of the third book. I just hope it ties things up reasonably well and so won&rsquo;t leave me too curious about the contents of book I&rsquo;ll never be able to read.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
