<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[HarveyNick]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-03T23:58:47+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WoW oh WoW]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/08/wow-oh-wow/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-08T12:40:51+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/08/wow-oh-wow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sooner or later, most people go looking for a bit of escapism every once in a while. There&#8217;s definitely a spectrum of how far people like to escape. Some can&#8217;t stand anything which steps outside the bounds of the possible, others practically require spaceships and dragons to co-exist with emotionally retarded vampires. Likewise, some people look to books for their diversions, some theatre, radio, television or cinema. Some people play computer games or one sort of another. No one is saying that everyone, or indeed anyone, has make a specific and binding choice, though. You can watch a movie about the emotional and theological struggle of gay monks one evening, read a couple of chapters of a book about an adolescent wizard immediately before bed, and take on the role of a greek god laying waste to&#8230; well&#8230; everything the next day.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The point of my new project (Clockwork Aphid), when you get right down to it, has to do with my own frustrations with a certain kind of computer game. Specifically: the ones I&#8217;m going to lump together under the moniker &#8220;virtual worlds&#8221;. There are a lot of them out there, and I can&#8217;t claim to have tried them all, but I have had a play with a couple of the major ones and that&#8217;s what I want to talk about today.</p>

<p>Where to start, though? I&#8217;ve gone backwards and forwards about this quite a bit and come to the conclusion that I should probably start at the top. The top in this case being the brute, the sprawling 500 lb gorilla that actually accounts for almost 10% of the revenues of the US gaming industry: World of Warcraft, or WoW, to give it its not exactly modest acronym. What we&#8217;re talking about here is not just a virtual world, but a massively multi-player online role playing game, or MMORPG. Let&#8217;s examine the meaning of this working backwards through the words:</p>

<ul>
<li>Game - this is something you play, for fun.</li>
<li>Role playing - it contains some component of playing a role different to that of your everyday life. All games do this to a greater or lesser extent, but the difference here is that your <em>character&#8217;s</em> own personality and skills have more relevance to the gameplay than your own.</li>
<li>Online - the game is played over the Internet.</li>
<li>Multi-player - the game is played simultaneously by multiple people.</li>
<li>Massively - the &#8220;multiple people&#8221; playing the game can number in the thousands.</li>
</ul>


<p>WoW is set in an essentially Tolkenesque fantasy world populated by humans, dwarfs and elves, acting more or less as you&#8217;d expect them to had you read or seen the Lord of the Rings. There are other races: Orcs, trolls, undead, gnomes, undead, who are a little more stylised. There&#8217;s quite a bit of steam punk and tribal culture in places. That&#8217;s not the point though. The point, as in any game, is the question &#8220;what does the user do?&#8221; and the answer in this case is:</p>

<p>The user takes on the role of one of a member of one of these races, with a particular profession and proceeds to battle their way through the world, fighting hostile elements and performing quests in order to gain &#8220;experience&#8221; and improve their character. They can also join forces with other players to take on quests; in fact this is practically required in some cases.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve spent a bit of time playing WoW and frankly it can be a lot of fun. The world is HUGE and exploring it can be very enjoyable. There&#8217;s also a genuine sense of achievement to be gained from &#8220;levelling up&#8221; your character. Most of the time. Which brings me to the first frustration: the grind. A lot of the time you just find yourself killing monster, after monster, after monster. This is partly because a large number of the quests (which are handed out by non-player characters, or NPCs, with large yellow exclamation points above their heads) sound like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;Oh no! &lt;insert description of peril>! Please help us! Kill &lt;insert number> of &lt;insert name of monster responsible for this peril>&#8221;</p></blockquote>

<p>Or even worse and with a more concrete example:</p>

<blockquote><p>&#8220;Please bring me 10 giant spider legs.&#8221;</p></blockquote>

<p>The problem here being that against all conventional logic, you might only get a giant spider leg for every third giant spider you kill. As you may have gathered, they don&#8217;t call it the grind because it&#8217;s fun.</p>

<p>The next frustration is that you don&#8217;t actually affect the world. You do the townsfolk a good turn by depleting the number of bandits besieging the town, but this changes nothing. Other players come along and do the exact same quest time after time after, because the bandits simply reappear a couple of minutes after you take them down. So, when you do the quest to take out the leader of the bandits, you arrive to find that a queue has formed. The first person kills him, the others wait for him to reappear and do the same. It sort of breaks the illusion of the game. More annoying still: you&#8217;ve been waiting patiently for your turn, but some git comes running in and kills him first. Most annoyingly, to my mind is&#8230; Well&#8230; Let me give you an anecdotal example:</p>

<p>I was playing as a rogue, which is a nice way of saying thief/assassin, and had been given a quest to recover a particular object from a beach. Needless to say, the beach turned out to be crawling with monsters. So I set about luring them away one by one, depleting their numbers so I could get my trophy without getting my ass handed to me (rogues can give it out, but they cannot take it). The problem being, that by the time I get the to point where I can start thinking about claiming the prize, the monsters I killed first have already started to resappear!</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s the problem: this is not how the game wanted me to go about this task. It wanted me to find a group of other players and storm the beachhead, quickly despatching the monsters and grabbing the prize. I was playing as a damn rouge, though! That is not how an assassin does business! In the end I got lucky. A warrior stormed the beach as I was creeping up, and I snaffled the loot while the monsters were distracted. Amoral? I believe I did point out that I was playing as a rogue.</p>

<p>In a regular, non MMO, RPG, everything you kill stays dead for the most part. In this case the world doesn&#8217;t have to be persistent (as in unchanging) because you&#8217;re the only one playing it and it doesn&#8217;t matter if no one else can do the quests. In an MMO, almost <em>everyone</em> needs to be able to do the quests, so the world generally performs a decent impression of Kirsten Dunst&#8217;s hair in Interview with a Vampire. It is a workable solution to the problem, but it can make you feel as though you and your actions don&#8217;t really matter, which isn&#8217;t ideal given that you&#8217;re supposed to be a hero.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m not the first person to have these sort of complaints, or to contemplate solutions, but that&#8217;s a story for another day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What in the Name of all that's Holy is a Clockwork Aphid?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/07/what-in-the-name-of-all-thats-holy-is-a-clockwork-aphid/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-07T16:24:15+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/07/what-in-the-name-of-all-thats-holy-is-a-clockwork-aphid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Clockwork Aphid is the name I&#8217;m giving to a side project I&#8217;ve had sitting at the back of head for a little while. I&#8217;m actually going to try and build it now. What it actually is is quite big and hard to explain, so I&#8217;m going to do it gradually, over time. This way I also get to maintain a little bit of mystery. Here&#8217;s what I will say up front, though:</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li>It&#8217;s a programming project;</li>
<li>It&#8217;s connected to computer games;</li>
<li>It&#8217;s also connected to&#8230; another form of digital entertainment which is (arguably) related to computer games;</li>
<li>In the beginning at least, I&#8217;m going to make the code I write open source.</li>
</ul>


<p>The actual name &#8220;Clockwork Aphid&#8221; comes from the name of the group I helped field to the &#8220;Dare to be Digital&#8221; computer game creation competition several years ago. We didn&#8217;t get in, but we proposed a game called &#8220;Bad Penny&#8221; which I still think was a bloody good idea. Some of the elements of that project are contained in this one also, but the name Bad Penny was chosen for a good reason. It was very appropriate for the type of game we were proposing. This project is potentially bigger, though, and I don&#8217;t want to limit the scope.</p>

<p>As for the Clockwork Aphid name itself? I just plain thought it sounded good then and I still think it sounds good now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Hestontastic!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/24/its-hestontastic/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-24T22:08:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/24/its-hestontastic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Strangely, I don&#8217;t think my good lady actually thought I&#8217;d attempt to make any of the actual recipes when she bought me a copy of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heston_Blumenthal">Heston Blumenthal</a>&#8217;s &#8221;<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Further-Adventures-Search-Perfection-Blumenthal/dp/0747594058/ref=pd_bxgy_b_img_b">Further Adventures in Search of Perfection</a>&#8221; for Christmas last year. Sometimes I worry about how little she appears to know me. A chili con carne recipe which takes three days to prepare is exactly the sort of challenge I&#8217;m practically incapable of resisting. A black forest gateau that requires the use of a hoover? I say &#8220;bring it on!&#8221;</p>

<p>I do intend to have a crack at those ones, but I thought I&#8217;d ease my way in with the Bolognese recipe from &#8221;<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Search-Perfection-Heston-Blumenthal/dp/0747584095">In Search of Perfection</a>,&#8221; which takes a mere ten hours to prepare and requires no special tools.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>We invited round two friends whom we have cause to thank and don&#8217;t see nearly enough of, and I gave it my best shot. Here&#8217;s the maestro himself, explaining how it&#8217;s done:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6pR5kVyemdY" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Mj9K6iSmafc" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UMx4HUKaA9k" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>In the interests of honesty, here are the things I did differently:</p>

<ul>
<li>My good lady is allergic to celery, so I took it out;</li>
<li>Every butcher I tried practically laughed in my face when I asked for minced ox tail, so I used good steak mince;</li>
<li>I don&#8217;t hold with serving a meat sauce with spaghetti, so I used pappardelle (thick ribbons);</li>
<li>I also served it with some particularly good garlic bread of my own devising.</li>
</ul>


<p>I should also point that the video is missing a couple of minor steps. If you want to actually make it, I recommend buying the book. If you have no desire to make it whatsoever, I recommend buying the book. Both books. They are fascinating reads. If you can&#8217;t read, I recommend buying the book. It also has good pictures. I&#8217;m a little confused if that&#8217;s the case, though.</p>

<p>At this point you&#8217;re probably wondering if the sauce is good enough to warrant the expenditure of an entire day to make it? In short: yes. Abso-fucking-lutely. It was amazing. Will I make it again? Probably, though certainly not often. I might make it sometime when my good lady isn&#8217;t in town and I can include the celery without the risk of her death (the sauce is not quite that good). Perhaps I&#8217;ll even try begging and pleading with one of the local butchers to get some minced ox tail or a better substitute.</p>

<p>What I will definitely do is use some of the individual techniques. The tomato base may well become a sauce for meatballs, and the caramelized onions will almost certainly get used in a gravy or two.</p>

<p>Across the entire of both books are sixteen recipes. One down.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Musical Arithmetic]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/15/musical-arithmetic/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-15T12:40:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/15/musical-arithmetic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so here&#8217;s the formula:</p>

<pre><code>(A - B) + C = D
</code></pre>

<p>And here are the variables:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>A = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UZjf9C6atT4" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Evanescence. More specifically: the original line up (as far as most of the world is concerned). I like Evanescence quite a bit, but that&#8217;s about 74.2% Amy Lee&#8217;s voice. The girl has one hell of a pair of lungs on her. I picked this particular song from the first album for reason which may become obvious later. For what it&#8217;s worth, I think Everybody&#8217;s Fool and Imaginary are a much better songs.</p>

<p>B = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/bP5wmtOXCQ" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Evanescence again? No. Well&#8230; yes, but the current line up. Specifically: Amy Lee herself. I picked this song from the second album (which is much better than the first) because it seems to have the most Amy Lee-ness in it. It doesn&#8217;t have an actual video, though, so alternatively:</p>

<p>B = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Hqd2FJF8-h8" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>I figure having a deficit of Seether won&#8217;t affect the sum either way, so this works too.</p>

<p>C = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dUyMvaJwACc" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Former Irish American Idol contestant* Carly Smithson. Once again: A hell of a pair of lungs. Not an entirely dissimilar look, but quite a different vocal style, it would appear. Carly&#8217;s voice has a bit more blues in it, a bit more sultriness.</p>

<p>D = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/zzTZeeMCUBk" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><a href="http://www.wearethefallen.com/">We are the Fallen</a>, the new band from Ben Moody, two other former members of Evanescence and Carly Smithson. Can you seen why I picked that particular Evanescence song? That&#8217;s more than a passing resemblance, style wise. There is a second reason I picked it, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kdYa0oeMLfI&amp;feature=related">however</a>. Carly has a less operatic voice, though, and a bit more range in terms of singing style. I love me some female fronted metal, so I&#8217;ll be keeping an eye on this band.</p>

<p>Okay, here&#8217;s another one which plays a bit better to her frankly spectacular voice:</p>

<p>D = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/u24NXTBHLYU" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>* That is: she&#8217;s Irish and was a contestant on &#8220;American Idol.&#8221; There is no such show as &#8220;Irish American Idol,&#8221; so far as I&#8217;m aware.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Location Location Location]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/05/location-location-location/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-05T19:47:54+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/05/location-location-location</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the few things I&#8217;ve missed since abandoning the good ship Windows PC for the Mac&#8230; er&#8230; Zeppelin (why not?) is magazines. I used to really enjoy reading the PC gaming and hardware mags. Oftentimes they were pitched at about the right level for me. I felt neither patronised nor confused. I&#8217;m afraid to say that this is not the case with Mac magazines. For the most part they tend to aim a little low, tech wise (no kidding, right?). I did also try Linux magazines, but generally found them to be way too dry and not especially well written. Once again, quelle surprise. Quelle surprise beaucoup.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So I was, as I&#8217;m sure you can imagine, quite overjoyed to discover <a href="http://www.wired.co.uk/">Wired</a> magazine. A platform agnostic tech magazine pitched about the right level (ish) for me, tech wise, whilst also having some focus on the business side of technology? Win! If you&#8217;re not reading it already, I highly recommend it. So, when Wired decided to give the cover story to location based social networks, concentrating on <a href="http://foursquare.com/">Foursquare</a> and <a href="http://gowalla.com/">Gowalla</a>, I though &#8220;sure, what the hell?&#8221; and gave them both a go.</p>

<p>That was a good couple of weeks ago now, and I can categorically say that I&#8217;m not sure if I like them or not. Nor am I sure which of the two I prefer. The idea, basically, is that you periodically tell them where you are.</p>

<p>Where are you going? Wait, there&#8217;s more.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a game of sorts, you see. Foursquare awards you points for visiting places (more if they&#8217;re new places) while Gowalla gives you badges in your&#8221;passport.&#8221; Both of them also award you bonuses for various things, and Foursquare declares you the &#8220;Mayor&#8221; of locations if you visit them more than anybody else. There is a bit more to it than this, of course, there&#8217;s a social aspect, connected to both locating your friends and finding out where is currently &#8220;happening,&#8221; (this is the correct term, yes?) but I think I&#8217;ve given you the gist.</p>

<p>On balance: foursquare seems to do more in terms of the whole &#8220;life as a game&#8221; idea, and makes it feel more worthwhile to visit places multiple times&#8230; but Gowalla has a MUCH better design, and the badges and pins (achievements) it gives you are much prettier, but lacks the competitiveness of Foursquare. I think, at this point, I would tentatively recommend both, but particularly Foursquare if you&#8217;re a competitive sort. Either way, feel free to friend me if you do give them a try (it&#8217;s free).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A couple more...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/07/27/a-couple-more/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-27T22:02:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/07/27/a-couple-more</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Further to my last post, here&#8217;s a couple more films which caught my eye, though one of them is a ways off yet.</p>

<p>Faster (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/independent/faster/">trailer</a>) - I will go and see Dwayne Johnson in any film which doesn&#8217;t involve him wearing a tutu or fairy wings. Perhaps even then, and you can quote me on that. The guy has more charisma and physical presence than just about everyone else out there, and is (as far as I&#8217;m concerned) always good value for money, regardless of the quality of the actual film. Frankly, the guy should be a much bigger start than he is. That he&#8217;s in an indie revenge flick makes me very happy indeed. Also: great trailer.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>Sucker Punch (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/wb/suckerpunch/">trailer</a>) - Zack Snyder is another one of those directors who&#8217;s work I would go sight unseen. Though Watchmen wasn&#8217;t quite the film I wanted it to be, I still enjoyed the hell out of it and I loved his two previous films (300 and Dawn of the Dead). This is a director who makes <em>cinema</em> and every frame of it is absolutely, stunningly beautiful. Evidence so far suggests that he actually works pretty well with actors and knows how to handle a plot, also, which is nice (Micheal Bay, take note). This is his first time working with an original property, so I guess we&#8217;ll have to see how it goes. Oh yeah, it also seems to have nazis, dragons, sword wielding burlesque girls, Zeppelins, spaceships and mini gun toting giant samurai demons&#8230; and something tells me that&#8217;s not the half of it&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking Forwards]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/07/18/looking-forwards/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-18T17:02:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/07/18/looking-forwards</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Cineworld unlimited card is a wonderful thing, especially given that I no longer have a student card (I am still a student, technically. Don&#8217;t ask). It encourages you to take a much more &#8220;what the hell,&#8221; type attitude to heading to the cinema, and I love me some cinema. That being the case, I thought I&#8217;d write a (probably) quick post covering the films coming out this year that I&#8217;m pretty certain I&#8217;ll be going to see.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So, in particular order (aside from the one in which they occurred to me):</p>

<p>Inception (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/wb/inception/">trailer</a>) - There are some director&#8217;s who pretty much guarente I&#8217;ll go see a film. Christopher Nolan is one of them. Likewise, there are some actor&#8217;s who pretty much guarente I&#8217;ll go and see a film. Ellen Page is one of them. Also: this film look awesome.</p>

<p>The Social Network (<a href="http://movies.yahoo.com/premieres/20889647/standardformat">trailer</a>) - David Fincher is another one of the directors who almost guarantees I&#8217;ll go see a film. Aaron Sorkin is a writer who pretty much guarantees I&#8217;ll go see a film. I didn&#8217;t think I was interested in a film about Facebook, but it turns out that I really, really am. Watch the trailer.</p>

<p>Machete (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/fox/machete/">trailer</a>) - I didn&#8217;t think much of Death Proof, but I loved me some Planet Terror, and this looks like it&#8217;s coming from the same headspace.</p>

<p>Tron Legacy (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/disney/tronlegacy/">trailer</a>) - I think I might have already mentioned this one.</p>

<p>The Town (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/wb/thetown/">trailer</a>) - Ben Affleck might be a genius. Perhaps you didn&#8217;t know that. You might assume that it was Matt Daemon who did most of the heavy lifting when it came to writing Good Will Hunting. But did you go see Gone Baby Gone? Because he wrote (well, adapted) and directed that and it was <em>spectacular</em>. I&#8217;m hoping he&#8217;s done it again.</p>

<p>The Expendables (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/lions_gate/theexpendables/">trailer</a>) - A cast made up almost entirely of action legends? Written and directed by the man who brought us Rambo? I&#8217;m there. If you didn&#8217;t watch Rambo (the most recent one), perhaps you should. It is incredibly, unflinchingly violent. But it&#8217;s a film about violence and you might be surprised by how much it has to say.</p>

<p>Scott Pilgrim vs. The World (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/universal/scottpilgrimvstheworld/">trailer</a>) - I love it. I love the style. I love the sense of humour. I love the ideas. I&#8217;ll be very surprised I don&#8217;t giggle with glee all the way through this one.<br/>
R.E.D. (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/summit/red/">trailer</a>) - I&#8217;m not even going to try explaining this one. Just watch the trailer.</p>

<p>Knight and Day (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/fox/knightandday/">trailer</a>) - I don&#8217;t know about you, but I mostly go to the cinema to be entertained. This looks like it will be super entertaining. Side note: I might not like Tom Cruise on a person, but I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever disliked him in a film.</p>

<p>The Green Hornet (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/sony_pictures/thegreenhornet/">trailer</a>) - This looks all kinds of silly. These ingredients (superhero + martial arts + star of Knocked Up + director of Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind) should not go together. But I bet the first person to eat a peanut butter and jam sandwich said the same thing.</p>

<p>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hollows (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/wb/harrypotterandthedeathlyhallows/">trailer</a>) - I expect to be disappointed by this one. I have been by every other one of these films. But that doesn&#8217;t mean I didn&#8217;t enjoy them (except the second one). I&#8217;m looking forward to the conclusion of the first set of adaptations of these books.</p>

<p>There are more, but that&#8217;ll do for now. What do you guys think? Any of these look good? Any look great? Any look awful? Anything you&#8217;re particularly looking forward to?</p>

<p>As a slight aside, I&#8217;m also HarveyNick on Tumblr and Twitter, and I&#8217;m thinking of moving the 15 words or less film review to Tumblr instead of here, as it seems to fit better. Can anyone think of a reason I shouldn&#8217;t (it&#8217;ll still get cross posted to Facebook).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Identity]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/06/19/identity/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-19T15:01:16+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/06/19/identity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As you may or may not know, I&#8217;m currently in Australia. In fact, I&#8217;ve now been here for a little over a month. I&#8217;ll blog about it sooner or later, but not yet. This is largely because I don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;m going to say. This trip has been an alarming combination of coolness and frustration so far, and I don&#8217;t want to let too much of the later slip out. That would be highly unprofessional of me, and possibly not great either for my employer or my career.</p>

<p>This post shall be about something else.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I have a side project that I&#8217;ve chomping at the bit to get started on, and while I&#8217;ve been here I&#8217;ve worked up a couple of fairly good ideas for it. I can&#8217;t start work on it, though, because I only have my work computer with me, and a studiously avoid doing any side projects or personal work on it, just to be on the safe side, intellectual property wise. Aside from reading up on things and doing some scribblings on paper, the other thing I can do is set up a bit of infrastructure.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m going to make the project public, both in terms of open sourcing the code and blogging about the ideas behind it (at least to begin with). But where, though? Here&#8217;s my dilema: I&#8217;m HarveyNick on wordpress, Tumblr, Twitter* and now BitBucket (the place I&#8217;ll be hosting the code - side note: I&#8217;ll be going with Mercurial for revision control). Should I write the blog entries here (and have them trickle down to tumblr and twitter), and host the code directly under HarveyNick&#8217;s account on BitBucket? Let&#8217;s say I name the project after my old band, the repository would be</p>

<pre><code>bitbucket.org/harveynick/hinge  
</code></pre>

<p>Which stamps my ownership on it quite heavily. Likewise, if I put blog entries here: same situation. In some senses that&#8217;s a good thing. Right now, it&#8217;s my project. I might not always want it to be that way, though. Getting other people involved might also be good. I tend to work better (a lot better) when I have someone to bounce ideas off. So let&#8217;s consider option 2; I put the project under another umbrella, and give myself (ie the harveynick identity) access to it. Let&#8217;s say I go with one of the names my old band was thinking of switching to after some assholes in Chicago threatened to sue us. That would put it here:</p>

<pre><code>bitbucket.org/deadcitywalking/hinge  
</code></pre>

<p>I could then start a deadcitywalking.wordpress.com blog to talk about it, and perhaps link the entries here. Should other people start playing in this particular sandpit, then they could perhaps add their own entries to this blog.</p>

<p>You&#8217;re probably not interested in this. I&#8217;m mostly just thinking out loud. But if you have any thoughts, I&#8217;d love to hear them.</p>

<p>* Why do I have all three of these? I&#8217;m not entirely sure yet, other than because they&#8217;re there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trailer Trash]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/03/15/trailer-trash/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-15T22:30:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/03/15/trailer-trash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every once in a while, a film trailer comes along that I can’t seem to stop myself watching repeatedly. I like trailers in general, which is definitely part of the problem, but some of them really grab hold of me. Two good examples of this are the final theatrical trailer for the recent <a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/paramount/startrek/">Star Trek reboot</a>, and one of the trailers for <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c9tnZRs4tNE">The Two Towers</a> (the one with the orchestral version of he awesome theme song from Requiem for a Dream, and words cannot express how disappointed I was when that music wasn’t in the actual film).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>You might be noticing a dramatic music related theme here, but visuals and dialogue are important too. It all has to click together. You’ve heard it said, I’m sure, that part (or even half) of the the pleasure of a present is in the unwrapping. Same thing, right here. Which brings me back to the latest object of desire I’m metaphorically tugging at the ribbon of. It’s the shiny new trailer for <a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/disney/tronlegacy/">Tron Legacy</a>, long awaited sequel to the 1982 cyber cult classic. I have something of a weakness for stories which which turn computer programmers* into heroes anyway (I’m sure you couldn’t possibly imagine why), but everything in this trailer works for me. There <em>was</em> an initial warning sign, to wit: one of the principle protagonists would appear to be the son of the original hero.</p>

<p>Shit. Where have I seen that recently?</p>

<p>But wait&#8230; Maybe he’s <em>not</em> a complete tool of a character, because I absolutely love the delivery of the one line line he really gets in the trailer. Bruce Boxleitner too, returning from the original, but then I already knew he could handle a bit of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Sheridan_(Babylon_5)">gravitas</a>. After a bit of initial set up, the trailer is basically all about the visuals, and what visuals they are. For a start, one of them is a visual of the gorgeous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olivia_Wilde">Olivia Wilde</a> (13 from House). It all looks very cool and it all makes me very curious indeed. For some reason, I especially love the way the music distorts as the main title is revealed. In case you hadn’t guessed: I’m quiet excited about this one. Let me know what <em>you</em> think.</p>

<p>* Apparently, “software engineer” is the more politically correct term, but screw you, I know what I am. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[...And Another Couple Of Things]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/02/07/and-another-couple-of-things/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-07T22:16:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/02/07/and-another-couple-of-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Something I forgot to mention in my last post was my trying to look at the iPad from a developer&#8217;s perspective. I talked before about a programming side project that I&#8217;ve had bouncing around in my head for a while. Previously, I mentioned that I wasn&#8217;t sure if it was a website, an application, or some combination of the two. Then again I could see some use cases in which a laptop might be a bit cumbersome and a smart phone too small and underpowered. In which case neither the application of the website is entirely satisfactory. I&#8217;m actually now starting to think that the iPad could be the exact right platform for it. Perhaps I should actually start working my way through the Objective-C text book I&#8217;ve had sitting on my shelf for over a year now&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I have another couple of side projects, some programmery and some writery that have me giving the thing a more than slightly critical glance.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s not the point of this post, though. The fact of the matter is that, although it might sometimes seem that way, Apple does not have a monopoly on multi touch user interfaces. If you want to see a particularly impressive example that neither you nor I (nor the governments of some small countries, I suspect) can afford, look no further than the <a href="http://www.perceptivepixel.com/index.html">Perceptive Pixel</a> website. Another cool example showing someone playing with a multi-touch implementation of the Warcraft 3 real time strategy game can be found below:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/KtKkOhMqVhY" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>That&#8217;s the sort of thing Apple <em>should</em> have shown at their event, in my opinion. There&#8217;s also another tablet doing the rounds called the &#8220;Joojoo,&#8221; which is apparently African for &#8220;magic.&#8221; You should be impressed already. I bet you didn&#8217;t think &#8220;African&#8221; was a language, did ya? That was news to me, too. This tablet looks one hell of a lot like the iPad, but is has a 12.1&#8221; multitouch screen and features a flash supporting web browser. It costs about the same as the starting price of the iPad, also. Sounds like a better deal, you say? Unfortunately I just listed its entire feature list. Web browsing is all it does and it doesn&#8217;t seem to have any capability for offline use. It also has a seriously dodgy past and it&#8217;s makers are being sued as a result. What? You want to see it? Oh. Here:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://realvision.ae/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/joojoo.jpg" title="&#34;The JooJoo&#34;" alt="&#34;The JooJoo&#34;"></p>

<p>I think this device is kinda cool, but way too limited. Like the iPad, iPhone, and iPod Touch it features an onscreen soft keyboard&#8230; but now I very good one from what I&#8217;ve seen. There&#8217;s a <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2009/12/08/joojoo-tablet-hands-on-video/">video</a> of the company&#8217;s CEO demonstrating the device and having a bit of trouble working the keyboard. Not a good sign. The hardware looks pretty cool though, the sort of thing a person might be tempted to buy with the intention of hacking. Not me though. I don&#8217;t like having to act as my own tech support when it comes to the hardware and operating system.</p>

<p>Perhaps I&#8217;m done talking about the iPad and it&#8217;s ilk, and I&#8217;ll soon find something else to prattle on about&#8230; or perhaps I&#8217;ll be back soon with a bunch of use cases the think will have to fulfil in order for me to consider buying one, perhaps in the context of these side project I seem to refuse to go into any detail about. Alright, here&#8217;s a clue which might have meaning to about one person reading this: Bad Penny.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[That iPad thing]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/02/03/that-ipad-thing/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-03T23:24:46+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/02/03/that-ipad-thing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Originally, right after I got around the watching the keynote presentation which launched the iPad, I was going to write a blog post about how disappointed I was. I thought they&#8217;d screwed the pooch and I, for one, was seriously underwhelmed.</p>

<p>Needless to say, I didn&#8217;t quite get around to writing it. Since then I&#8217;ve read all the criticism by the naysayers and Apple haters, all the gushing praise from the fanatics and all the stuff in between from the more sensible people*. Now, after some reflection, I find myself somewhere in the middle. I flip back and forwards between thoughts of &#8220;that could be awesome,&#8221; and &#8220;that&#8217;s far too much of a compromise.&#8221;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Ironically, the thing that&#8217;s bringing me around to the idea is the very thing which people seem to be complaining about the most. Specifically: &#8220;It&#8217;s just an iPod Touch with a bigger screen,&#8221; which, in fairness, is exactly what I was thinking. It&#8217;s not a bad thing, though. The iPod Touch (and iPhone) have a <em>spectacular</em> interface. The touch controls work well enough and the device is responsive enough to make you feel is though you&#8217;re interacting with your music or the internet or your emails in a very direct manor. As a matter of fact, the main limitation of the interface is the small size of the screen. Ah hah&#8230;</p>

<p>I think what actually happened is that Apple made a mess of the keynote. Yes, the first person shooter was very pretty, but not really ideal for the interface. A real time strategy game, something like command and conquer, could really sing on this thing. The iWork apps look pretty cool, but a multi-touch version of iMovie or GarageBand could have been seriously impressive. They really didn&#8217;t make me believe that I could comfortably read a book on this thing&#8230; but if they&#8217;d announced text books for the iBooks store and placed an iPad next to the pile of books you usually need each year&#8230; well, then we&#8217;d have been talking. If they&#8217;d have shown how you could search the contents of a text book, spot light style, I might have been sold. Instead they left me to have to think of these things by myself.</p>

<p>I still not 100% certain I know what it&#8217;s for, though. Does it replace my laptop? Does it go alongside my laptop? Would I use on the sofa? Probably. On a short journey? Can&#8217;t see me getting it out on the bus. A long journey? Yes, I think so. Sitting in a coffee shop? Maybe. It would take up less room on the table. Sitting in the park? A tad more risky. But still, I don&#8217;t know. I&#8217;m disinclined to spend £500+ on something which is just a toy. I think I can live without multi-tasking, but there needs to be a better system to allows different apps to work together. What use are great OmniGraffle and Pages apps if I can&#8217;t insert a diagram from the former into the latter?</p>

<p>Bottom line: I&#8217;ll go and have a play with one after they come out. Then we&#8217;ll see.</p>

<p>PS For my parents, though, the damn thing is almost perfect.</p>

<p>* Well&#8230; I say &#8220;all&#8221;&#8230; what I actually mean is &#8220;some.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Goldilocks Dilema]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/12/09/the-goldilocks-dilema/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-09T11:43:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/12/09/the-goldilocks-dilema</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Daddy Bear&#8217;s porridge is too expensive.</p>

<p>Baby Bear&#8217;s porridge is underpowered.</p>

<p>Mummy Bear&#8217;s porridge is just right&#8230; but has a monitor in it.</p>

<p>Hhhmmm&#8230; perhaps I should explain&#8230;</p>

<p>It&#8217;s reached that time. My computer is starting to show it&#8217;s age. In small ways, mostly. It stalls occasionally, but with gradually increasing frequency. Every now and then it&#8217;s slow down noticeably, and the fans are spending more and more time going full blast. If it actually died on me that would a <em>disaster </em>right now, but I&#8217;m not too worried about that just yet. Even so, I think it&#8217;s time that it had a worthy heir.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>At present I have a first generation black MacBook, but I think I&#8217;m going to go for a desktop for my next system. I like working at a desk, and with a desktop I&#8217;ll get more bang (and screen) for my buck. I&#8217;ll keeps the laptop around for taking to coffee shops and trips (and the times when I really feel I need to work on the sofa), and synchronise my data between machines using the <em>fantastic</em> <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/referrals/NTExMTkzNDQ5/">DropBox</a>. While I&#8217;m on the subject, I can&#8217;t recommend DropBox enough. It seamlessly synchronises your files to and from the web, and works on all operating systems. Even Windows. Also: it&#8217;s free for the first 2GB. If you&#8217;re interesting in DropBox, please go via the link I posted above, we&#8217;ll both get a bonus 250MB of space!</p>

<p>When, or indeed if, my laptop dies, assuming I&#8217;ve had a pay rise and/or won the lottery, I might replace it with something a bit sleeker. By which I mean a MacBook Air. You might be saying: &#8220;Wait a minute, don&#8217;t you have one of the those funky and cheap little netbook things?&#8221; and the answer would be yes, but I don&#8217;t really use it. The simple fact is: you get what you pay for. It&#8217;s way underpowered and the keyboard is a serious pain to use. Don&#8217;t even get me started on the trackpad. I do have a use for it, though, and I might come back to that at a later date.</p>

<p>But what desktop to get? Which brings us about back to where we came in. The question is: which desktop should I get. I&#8217;m getting a Mac, so my options are:</p>

<p>Mac Pro. Ludicrously powerful, and very expensive. Almost certainly more than I need, and a bigger physical footprint than I&#8217;d prefer. Also uses a LOT of power.</p>

<p>iMac. Gorgeous. Just about the exact specification I&#8217;m looking for. Not exactly cheap, but within the budget. Uses a reasonable amount of power. Is about as eco friendly as a machine with this sort of spec can be. Has an absolutely gorgeous built in 27&#8221; (or 21.5&#8221;, but I would probably go for the 27&#8221;) monitor. That last point is both a pro and a con, while it is spectacular monitor which would probably cost about the same amount as a stand alone unit as the iMac itself costs, I&#8217;d ideally like to be able to use the same monitor for my XBox 360. That&#8217;s how I&#8217;ll be playing games, you see. If I got the iMac I&#8217;d either have to put my old, smaller monitor next to it for the XBox, or move the XBox back into the lounge where I tended not to use it, as I felt like I was imposing and I like to sit quite close to the screen when playing.</p>

<p>Mac Mini. Slightly underpowered. You can get decent processor in it, but the graphics card is quite low spec and I have plans to do some quite graphics-ey things. It is quite cheap, though, and I could buy an decent external monitor to go with it (XBox 360 ahoy!)  and still spend less than I would on an iMac. It&#8217;s also very low power. The most eco friendly desktop on the market, in fact. Going flat out it would still be using less power than the iMac would idle (even taking the monitor into account) and uses only 14 Watts when idle. 14!</p>

<p>So those are my options. You might now be thinking &#8220;Fool! Those are not your options! Get a PC! Then you&#8217;ll have hundreds of options! PCs are better anyway! Macs are for idiots who don&#8217;t know how to use a real computer!&#8221; and you would be a little bit right. That would solve <em>this</em> problem. It would also create about a bazilion new problems, though. Like the distinct possibility that I might throw my computer out of the window.</p>

<p>Maybe you use Windows. Maybe you think it&#8217;s just fine. Maybe you find those Mac adverts really annoying (so do I, most of the time) and you&#8217;re fed up of being told that you should &#8220;get a Mac&#8221; by slightly pompous and patronising people. I&#8217;m not going to do that. If Windows works great for you, keep using it. It <em>is</em> shit though. Maybe not on the surface, but as a piece of software engineering it&#8217;s a chrome plated turd, and Microsoft spends most of the their time doing extra chrome plating. That one of the many reasons that I&#8217;ll be sticking with the Macs until something changes drastically&#8230; and I do mean <em>drastically</em>.</p>

<p>In lieu of a nearby Apple Store I think I might go to John Lewis at the weekend and stare at my options. Maybe push a couple of buttons and try and find a way to stress out the graphics chip on the mini. Anyone got any opinions?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Can't Recommend Highly Enough]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/09/20/just-cant-recommend-highly-enough/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-20T18:25:45+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/09/20/just-cant-recommend-highly-enough</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I finished &#8220;The Girl Who Played With Fire&#8221;, translated by Reg Keeland from the swedish book of the same name by Stieg Larsson. It&#8217;s the sequel to &#8216;The Girl With the Dragon Tattoo&#8221; (which is called &#8220;Men Who Hate Women&#8221; in the original swedish), and I really can&#8217;t recommend the pair of them highly enough (as you might have guessed from the title of this blog post).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I picked the first book up as the combination of the titular character being described as &#8220;an expert computer hacker&#8221; and the synopsis on the back cover put me in mind of Neil Stephenson&#8217;s &#8220;Cryptonomicon&#8221;, not only one of my favourite books but also an outright work of genius, in my opinion. I would describe &#8221;Cryptonomicon&#8221; as recommended reading if you&#8217;re the sort of person who breaths oxygen and walks upright, if you work with computers I&#8217;d say it verges on being <em>required</em> reading. Since Stephenson lost the plot more recently (in my opinion, that is; I didn&#8217;t make it more than half way through &#8220;Quicksilver&#8221; before giving up in pained frustration) there has been a rather large cyber-fiction based hole in my world. &#8220;&#8230;Dragon Tattoo&#8221; seems as though it might be poised to fill it.</p>

<p>In fact it did not. It&#8217;s a different beast all together. A slow burning and wonderful one, written (and translated) with great skill and care. Both books are very powerful reads, laced with a hatred of misogyny and criticism of a system which doesn&#8217;t do nearly enough to prevent it. It&#8217;s also a ripping great yarn of a mystery, full of strong male <em>and</em> female characters. Nominally, the books are the first two parts of a trilogy. In fact Larsson planned ten books and left an unfinished fourth manuscript together with outlines for books five and six when he died. I&#8217;m waiting with bated breath for the release of the third book. I just hope it ties things up reasonably well and so won&#8217;t leave me too curious about the contents of book I&#8217;ll never be able to read.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The right kind of holiday]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/09/06/the-right-kind-of-holiday/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-06T16:00:18+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/09/06/the-right-kind-of-holiday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been, by my count, at least 18 months since I last had a holiday (aside from one weekend spent in Cardiff). It&#8217;s getting to the point where I&#8217;m starting to feel that I really need a one. But what <em>kind</em> of holiday?</p>

<p>Having stopped to think about it, I&#8217;ve realised that most of the holidays I&#8217;ve taken have been of the package type. With the skiing holidays this isn&#8217;t so bad, it&#8217;s possibly even ideal. The rest of the time&#8230; not so much. It feels a little too much like being cattle, it feels very lowest common denominator (largely because it is) and you&#8217;ll tend to spend a lot of time around <em>British Tourists</em> (if you know what I mean). The holidays I remember enjoying most are the other kind. The ad hoc ones. Three stand out.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Something like five years ago my friend Pete was living and working in Barcelona for the summer, staying with a friend he&#8217;d met while previously living in Switzerland. My friend Ruth and I made our way out there (slightly haphazardly, in my case) and spend a fantastic week, sleeping on Pete&#8217;s floor and trying to spend as little money as possible, whilst also trying to see and drink as much as possible. Pete&#8217;s friend also had a couple of friend&#8217;s kipping on her floor, and they&#8217;d also befriended an Irish fella they&#8217;d found in the bar Pete worked in. It was a great time. When I think back on the seriously happy moments in my life, swimming in sea at 1 am on Barcelona beach while holding onto a bottle of white wine in an attempt to cool it down a little&#8230; yeah, that ranks pretty high up there.</p>

<p>A couple of years later I (English), together with my friends Mark (Scottish) and John (Irish) made another ad hoc trip, this time to Italy. We flew with Easy Jet, rented a cheap but very comfortable villa in the hills and drove our selves around in a rental Alpha Romeo. We ate some great food food, played some cards, looked at some very pretty cities (and some very pretty girls), and <em>accidentally</em> drove up the off ramp of an Italian motorway. I highly recommend it (except for the last one).</p>

<p>Lastly, and most recently, I spent a long weekend in a hostel in Berlin with 7 friends. We saw the sites, ate lots of pig and potato based products, probably drank too much, and wrapped up very, very warm. Only one of our number actually spoke German and he had to go elsewhere for the last night, leaving us to end up in what turned out to be an awesome and <em>very</em> cheap socialist bar. Though there was an tense few minutes when we were sure what <em>kind</em> of socialist bar it was (it was the good kind).</p>

<p>I would like to have more holidays like this. Now, if I could just figure out a good way of setting them up&#8230;</p>

<p>BUNAC appeals to me (and I only have two years left to try it, depending on the country), as does farm working my way a cross a (hot) country. Burning Man is also not without it&#8217;s a appeal&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Web Frameworks, Desktop Application and My Newly Melted Brain]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/09/01/web-frameworks-desktop-application-and-my-newly-melted-brain/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-01T00:14:07+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/09/01/web-frameworks-desktop-application-and-my-newly-melted-brain</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s get the preliminaries out of the way: Hello, long time no see, how have you been? Etc&#8230;</p>

<p>So, whilst writing up my PhD (experiments finally finished!) and working three days a week (going fully full time at the end of September!) I have a fair bit on my plate at the moment. So obviously I&#8217;ve also started cooking up a side project&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I don&#8217;t want to talk too much about what it actually is (mostly because I don&#8217;t know how &#8220;open&#8221; I want it to be yet), but it&#8217;s definitely going to require a web service. It might also require a fully fledged website (lets call this the spotify model), or it might just use a desktop application which connects to the service when it needs to (lets call this the iTunes model). Then again it might have both, with the desktop application providing some extra functionality which is hard to do over the web or in the browser. I think there&#8217;s also scope for a mobile application, so lets throw iPhone and (what the hell) Android into the pot as well.</p>

<p>I had a bit of a poke around with some web development frameworks first, since this is probably the bit I know least about.</p>

<p>One of the first solutions I came across was <a href="http://www.djangoproject.com/">Django</a>, which is based on the <a href="http://www.python.org/">python</a> language. It looks good, through I have some issues with its handling of &#8220;one to many&#8221; relationships. Python is a language I have limited experience with, but it gets a lot of love, and people are putting a lot of work into into making it better. It also has good integration with native libraries. So that&#8217;s nice. It&#8217;s also named after Monty Python, which only raises my opinion of it.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll essentially skip over <a href="http://turbogears.org/">TurboGears</a> and <a href="http://www.web2py.com/">Web2Py</a>, two other python based frameworks I did some reading about. Django seems like the best choice out the python based frameworks I&#8217;ve looked at.</p>

<p>Soon afterwards I discovered <a href="http://grails.org/">Grails</a> which is based on the very cool <a href="http://groovy.codehaus.org/">groovy</a> dynamic language. Groovy, as well as being fun to say, is implemented directly on top of Java, by far the language I&#8217;m most comfortable with. The are a lot of existing Java libraries, and groovy has <em>perfect</em> integration with them. Groovy and grails have some serious weight behind them, also.</p>

<p>One framework I hadn&#8217;t really considered was <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/">Ruby on Rails</a>, which is in many ways the daddy here. This is mostly because I dismissed <a href="http://www.ruby-lang.org/">Ruby</a> as a language out of hand. It looks mental. For reasons I&#8217;ll come to in a minute, I&#8217;ve re-evaluated this desision, and will be having a good long look at it. On the one hand it&#8217;s been around a good long while, so has had the oportunity to become more refined. On the other hand, it was the first of its kind, which means it might also be stuck with some bad early design desicions. It&#8217;s the original, this might not make it the best. I don&#8217;t know yet.</p>

<p>In order to build this&#8230; thing, I&#8217;ll need data representation, I&#8217;ll need algorithms for processing this data, and I&#8217;ll need ways of displaying it. I&#8217;d rather not have to deal with multiple implementations in different languages, particularly with the algorithms.<br/>
Problem.</p>

<p>If I want to make desktop applications, python is a possibility. It has good bindings to GTK and QT for linux, and Cocoa for OSX (there&#8217;s probably also something which will work on windows, and at some point I&#8217;ll probably have to care about this). Java will work anywhere, but it&#8217;s quite difficult to make a desktop application with Java which won&#8217;t look like crap. My priority in this area is going to be OSX, and Java does not measure up here. I had not considered Ruby, until I came across MacRuby, which is a <em>very</em> interesting idea. It&#8217;s not a bridge or a set of bindings, you see, it sits right on top of the objective-c runtime. All of a sudden, Ruby and Rails are a contender.</p>

<p>In the mobile space, things get shitty. iPhone requires objective-c, Android requires Java.</p>

<p>Bugger.</p>

<p>So here&#8217;s where I am: I think groovy is a better language than python (and probably ruby), and I think grails is a better framework than django (I&#8217;ll get back to you regarding rails)&#8230; but I&#8217;m not sure I want Java hanging around my neck when it comes to building a desktop application. I might also need some serious grunt in the algorithm stakes, and I&#8217;m not sure I want to do that in a scripting language. Yes, I need to be able to implement it quickly, but I also need it to run quickly. I&#8217;m not sure I want to do that in either C or C++. Java would be good for this (and yes, it&#8217;s plenty fast). Objective-c is an option I haven&#8217;t discounted.</p>

<p>The search continues&#8230; any thoughts?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spending to make...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/02/26/spending-to-make/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-26T23:23:03+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/02/26/spending-to-make</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While it&#8217;s a fairly common and reasonably accurate maxim that you have to spend money to make money, I find myself wondering if the same is true of energy. To reword and disentangle the metaphor: Can you save energy by using energy?</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s a my train of thought: You have curtains in your house. It&#8217;s possible to fit a motorised unit and automate the opening and closing of the same. This would same ostentatious, lazy and wasteful. To have a computer, sitting, always on, in your house, which decides when this should happen would seem to increase these negative factors.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>But&#8230;</p>

<p>During winter, you try to close the curtains to keep heat in. Doing this early means you miss out on daylight and, furthermore, you have to turn on artificial lights. Doing this too late means that you loose heat through the windows. There&#8217;s is probably a converse example in hotter climates than this, in which your house gets too hot in the middle of the day if you don&#8217;t close the binds, meaning you have to turn on the air conditioning.</p>

<p>So then, at what point does the energy used to run the computer become a good investment? What if it has sensors inside and outside in order to measure the temperature gradient, and so it can choose the best time to close the curtains? What if it also manages your heating? What if it intelligently turns out the lights in rooms you&#8217;re not in? Reminds you that you turned the oven on but haven&#8217;t actually put anything in it&#8230; Makes damn sure that you get out of bed in the morning&#8230; and so on&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call by the what now?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/02/24/call-by-the-what-now/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-24T23:40:04+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/02/24/call-by-the-what-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some not work related computery bits and pieces have been percolating around my head for some time now. I think we should talk about them for a while. That is: I&#8217;ll talk. You listen.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m probably going to write a couple of more techy blogs, all loosely interrelated. I am going somewhere with them, but I&#8217;m not entirely certain as to how much of this journey I will share with you.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First of all, I&#8217;m going to talk about the fairly simple computer related concept of &#8220;Call by reference&#8221; versus &#8220;Call by value&#8221;. This is fairly basic computer science (though I wish they&#8217;d taught it properly earlier on in my course). It&#8217;s possible (probable, even) that this example (or variations of it) has been used a thousand times before. I&#8217;m not going to go look for one (or the absence of one), I&#8217;m just going to write down my own particular take on it. I assure you that any plagiarism I&#8217;m about to commit is in no way deliberate. So, without further ado&#8230;</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s say you want to send a specific piece of information to someone via email. Let&#8217;s say it&#8217;s part of today&#8217;s featured article on Wikipedia (William I of Orange, at the time of writing). In today&#8217;s connected digital world, you have too main options. First of all, you could send them the information itself, like so:</p>

<blockquote><p>William was born in the castle of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dillenburg">Dillenburg</a> in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nassau_(duchy">Nassau</a>), present-day <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Germany">Germany</a>. He was the eldest son of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_I,_Count_of_Nassau-Dillenburg">William, Count of Nassau</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Juliana_of_Stolberg">Juliana of Stolberg-Werningerode</a>, and was raised a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lutheran_Church">Lutheran</a>. He had four younger brothers and seven younger sisters: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Johan_of_Nassau">John</a>, Hermanna, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Louis_of_Nassau">Louis</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Mary_of_Nassau&amp;action=edit&amp;redlink=1">Mary</a>, Anna, Elisabeth, Katharine, Juliane, Magdalene, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adolf_of_Nassau">Adolf</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_of_Nassau-Dillenburg">Henry</a>.</p></blockquote>

<p>There are several things your recipient can do with this. They can read it. They can edit it, but this will only edit their local copy. The original remains unchanged. If they want to request that a change be made, they can, however, edit it and send it back to you. This is &#8220;calling by value.&#8221;</p>

<p>Your second option is to send them a link to the information:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_I_of_Orange#Early_life">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/William_I_of_Orange#Early_life</a></p></blockquote>

<p>This, again, allows them to read it. They have to follow the link to the information it points to first, though. This time, if they make an edit (this being wikipedia) they actually are changing the original copy. They can also see what other information is around it, and if they feel so inclined they can change that is well. You might consider this to be an undesirable consequence. This method has the aditional advantage, however, that you did not have to take the time and effort to make a copy, and the amount of information you had to actually send is significantly smaller. This is &#8220;calling by reference.&#8221;</p>

<p>If you deal with this sort of thing on a day to day basis, you may well be aware that when you do this sort of thing in a computer program you have another option. You can send a constant reference, which would be analagious to sending a link to a website the recipient has no write access to. For example:</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/644041/William-I">http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic/644041/William-I</a></p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serendipitous Nostalgia]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/13/serendipitous-nostalgia/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-13T23:31:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/13/serendipitous-nostalgia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I was walking home from work and absent-mindedly listening to music, when I noticed that that my supposedly shuffled iPod was displaying a definite preference for one band in particular. A band I haven&#8217;t really spared a seconds thought in some years. As I walked I hatched a plot a write a blog post regarding the nostalgia this inspired. So I arrived home and thought to have a look on youTube for some reference material to post&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There is a reason I have a marked preference for the combination of a heavy rock music and female vocals, and her name is Aimee Echo. In the late nineties she fronted a band called Human Waste Project with vocals which managed to be both sugary sweet and ragged at the same time. My youthful self took notice. My youthful self also attended a festival called the &#8220;Ozzfest&#8221; with his friend Rich and said friend&#8217;s father, where he found Human Waste Project to be a late addition to the bill. My youthful self promptly had the back of head damn near blown off by one of the best live shows he had (or was ever to) see.</p>

<p>As it turned out, that was to be their second to last show. Aimee Echo left the band, who sounded like this:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/xGLglF2MuEo" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>and formed a new one, called at first Hero and then theSTART, who sounded more like this:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/J-K64wVAn5U" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p></p>

<p>Though I like this second song, I find that the raw edge is missing from her voice. This is probably due to the more electronic sound of the new band and thus the requisite multi-tracking of a voice I don&#8217;t feel requires it. The point is I don&#8217;t like the second band as much, not least because this is the only song of there&#8217;s I found which has much of a chorus.</p>

<p>So where was I&#8230; ah yes, I was searching youTube for content to post. What I found was a lot of presumably live videos. I saw one for &#8220;Dog&#8221;, thought &#8220;sweet!&#8221; and clicked. The video loaded. Aimee Echo was talking into the mike. &#8220;So a long time ago&#8230; there was a band in the nineties&#8230; called Human Waste Project&#8230; and we are them&#8230;&#8221;</p>

<p>Hang on&#8230; this is a new video&#8230; and then the opening riff gave me goose bumps&#8230;</p>

<p>I&#8217;m aware the sound quality is <em>awful</em> on the video, but here it is:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/V-fFg3b76j0" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p></p>

<p>A bit of frantic web searching promptly revealed that yes, gloriously, the band were back to together. At least to some extent. They&#8217;d played two shows in 2008 (well&#8230; more like one and a half, since the first one was actually the encore from a theSTART show) and were rehearsing for a reunion tour.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s when things like this come together that I&#8217;m given to smile inwardly and think that perhaps there is someone &#8220;up there&#8221; who likes me.</p>

<p>For what it&#8217;s worth, another lady who had an (arguably stronger) effect on my musical taste is Sandra Nasic. So, for the sake of completeness, here&#8217;s a couple of videos of her singing with her (now defunct) band, &#8220;Guano Apes&#8221;, and another of her providing guest vocals on an Apocalyptica song.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ifASH53DNXQ" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>




<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XvfYrKo1KGs" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p></p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/wCeMJR33fkg" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Apocalyptica, in case you were wondering, are a group of Finnish &#8216;cello players, who once exclusively played Metalica covers, but now play original material. Here&#8217;s another one, this time with Corey Taylor:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/OCqUR_iActA" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p></p>

<p>I think that&#8217;s enough music for now. Tootles.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Street Fighter Tutu]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/06/street-fighter-tutu/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-06T01:25:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/06/street-fighter-tutu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I like computer games. This isn&#8217;t news, really. Not in a hardcore live-to-game type way, more in a general fondness type way. That said, I did, as a youngster in an age before mobile phones, catch a bus to the next town so I could play a particular arcade game in what was (on reflection) a seriously dodgy little shop. That game was Street Fighter 2. It was a pretty great game, and it pretty much changed everything as far as the gaming industry was concerned. It spawned a bunch of sort of sequels which were mostly very popular, a couple of prequels, which were also very popular, and an actual sequel&#8230; which ditched most of the characters people loved and wasn&#8217;t quite as popular.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Coming out a couple of months is Street Fighter 4, a sequel to Street Fighter 2, but a prequel to Street Fighter 3. More about that later, but to complicate things further, there&#8217;s also a new version of Street Fighter 2, Super Street Fighter 2 Turbo HD Remix, or as I&#8217;d like to call it: &#8220;Street Fighter 2: Really Fricking Pretty Edition&#8221;. What it is is a revamped edition of the &#8220;original&#8221; Super Street Fighter 2 Turbo with redrawn graphics, new music and rebalanced game-play (all the characters are about equal now). So now (referring to the images below), instead of looking like the image on the left, the character Ken now looks like the image on the right.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Super_Street_Fighter_II_Turbo_HD_Remix"><img class="center" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/1/19/Hdstreetfighter.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Pretty cool, huh? What&#8217;s really weird, though, is that they didn&#8217;t change any of the game mechanics, so it still plays like it always did, thus:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/WbYrxVDPBbM" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Which is a little jarring, but apparently necessary. Why? Because there are still large touraments with this game and some people actually count the frames in order to get their combos right. Weird.</p>

<p>But what of Street Fighter 4? Well it&#8217;s still the same style of 2D fighting game, but it uses what I think is the most beautiful graphics engine I&#8217;ve ever seen:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.zath.co.uk/street-fighter-4-review-ps3/"><img class="center" src="http://cdn.zath.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/street-fighter-4-screenshot-1.jpg"></a></p>

<p>This gives it a gorgeous cell shaded / traditional Japanese art type look which I really like. Also, even though the game-play is 2D, the engine is 3D; meaning it&#8217;s not limited to pre-programmed graphics, and so Ryu can actually react to the fact that he&#8217;s probably about to get dropped on his head, in real time. What&#8217;s more, when you pull off a more spectacular move, the game can get a bit more cinematic on your ass:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.zath.co.uk/street-fighter-4-review-ps3/"><img class="center" src="http://cdn.zath.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/street-fighter-4-screenshot-2.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Credit where credit&#8217;s due: I stole all the images from <a href="http://www.wikipedia.org/">wikipedia</a> and <a href="http://www.zath.co.uk">Zath</a>. Click any of them to jump to the relevant article.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It Kneads the Dough]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/04/it-kneads-the-dough/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-04T19:06:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/04/it-kneads-the-dough</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like bread. I like it lot. So I was quite pleased when my parents gave me their bread machine and associated recipe book a couple of years ago. Their reasoning was (believe it or not) that I was the only one actually able to make bread with it. Their own attempts closely resembled articles suitable for construction, rather than ones suitable for mastication.</p>

<p>So I&#8217;ve used it on and off since then. Sometimes the bread was good (the sweet potato bread, for example, is awesome), sometimes it was bad (chick pea bread: no, no, no). Just lately I&#8217;ve been using it with renewed vigour, since I&#8217;ve resolved to avoid mass produced bread. Why (you might ask)? The short answer is that the methods used are damaging to the environment, in some respects the economy, and also to the digestive tract of the person who consumes it (which in my case would be me). The long answer is <a href="http://www.dolectures.co.uk/speakers/andrew-whitley">here</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Out of curiosity I decided to have a crack at the San Francisco sour dough recipe in the book. This takes about a week to make in total, uses no yeast (none that <em>you </em>add, anyway), and only uses the machine for the kneading and some of the mixing.</p>

<p>On the whole I&#8217;m not that impressed with it. I don&#8217;t actually know what sour dough is supposed to taste like (oops), but this one doesn&#8217;t taste that great and didn&#8217;t rise very well. That last one could be my fault, since I definitely messed up some of the timing.<br/>
Ahem.</p>

<p>Usually with a bread machine, the timing goes something like this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Put ingredients in the machine and push go.</li>
<li>Wait a couple of hours (about four in the case of my machine, depending on the recipe).</li>
<li>Remove bread from machine.</li>
</ol>


<p>That, you see, is the brilliance of it. It&#8217;s very simple and requires a distinct lack of effort on your part (aside from a scrupulous accuracy in the measurements). With the sour dough it&#8217;s more like this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Mix some stuff in a bowl.</li>
<li>Wait three days.</li>
<li>Add some stuff to the bowl.</li>
<li>Wait two days.</li>
<li>Add some more stuff to the bowl.</li>
<li>Wait twelve hours.</li>
<li>Put the contents of the bowl and some other things in the machine and push go on the dough setting.</li>
<li>Wait the time it takes to start mixing plus ten minutes.</li>
<li>Turn off the machine.</li>
<li>Wait eight hours.</li>
<li>Add some more stuff to the machine</li>
<li>Run an complete dough cycle (about two hours).</li>
<li>Take the dough out of the machine and knock it back.</li>
<li>Wait two hours.</li>
<li>Put it in the oven.</li>
<li>Wait twenty-five minutes.</li>
<li>Turn the oven down.</li>
<li>Wait ten minutes.</li>
<li>Remove bread from the oven.</li>
</ol>


<p>Couple this <em>small</em> amount of added complexity with the fact that I discovered I was missing a key ingredient around step 11 (which due to the timing was at 6 am)*, what you end up with is a near complete loss of the simplicity, an inferior product, and a dirty flappy paddle bread tin thing which is even harder to wash than it would have been if you&#8217;d actually baked the bread in it.</p>

<p>The point, in case you were starting to doubt that I had one, is that from now on I shall only be making relatively simple breads in the machine (and they can bloody well cook in there, as well). For fancier, more exciting breads I think I may well tread the same path as <a href="http://www.dougalstanton.net/blog">Dougal</a> (who pointed me in the direction of the above video), buy myself a copy of <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Dough-Richard-Bertinet/dp/1856267628/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1231095568&amp;sr=8-1">this</a> and prepare to get my hands dirty.</p>

<p>* Erm&#8230; and fell asleep for an hour too long around step 14.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
