<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[HarveyNick]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-03T21:20:44+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It Kneads the Dough]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/04/it-kneads-the-dough/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-04T19:06:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/04/it-kneads-the-dough</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like bread. I like it lot. So I was quite pleased when my parents gave me their bread machine and associated recipe book a couple of years ago. Their reasoning was (believe it or not) that I was the only one actually able to make bread with it. Their own attempts closely resembled articles suitable for construction, rather than ones suitable for mastication.</p>

<p>So I&#8217;ve used it on and off since then. Sometimes the bread was good (the sweet potato bread, for example, is awesome), sometimes it was bad (chick pea bread: no, no, no). Just lately I&#8217;ve been using it with renewed vigour, since I&#8217;ve resolved to avoid mass produced bread. Why (you might ask)? The short answer is that the methods used are damaging to the environment, in some respects the economy, and also to the digestive tract of the person who consumes it (which in my case would be me). The long answer is<br/>
<a href="http://www.dolectures.co.uk/speakers/andrew-whitley">here</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Out of curiosity I decided to have a crack at the San Francisco sour dough recipe in the book. This takes about a week to make in total, uses no yeast (none that <em>you </em>add, anyway), and only uses the machine for the kneading and some of the mixing.</p>

<p>On the whole I&#8217;m not that impressed with it. I don&#8217;t actually know what sour dough is supposed to taste like (oops), but this one doesn&#8217;t taste that great and didn&#8217;t rise very well. That last one could be my fault, since I definitely messed up some of the timing.<br/>
Ahem.</p>

<p>Usually with a bread machine, the timing goes something like this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Put ingredients in the machine and push go.</li>
<li>Wait a couple of hours (about four in the case of my machine, depending on the recipe).</li>
<li>Remove bread from machine.</li>
</ol>


<p>That, you see, is the brilliance of it. It&#8217;s very simple and requires a distinct lack of effort on your part (aside from a scrupulous accuracy in the measurements). With the sour dough it&#8217;s more like this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Mix some stuff in a bowl.</li>
<li>Wait three days.</li>
<li>Add some stuff to the bowl.</li>
<li>Wait two days.</li>
<li>Add some more stuff to the bowl.</li>
<li>Wait twelve hours.</li>
<li>Put the contents of the bowl and some other things in the machine and push go on the dough setting.</li>
<li>Wait the time it takes to start mixing plus ten minutes.</li>
<li>Turn off the machine.</li>
<li>Wait eight hours.</li>
<li>Add some more stuff to the machine</li>
<li>Run an complete dough cycle (about two hours).</li>
<li>Take the dough out of the machine and knock it back.</li>
<li>Wait two hours.</li>
<li>Put it in the oven.</li>
<li>Wait twenty-five minutes.</li>
<li>Turn the oven down.</li>
<li>Wait ten minutes.</li>
<li>Remove bread from the oven.</li>
</ol>


<p>Couple this <em>small</em> amount of added complexity with the fact that I discovered I was missing a key ingredient around step 11 (which due to the timing was at 6 am)*, what you end up with is a near complete loss of the simplicity, an inferior product, and a dirty flappy paddle bread tin thing which is even harder to wash than it would have been if you&#8217;d actually baked the bread in it.</p>

<p>The point, in case you were starting to doubt that I had one, is that from now on I shall only be making relatively simple breads in the machine (and they can bloody well cook in there, as well). For fancier, more exciting breads I think I may well tread the same path as <a href="http://www.dougalstanton.net/blog">Dougal</a> (who pointed me in the direction of the above video), buy myself a copy of <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Dough-Richard-Bertinet/dp/1856267628/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1231095568&amp;sr=8-1">this</a> and prepare to get my hands dirty.</p>

<p>* Erm&#8230; and fell asleep for an hour too long around step 14.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Objects of Desire]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/02/objects-of-desire/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-02T02:31:07+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/02/objects-of-desire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven&#8217;t blogged in some, so it seemed only natural that I should do the churlish thing and write about items I would like, but do not have, post Christmas.</p>

<p>First of all is a pod based coffee maker. When walking through House of Fraiser pre Christmas my beautiful and wonderful girlfriend had cause to exclaim &#8220;These are so cool*!&#8221; What she was talking about was a Nespresso machine (or more precisely a table full of them). Basically you pop a little pod of coffee in the top, push a button and really quite good espresso (or something a lot like it) comes out of the spout. Boom. Simple and fast, without any fuss or the need to do much in the way of cleaning. This appeals to me. A lot.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There is of course a problem. The clue is in the name, and being the intelligent general reader you may have already spotted it. The whole shebang is made (or at least owned) by Nestle, who are are (by my own personal set of benchmarks) evil. Like, actually killing babies evil. They make all the coffee which can be used with the machines, meaning there is a limited selection, and have patented the design thoroughly enough that this will be the case for ever-more. So, refillable pods are not an option and the pre-filled ones are aluminium and only recycle-able in Switzerland. Unacceptable. Bugger.</p>

<p>So I did a bit of reading about the other pod based systems out there, and discounted almost all of them for one reason or another. It generally comes down to either evil companies or an unacceptable degree of waste. The one I didn&#8217;t discount is the Senseo, which doesn&#8217;t produce such good coffee (it has a 2 bar pump versus the nespresso&#8217;s 19 bar), but you can buy refillable pods for it. Also, it&#8217;s cheaper. A lot cheaper since Sainsbury has it on sale at half price. Problem solved. I&#8217;ll probably pick one up tomorrow.</p>

<p>What I won&#8217;t b picking up tomorrow is one of Sony&#8217;s eBook readers. While I think they&#8217;re completely awesome (eInk rules, I though it was actual paper when I first saw it and didn&#8217;t even believe it was a screen until I saw it change) £350 is just too high an asking price. That&#8217;s a lot of books. Check them out if you get the chance, though. One day, when its price goes down and mine goes up, I&#8217;ll get myself one.</p>

<p>Lastly come the controversial one. Women carry bags. This is accepted. The size varies, though. I&#8217;ve seen at least one girl with a bag which, though clearly a handbag in terms of design, was about a metre long. Men on the other hand, are expected not to. If they do it is derisively referred to as a &#8220;Man Bag.&#8221; Frankly, though, it&#8217;s bloody useful. I tend to carry a messenger bag around a lot of the time as a result. It holds my tiny laptop, a notebook, some pens (duh), a reusable shopping bag and generally a book and some uni related things. The one I originally bought doesn&#8217;t really measure up, though, in either form or function. What I&#8217;m looking for is something stylish on the outside, but nerd-tastically well organised on the inside. Stylish that is, again, by my own personal set of benchmarks. I kinda like <a href="http://www.caselogic.com/15_4_canvas_messenger_bag/product_detail/index.cfm?modelid=113539">this one</a>. Now, if I could only find somewhere that actually sells it&#8230;<br/>
 <br/>
* Even though she, in fact, does not drink coffee. No one, it seems, is perfect.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Open Letter]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/10/24/an-open-letter/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-24T15:46:54+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/10/24/an-open-letter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Road User,</p>

<p>Should you be located in the UK and in possession of an automobile, you may have noticed a strange lever positioned to the left of your steering wheel (the circular device which changes the direction of your car). If you are of the inquisitive sort you may have also discovered a causal relationship (or at least a very strong correlation) between pushing this appendage in either of the upwards or downwards directions, and the flashing of two sets of orange lights positioned down the sides of your car.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&#8217;m here to assure you that this is a good thing and in no way the cause or result of black magic. The intention is that when you (the automobile operator) &#8220;turn&#8221; (to use the vernacular) you first activate one (but not both) of these sets of lights, thus apprising your fellow road users of your intentions. They would, of course, otherwise be forced to rely on telepathy. Telepathy is a dicey proposition at best, and one which should certainly not be attempted whilst simultaneously maneuvering around a ton of vehicular machinery. Contact of this sort with your cerebrum might also have the unfortunate side effect of causing them to &#8220;catch the stupid&#8221;.</p>

<p>Do not forget: You are in Britain. To not follow these simple precautions is not just dangerous, worse, it is <em>rude</em>.</p>

<p>Best Regards,</p>

<p>Cursing your Existence, That Last Roundabout.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sasanach]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/10/04/sasanack/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-04T16:10:09+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/10/04/sasanack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Helen&#8217;s comment on my previous entry put me in mind of what I&#8217;ve felt as the Scottish attitude towards England and the English more or less ever since I arrived here (seven years ago!). It goes something like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>The English? Bastards! We hate &#8216;em! Oh, but we&#8217;re not talking about you, of course. Dear me, no. More tea? Scone?</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<p>I am generalising massively here, but it is the case that though I&#8217;ve felt quite a bit of anti-English sentiment here (World Cup, anyone?), I&#8217;ve met seldom few who&#8217;ve had a problem with me because <em>I&#8217;m </em>English. The exceptions are a drunk old man out side the Cameo cinema (that encounter proved to be too humerous a story for me to bear him any real ill will) and a couple of drunk guys in a shady night club. The later was two separate events, with both unfolding more or less exactly like this:</p>

<p>Him: You&#8217;re English.<br/>
Me: Yes.<br/>
Him: What the fuck are you doing in Scotland, then?<br/>
Me: I might be English, but I chose to live in Scotland.<br/>
Him: Aye&#8230; well&#8230; fair play to you, then.</p>

<p>Quite a reasonable outcome, I thought. Things might have been different If I&#8217;d said &#8220;I&#8217;m here for the football,&#8221; or &#8220;I&#8217;ve come to have sex with your family,&#8221; though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Bristol Depressed Me, and Other Stories...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/10/02/why-bristol-depressed-me-and-other-stories/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-02T23:01:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/10/02/why-bristol-depressed-me-and-other-stories</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s not that I feel that Bristol is an intrinsically bad or depressing place. My attitude to it was coloured by the fact that I was a little tired of travelling, tired in general and didn&#8217;t entirely want to be there. Also, and this is the key fact, I&#8217;d just got back from Iceland. I liked Iceland a lot, despite the twelve hour days I felt almost no stress the entire I was there. There&#8217;s something very chilled about the place, and there was almost no traffic congestion, even considering that we drove through the middle of Reykjavik every morning during hush hour. But there&#8217;s something else.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I talk quite a bit about how safe I feel in Edinburgh. I&#8217;ll walk the length of the city at 3am, no problem. Not that this place is perfect. On my very first night we had to take a diversion on the way back from a night club to avoid a murder scene. But&#8230; the last time I tried to walking home after a few drinks back in Maltby a gang of around fifteen guys tried to start a fight with us, and then we had to hide out at a friend&#8217;s house and get a lift home in case they were waiting for us further down the road. This wasn&#8217;t even in a bad part of town, this was on High Street. Our actions weren&#8217;t out of the ordinary, we were just following the drill. Do you get the picture?</p>

<p>It&#8217;s not something I generally feel I have to worry about in Edinburgh, sasanach as I may be. In Reykjavik, though, we managed to&#8230; hhhmmm&#8230; how to phrase this without making myself and my colleague look like complete retards&#8230; nope&#8230; don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s possible&#8230; leave our belongings unguarded, unwatched and open to theft in an area of town, which, though out of the way, was frequented by the boy racer crowd. Nothing was stolen or even touched. The response we received to our astonishment regarding this: &#8220;Well, no&#8230; of course it wasn&#8217;t.&#8221; I didn&#8217;t see a single person I would describe as a Ned or a Chav the entire time I was there. Apparently they&#8217;re closing prisons <em>down</em>. It was nice.</p>

<p>Then I arrived in Bristol and found my self literally sounded by signs saying &#8220;Warning: bag snatchers operate in this area.&#8221;, &#8220;Pickpockets operate in this area.&#8221; and &#8220;Remove all valuables from your car.&#8221;</p>

<p>That&#8217;s what depressed me.</p>

<p>Enough of this talk, though! Here&#8217;s some more Jonathon Coulton for you:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j4TnhemCEmc" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I really wish I had a girlfriend right now, ideally one who was also a programmer, so I could giver her <a href="http://www.cafepress.com/jonathancoulton.58539188">these</a>. I&#8217;d probably get my arse <em>kicked</em> for it, but damn it would make me laugh&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flip side]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/30/flip-side/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-30T20:54:06+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/30/flip-side</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two updates in one day shocker!</p>

<p>The last one was a little downcast, though, and I felt a need to pass on something awesome by way of balance. Here it is:</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sxNmeMklFk8" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Perhaps you&#8217;re thinking &#8220;Huh? Who&#8217;s this guy?&#8221; or &#8220;What&#8217;s with the cake?&#8221;. You&#8217;ve been missing out if that&#8217;s the case. Jonathan Coulton (for that is the man&#8217;s name) is a computer programmer turned unlikely rock star (You scoff? He has a song in Rock Band. I&#8217;m having trouble thinking of a better benchmark), who&#8217;s become something of a geek standard thanks to the somewhat unlikely nature of his subject matter (one song has Pluto&#8217;s moon singing its condolences regarding its loss of planet status).</p>

<p>The song itself is the song over the closing credits of the game Portal, which is, quite frankly, an absolute fucking work of art. You probably know that I&#8217;m several different flavours of nerd and so JC&#8217;s* stuff appeals to me on a fairly base level , but I&#8217;m not a hardcore gamer. I have above average social skills, leave the house regularly and I prefer making love to playing computer games. There. I said it, and with a completely straight face. But that game is complete genius, through and through. I think Valve do amazing work in everything they do, and the fact they got JC* to write the song for the closing credits of one of their games makes me grin from ear to ear.</p>

<p>Check out some more of his stuff, it might make you smile. If you do and it does, leave a comment telling me about it, because that would make me smile**.</p>

<p>Update: His website is here <a href="http://www.jonathancoulton.com/">http://www.jonathancoulton.com/</a> And you can buy (and download for free) all his music there.<br/>
That is all.</p>

<p>* No, not <em>that</em> JC<br/>
** At the risk of me smiling so widely that the top of my head falls off.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ferðalangur]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/30/ferc3b0alangur/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-30T16:12:18+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/30/ferc3b0alangur</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been traveling around for work for the vast majority of the last month, so generally speaking I&#8217;ve been anything but at a loose end. Evenings were full of work or spent with the colleagues / friends I was traveling with. But now I&#8217;m back and finding that I don&#8217;t know what to do with myself a lot of the time. It&#8217;s giving me time to think about things, and that never ends well.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I think my PhD is in better shape than I had been supposing. I found a couple of stupid mistakes in my code today and now it actually seems to be working quite well. With a bit of tweaking of settings it might produce valid, or even impressive, output. This is good. It means I can stick to my plan to only put in eight hour days at the lab (though I might do a bit of writing up at home). An eight hour days feels pretty short just now. Thus the stress levels may reduce. I&#8217;ve more or less been running on stress and adrenaline/caffeine for the last few months though, so once again: time and head space to think about things.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s making me very uncertain about a lot of things. The financial market is clearly well up shit creak, and it ate its paddle some miles back. This also coincides with a financial meltdown of my own, precipitated by my funding running out and exacerbated by my purchase of a car. Yep, I reckon I&#8217;ll look back on that one as a particularly retarded mistake in years to come. I&#8217;ve got things on a more or less stable footing now, but my long term security is&#8230; clouded&#8230; not what I&#8217;d like it to be&#8230; in a lot of respects.</p>

<p>I also find myself thinking about sex, love, friendship, their relationship to each other, and my relationship to each. Things I had, things I&#8217;ve lost, and things I want in the future. I&#8217;m not feeling quite introspective enough to textualise any of that just now, but you should probably be thankful for that.</p>

<p>These are indeed uncertain times.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve also decided to try and get back into going to the gym. I&#8217;ve had no time for exercise in the last month and have probably been eating a little too well and it&#8217;s stating to show. I went for the first time in what feels like an age last night, and, you know what, it felt pretty good. I&#8217;ve missed that post gym sensation of having actually done something and made my muscles (such as they are) work for a living.</p>

<p>I just looked out of the window. The sun is shining! Time to go out into it, I suspect!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Yvan Petillot]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/16/being-yvan-petillot/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-16T22:19:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/16/being-yvan-petillot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So.</p>

<p>There I was, sitting across from a senior manager from Thales and two Professors, one each from Cambridge and Robert Gordon&#8217;s Universities, discussing the precise definition of the term “emergent behaviour”&#8230;</p>

<p>Wait.</p>

<p>No.</p>

<p>Rewind.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Thanks to my current uncharacteristically basy schedule, I arrived late to the Forum on Unmanned Systems and Artificial Intelligence, an event designed to facilitate a high level discussion of these areas, and create the beginnings of a coherent plan for their future. In order to do this it brought together the foremost expects in the relevant fields, from both industry and academia.</p>

<p>And me.</p>

<p>Ah. No. See, there&#8217;s a serious failure in continuity and a complete lack of explanation here. I am a terrible narrator (and worse still, I&#8217;m stealing Shane Black&#8217;s material). Rewind <em>again</em>.</p>

<p>Actually invited to this forum were exhibits A, B and C. Namely: Doctors Yvan Petillot (Head of the Vision and Robotics course at Heriot-Watt University and SeeByte Chief Technical Officer) and Jonathan Evans (Former Head of Research a the Ocean Systems Laboratory and SeeByte Head of Engineering), and Professor David Lane (Head of Ocean Systems Laboratory and SeeByte Chief <em>Executive</em> Officer and Board Chairman).</p>

<p>Enter stage left: Exhibit D, yon plucky PhD student and sometime SeeByte “Development Engineer”, myself. Exhibits A, B and C were unable to attend for various reasons, and so Exhibit A (that&#8217;s Dr Petillot for those of you not keeping track) asked me to attend in his stead, get a feel for what was going on, and fly the respective SeeByte and OSL flags. This suggestion was redoubled by Exhibit B, but never actually discussed with Exhibit C, who&#8217;s inclusion in the program suggests the organisers were in some doubt regarding his attendance, or the lack thereof. This is not unusual.</p>

<p>And so, a mere 12 hours after arriving back in my beloved Edinburgh, fresh from my jaunt to Iceland (which I will write about in due course, once I can trust myself not to gush too unabashedly), I caught a plane to Bristol (it has a very impressive bridge, you know) and subsequently found myself in a room surrounded by people considerably more qualified and important than I. I&#8217;ll leave it to you to make a judgement as to where on the scale between “high opinion of me” and “low opinion of this forum” the exact mark which led to this eventuality lies.</p>

<p>But what of it? I strongly suspect that I shouldn&#8217;t go into much (or indeed any) detail yet, and the detail might in fact be supremely boring to the vast majority of readers. Suffice to say that it was an interesting experience, if frustrating reminiscent of the episode of The Simpsons in which the MENSA members take control of Springfield for much of its second day.</p>

<p>I found Bristol quite depressing, but for the reasoning behind that you&#8217;ll have to wait until I&#8217;ve talked about Iceland some. For context, you see.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Well... Here I am...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/02/well-here-i-am/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-02T20:42:40+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/02/well-here-i-am</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#8230;In Iceland!</p>

<p>I wanted to come here for a long time (this is no secret), and as the result of a highly unsubtle campaign of strategic hint dropping, here I find myself. It&#8217;s not under ideal circumstances, though. I&#8217;m here for work and so I&#8217;ll be spending most of my time working 12 hour days, doing fiddly embedded computer programming and ridding about in boats waiting for robots to do their thing. I&#8217;m also here with my boss (or someone far higher up the chain of command than myself, at least), and though he&#8217;s a really nice guy there&#8217;s always going to be a significant disconnect. He&#8217;s not my first choice(s)* to share this experience with. I&#8217;d rather be here with my friends. My friends are awesome, you see.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>A particular subset of my awesome friends, appropriately: the Icelandic ones, have furnished me with a list of things I might like to see, do and eat while I&#8217;m here. It&#8217;s not a challenge on the scale of &#8220;cook every single recipe in a recipe book&#8221;, but it&#8217;s a fun list all the same and one I plan on making an impression on. I&#8217;ve found a guide to Icelandic punctuation online and am even working up to actually asking for some of the foodstuffs on the list, rather than simply writing them down, pointing at them and smiling hopefully. We&#8217;ll see how it goes. Hopefully it won&#8217;t be a repeat of the Turkish &#8220;thank you&#8221; debacle**.</p>

<p>So far I like it here. It&#8217;s pleasantly calm and quiet (except for the boy racers who just went screaming past the office). We went for Italian food last night (not my choice), but I&#8217;m hoping for something a little more geographically appropriate tonight. Perhaps I&#8217;ll try puffin, it&#8217;s always good to try new things. More news as I get it.</p>

<p>It might amuse some of you to know that I&#8217;ve typed this while my boss was out of the room, launching into a long explanation of&#8230; something.</p>

<p>More news as I get it.</p>

<p>* Why is there no legitimate plural for &#8220;first choice&#8221;? That&#8217;s a linguistic deficiency, right there&#8230;</p>

<p>** It&#8217;s about 20 syllables long and never elicited anything more than a blank stare from anyone we said it to.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Celtx on the Acer Aspire One]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/24/mdl-celtx-on-the-acer-aspire-one/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-24T21:23:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/24/mdl-celtx-on-the-acer-aspire-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I managed to get the Celtx screenwriting (and general preproduction) software up and running on my shiny new AA1, and in the interests of sharing the knowledge I thought I&#8217;d post how I did it. Please note, this should also work as general recipe for installing any software not available under the package manager in Linpus Light Linux (provided there are no additional dependencies).</p>

<p>First of all you need to download the software from the downloads page of the Celtx website, <a href="http://www.celtx.com/download.html">here</a>. I&#8217;d recomend getting the straight up Linux version in your choice of language (frustratingly there is no option for British English, though). There is an Asus eee specific version, but that just clears up some dependencies and doesn&#8217;t really provide you with anything extra.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First of all you&#8217;ll need a terminal, so hit Alt+F2, type &#8220;terminal&#8221; (without the quotes) and hit enter. A terminal should have popped up. If you&#8217;re a Linux novice, don&#8217;t worry, you should just be able to copy and paste everything from this page.<br/>
Now you need to unpackage the software. I put it in /opt, because it generally seems to be a dumping ground for user installed applications (as far as I can tell). Type these in the terminal one at a time:</p>

<pre><code>cd /opt

sudo tar -xf /home/user/Downloads/Celtx.tar.gz
</code></pre>

<p>Now, if you type &#8220;ls&#8221; you should see a directory named celtx. So far so good. Next you need to add a link so Celtx can be run from the command line, like this:</p>

<pre><code>sudo ln -s /opt/celtx/celtx /usr/bin/celtx
</code></pre>

<p>In theory that&#8217;s all you need to do. Now if you type &#8220;celtx&#8221; on the command line (or after hitting Alt+F2) the program will run. We can make it a lot easier than that, though. Next we need an icon to represent it on the desktop. There are two options here. First of all you could use an existing one. Type this:</p>

<pre><code>sudo thunar /usr/share/pixmaps
</code></pre>

<p>A file manager window should pop up and if you scroll down you&#8217;ll find all the system icons. If you find one you want to use for Celtx: cool, if you don&#8217;t then you&#8217;re other option is to make one. I&#8217;m not going to get into that, but if you want to do it please bare in mind that is has to be a png, it has to be 90px x 90px in size and it has to be placed in that directory. I found one on the web and resized it myself. Assuming you have the icon you want in the downloads directory and it&#8217;s called &#8220;celtx.png&#8221;, you would type this to get it in the right place:</p>

<pre><code>sudo mv /home/user/Downloads/celtx.png /usr/share/pixmaps/celtx.png
</code></pre>

<p>That done we need to create a desktop entry for it. You need to use a text editor for this. I used &#8220;vim&#8221;, so that&#8217;s what the directions here will say. &#8220;vim&#8221; can be pretty hard to use at first, though, so if you&#8217;re not linux minded you might want to find a tutorial on the web, or replace the &#8220;vim&#8221; command with something else (mousepad is one option that might be easier to use and more familiar). We start by (basically) creating the file:</p>

<pre><code>sudo vim /usr/share/applications/Celtx.desktop
</code></pre>

<p>If you&#8217;re using vim, hit &#8220;i&#8221; (the word &#8220;insert&#8221; should appear at the bottom) and then paste the following into the file:</p>

<pre><code>[Desktop Entry]
Version=1.0
Encoding=UTF-8
Name=Celtx
Name[zh_TW]=Celtx
Name[zh_TW]=Celtx
Name[zh_CN]=Celtx
Name[de]=Celtx
Name[it]=Celtx
Name[fr]=Celtx
Name[es]=Celtx
Name[pt]=Celtx
Name[nl]=Celtx
Name[ja]=Celtx
Name[ru]=Celtx
GenericName=Celtx
GenericName[zh_TW]=Celtx
GenericName[zh_CN]=Celtx
GenericName[de]=Celtx
GenericName[it]=Celtx
GenericName[fr]=Celtx
GenericName[es]=Celtx
GenericName[pt]=Celtx
GenericName[nl]=Celtx
GenericName[ja]=Celtx
GenericName[ru]=Celtx
Comment=Write and edit media scripts
Exec=celtx
Icon=Celtx.png
Terminal=false
Type=Application
StartupWMClass=celtx-bin
MimeType=text/html;text/xml;application/xhtml+xml;application/vnd.mozilla.xul+xml;text/mml;application/x-shockwave-flash;
X-Desktop-File-Install-Version=0.10
Categories=Work;
StartupNotify=true
</code></pre>

<p>Be sure to replace &#8220;Celtx.png&#8221; with whatever the icon you want to use is called. Also, all those language options are possibly not strictly necessary, but I copied most of this from another file and left them in to be on the safe side. Likewise, I could probably have done something a bit more clever with the &#8220;MimeType&#8221; bit, but decided not to bother. Next, save and exit the file. In &#8220;vim&#8221;, you hit escape, then type:</p>

<pre><code>:wq
</code></pre>

<p>and hit enter. Lastly, we just need to tell Linpus to display Celtx on the desktop:</p>

<pre><code>vim /home/user/.config/xfce4/desktop/group-app.xml
</code></pre>

<p>You should now be looking at an XML file. You need to find this:</p>

<pre><code>&lt;id&gt;6&lt;/id&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>And insert this underneath it:</p>

<pre><code>&lt;app sequence="2"&gt;/usr/share/applications/Celtx.desktop&lt;/app&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>Be sure to increase the &#8220;sequence&#8221; numbers on the other &#8220;&lt;app>&#8221; entries as well, to make sure there are no duplicates.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s about all there is to it. If you reboot the machine you should now find that you have an icon for Celtx on the desktop. After you put some .celtx files on the machine, you might want to right click on one and select &#8220;properties&#8221;, then tell Limpus to open the file type with Celtx (otherwise it&#8217;ll just treat it like a zip file).</p>

<p>This is quite a long post and I have work to do, but I might return in the next couple of days with some things to say about Celtx itself. Happy hunting!</p>

<p>PS Thanks to the users of the forums on aspireoneuser.com for the knowledge which was needed to work this out.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'll see your eee and raise you One]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/18/my-digital-life-ill-see-your-eee-and-raise-you-one/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-18T22:53:47+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/18/my-digital-life-ill-see-your-eee-and-raise-you-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My good friend Dougal got himself an Asus eee pc (relatively) recently. He likes it a lot. I like the idea of it, but not so much the implementation. On his version at least, the screen is too small for me, and the later versions are a bit too pricey. I love the idea of a small, light and eminently carriable laptop though. It&#8217;s the premise I originally bought my MacBook under, but I found even that machine to be too bulky and heavy to carry around constantly. The MacBook Air might work, but it&#8217;s very expensive (from the direction I&#8217;m looking at it from, anyway) and not really something I&#8217;d be prepared to pull out of my bag and start working on while sitting on the Meadows.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So I bought myself an Acer Aspire One. I like it quite a bit. I was worried about the size of the keyboard, but it&#8217;s fine; I&#8217;m typing this on it right now. The fact that I don&#8217;t (deliberately) touch type is probably an advantage in this case. I comes with 8 GB of SSD (hard drive, basically) which doesn&#8217;t sound like a lot these days, but I&#8217;ve already bought an extension to this (just waiting for it to arrive). The RAM is also a little low, so I&#8217;m thinking of upgrading that. It&#8217;s not expensive at all, but it is very fiddly, so I guess we&#8217;ll see. I don&#8217;t like laptop touchpads in general, and the one on the one is particularly lame, so I have a two part plan to help with this. The first part is software based and I&#8217;ll come to that later. The second though is yet another fiddly hardware upgrade (how exciting!), namely the installation of a touchscreen. Battery life isn&#8217;t great, so I might get a spare, or an external backup.</p>

<p>The next concern is software. This machine is basically intended to be a glorified word processor, so most of what I want it to run is writing software. Writing in this case means:</p>

<ul>
<li>Blogging (like this)</li>
<li>Work (Thesis, papers etc)</li>
<li>Screen Writing (be nice to get back into this)</li>
<li>General Purpose Writing (of course)</li>
</ul>


<p>and also:</p>

<ul>
<li>Keyboard Control</li>
<li>Synchronisation with my real computer</li>
</ul>


<p>The first obstacle here is the operating system. It currently runs Limpus Light Linux, which I recently heard referred to as “Linux for Pussies”. Unfortunate turn of phrase aside, this description isn&#8217;t too far off the mark. It&#8217;s very simple, very easy too use and boots in about ten seconds. But it&#8217;s also not as easy to customise. It seems that it is possible to install OSX on the One (always my first choice of operating system these days), but due to the lack of Apple hardware it would be crippled to some extent. Even so, it would make finding the other software I need a lot easier, because Open Source and Graphical User Interfaces DO NOT MIX. It&#8217;s one of those instances where to get what you pay for. Open source command line applications are almost uniformly fantastic, but anything with a GUI will probably look like the developer just shat on the floor when asked and then got his dog to do it while he cleaned up the mess. The two serious open source advocates I know both confess to a dislike of doing anything graphical, so maybe it&#8217;s symptomatic. I dunno.</p>

<p>There are exceptions, of course. Eclipse is one, to a lesser extent so is Firefox. Also an exception is the currently gestating Netbook Remix of Ubuntu Linux, which might just be exactly what the doctor ordered, operating system wise. As far as I can tell it&#8217;s not quite ready for public consumption yet, though. As soon as it is I&#8217;ll probably switch, but for the time being I&#8217;ll hack away at the Limpus until I get something workable.<br/>
I&#8217;ll probably use Open Office (with actually runs quite quickly on this machine) for most of the writing, with Celtx (surprisingly good and free) for the screen writing and maybe Kyle for Latex formatting.</p>

<p>Gnome Do should take care of the keyboard control. It&#8217;s a clone of Quicksilver on OSX which works pretty well. It&#8217;ll never work <em>as</em> well, since the architecture of OSX supports this sort of thing better, but it comes close enough. For the synchronisation I&#8217;ll try and set up a custom rsync script to move things back and forward between this machine and my Mac, and then I&#8217;ll do most of the heavy formatting and posting and such from there when possible.<br/>
Speaking of which&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is it still limping if you're doing it with both legs?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/12/is-it-still-limping-if-youre-doing-it-with-both-legs/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-12T14:54:11+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/12/is-it-still-limping-if-youre-doing-it-with-both-legs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Friday night I went to the Silent Disco and danced away until 4 am. On the whole I think it was excellent. I think it (or some progression of it) might well be the future of night clubs. It was £10 entry, which might seem a little expensive, but is really no more than the entry to a lot of clubs in Edinburgh. The music was also quite mainstream, and not the hardcore dance I was expecting, which is good because I think his sort of thing is a lot more fun when you can shout along with the words. Especially when you can take of your headphones and watch everyone dancing away without there being any apparent music.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Then on Saturday I drove through to Dunbar with Helen and Dougal to attend a ceilidh for our friend Matt&#8217;s sister, who is leaving the country. What the hell was I doing there? I was invited mostly for my Y chromosome, since it was thought there would be a near overwhelming majority of female types present. This never in fact materialised, leaving me feeling that I was massively intruding (situations like this bring out the English in me to an alarming extent&#8230; I feel as though I can&#8217;t say &#8220;please&#8221;, &#8220;thank you&#8221; and of course &#8220;sorry&#8221; nearly enough). I had a really good time though, and enjoyed the dancing a lot&#8230; even though it&#8217;s the only ceilidh I have clear memories of participating in. Luckily I had a good impromptu dance teacher and I don&#8217;t think I embarrassed myself <em>too</em> much.</p>

<p>I stayed in Dunbar at Helen&#8217;s parent&#8217;s house on Saturday night and then went for long (well&#8230; more mid length) walk around the town the next morning, after a truly fantastic breakfast. Then I was invited to have lunch with Dougal and his parents, which was very pleasant. Still don&#8217;t feel I said those three magical phrases enough at any of those places, but all in all it made for a most enjoyable weekend.</p>

<p>Yesterday, though, I woke up and could barely walk. I seem to have strained both my calves, which really isn&#8217;t ideal. I suspect that I over used them during the weekend and know the muscles are trying to build themselves up. I have hyper-tense muscles in my legs (I think that&#8217;s the phrase the physio used), which on the one hand sometimes means that they resemble steel cables (which is nice), but I can&#8217;t even come close to touching my toes with my legs straight. I suspect this is a participating factor.</p>

<p>Ouch.</p>

<p>As a result of this I&#8217;ve been doing some work from home, as I suspect driving isn&#8217;t such a great idea just now. I could catch the bus in to the University&#8230; but&#8230; well&#8230; I just don&#8217;t want to. Writing up ahoy!</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s a bit more Swedish music for you, this time of a much more melodic nature:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=saTz3vNW3UQ" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Nevertheless, this is the same singer who appears on &#8220;Dead End&#8221; by In Flames, which is from the exact opposite end of the musical spectrum.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclecticism]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/05/eclecticism/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-05T15:02:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/05/eclecticism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seems the Facebook app does not do what it&#8217;s supposed to. Never mind, I shall content myself with the (better) Wordpress interface. Maybe I&#8217;ll look into writing a Facebook app which interfaces with my RSS feed. That would be cool.</p>

<p>I thought I would write a music related post, since I found a couple of things on YouTube which piqued my interest. First an entirely serious one:</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/vIhJC2-UNZA" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>When I first heard this on the radio I thought it sounded so fresh they must be a new band. But no, they&#8217;ve been around quite a while, I even knew other songs by them. Unfortunately I don&#8217;t like many of them, but you can&#8217;t have everything. Apparently.</p>

<p>Next, something quite different. Helen played me this at a dinner party on Saturday night for the comedy value. I went looking for it on YouTube, mostly out of curiosity regarding the identity of the female singer, and found a live version. Promise me you&#8217;ll listen to at least some of it, and not just hit stop as soon as the guitars start. It might make you smile.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/nAR4ieUrxUM" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I think I genuinely like this. It helps that I actually like ABBA. I think they wrote really good songs. I also love cross genre covers, and this is definitely that. The female singer&#8217;s voice really works for me as well. I had a look for some of their other stuff, but it&#8217;s really not good, not good at all. It seems they split and formed two entirely new bands, both of which are a slight improvement, though.</p>

<p>Told you I had eclectic taste. Here are a couple more for your edification:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/OyZqpRxnHWg" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p></p>

<p>A soft one to start off with. Dido is so much better live. In my opinion her voice is perfect, but sounds overly processed on her recordings.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/YgrMfRYCRgw" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Bit of a heavier one, there. This is about as heavy as my taste in music gets. I love the singer&#8217;s voice, though. If you&#8217;re confused by this wait for the chorus. If you don&#8217;t have the pertinence for that, try this one by the same band:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/wAfRW_RMK4M" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>See? The band, if you&#8217;re interested, are called &#8220;In Flames&#8221;. Look up a song called &#8220;Dead End&#8221; if you want to know what happens when a Swedish metal (death metal? pop metal? disco metal? death pop disco metal?) band collaborates with a Swedish pop singer song writer&#8230;</p>

<p>How about another soft one? Okay, but I&#8217;m going to get it from an unexpected place:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Waw61eE9FyY" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Yes, that was Slipknot. Bet you didn&#8217;t see that coming.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll skew a bit heavier again, but not too far.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/hiHBiRRB1Mw" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I&#8217;m a little disappointed that YouTube couldn&#8217;t supply &#8220;Father&#8217;s Daughter&#8221; from &#8220;Like a Bolt of Lightning&#8221;, but this will do.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m tempted to throw in a bit of Massive Attack, a bit of Evanescence, a bit of Killswitch Engage&#8230; but this post really could go on for ever, so I&#8217;ll stop it here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting again... again.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/03/starting-again-again/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-03T22:36:54+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/03/starting-again-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Blogging.</p>

<p>By my count I&#8217;ve had three previous attempts (on different services), none of which has entirely worked out. The problems which cause this to be are multiple, but two in particular tend to stand out. Firstly, I tend to write long rambling posts which take a lot of effort, and secondly I tend to not believe that anyone is actually reading them.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So I&#8217;ve come up with the two pronged strategy to try and solve this. First of all, I&#8217;m going to try and make it easier for me to blog. Thus, I&#8217;m switching to WordPress. Why does this make things easier? Well, it means that I can use their software to blog from my iPhone (which will theoretically also lead to shorter posts) and I can also use the web interface.</p>

<p>Thus I can blog from (literally) anywhere, where as before I could only do it from my home computer, as I was using iWeb. I still think iWeb is an awesome program, but I was using a small portion of it&#8217;s functionality, and thus a more bespoke solution becomes a better idea.</p>

<p>Secondly, I&#8217;m going to try and advertise it a bit better. So the particular web interface I&#8217;m using is the WordPress facebook application, which should drop a thingy into my friends&#8217; feeds when I write a new post. Maybe some will read it. Hopefully not too many will find it massively annoying. I like this synergy, it&#8217;s certainly not something I could accomplish using iWeb.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m going to transfer over my previous film reviews, but stripped down without the header and the footer, and make this blog a bit prettier over the next couple of days. I&#8217;m also going to finish the my digital life post I start an age ago, so come back, ya&#8217; hear?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
