<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[HarveyNick]]></title>
  <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-12-27T21:05:13+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://harveynick.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is it still limping if you're doing it with both legs?]]></title>
    <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/12/is-it-still-limping-if-youre-doing-it-with-both-legs/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-12T14:54:11+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/12/is-it-still-limping-if-youre-doing-it-with-both-legs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On Friday night I went to the Silent Disco and danced away until 4 am. On the whole I think it was excellent. I think it (or some progression of it) might well be the future of night clubs. It was £10 entry, which might seem a little expensive, but is really no more than the entry to a lot of clubs in Edinburgh. The music was also quite mainstream, and not the hardcore dance I was expecting, which is good because I think his sort of thing is a lot more fun when you can shout along with the words. Especially when you can take of your headphones and watch everyone dancing away without there being any apparent music.<br/>
Then on Saturday I drove through to Dunbar with Helen and Dougal to attend a ceilidh for our friend Matt&#8217;s sister, who is leaving the country. What the hell was I doing there? I was invited mostly for my Y chromosome, since it was thought there would be a near overwhelming majority of female types present. This never in fact materialised, leaving me feeling that I was massively intruding (situations like this bring out the English in me to an alarming extent&#8230; I feel as though I can&#8217;t say &#8220;please&#8221;, &#8220;thank you&#8221; and of course &#8220;sorry&#8221; nearly enough). I had a really good time though, and enjoyed the dancing a lot&#8230; even though it&#8217;s the only ceilidh I have clear memories of participating in. Luckily I had a good impromptu dance teacher and I don&#8217;t think I embarrassed myself <em>too</em> much.<br/>
I stayed in Dunbar at Helen&#8217;s parent&#8217;s house on Saturday night and then went for long (well&#8230; more mid length) walk around the town the next morning, after a truly fantastic breakfast. Then I was invited to have lunch with Dougal and his parents, which was very pleasant. Still don&#8217;t feel I said those three magical phrases enough at any of those places, but all in all it made for a most enjoyable weekend.<br/>
Yesterday, though, I woke up and could barely walk. I seem to have strained both my calves, which really isn&#8217;t ideal. I suspect that I over used them during the weekend and know the muscles are trying to build themselves up. I have hyper-tense muscles in my legs (I think that&#8217;s the phrase the physio used), which on the one hand sometimes means that they resemble steel cables (which is nice), but I can&#8217;t even come close to touching my toes with my legs straight. I suspect this is a participating factor.<br/>
Ouch.<br/>
As a result of this I&#8217;ve been doing some work from home, as I suspect driving isn&#8217;t such a great idea just now. I could catch the bus in to the University&#8230; but&#8230; well&#8230; I just don&#8217;t want to. Writing up ahoy!<br/>
Here&#8217;s a bit more Swedish music for you, this time of a much more melodic nature:<br/>
[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=saTz3vNW3UQ]<br/>
Nevertheless, this is the same singer who appears on &#8220;Dead End&#8221; by In Flames, which is from the exact opposite end of the musical spectrum.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In search of shiny Swedish music]]></title>
    <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/07/in-search-of-shiny-swedish-music/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-07T22:13:49+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/07/in-search-of-shiny-swedish-music</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So in my last (none film review) blog entry I posted a video by a Swedish goth metal band called &#8220;Beseech&#8221; and then mentioned that they&#8217;d split to form two other bands.<br/>
I was bored waiting for code to run today and did a little digging. Seems there&#8217;s a bit more too it than that. The female singer joined formed another band called The Mary Major, which also has a male singer.<br/>
The male singer from Beseech is called Erik. He has a beard and long hair.<br/>
The male singer from The Mary Major is also called Erik and also has a beard, but has <em>short</em> hair and <em>wears a hat</em>.<br/>
But I am not fooled! Though he dons a disguise, my eyes do not lie! For it is he, the same Penniless Sitar Player! Wait&#8230; no&#8230; that&#8217;s not right&#8230;<br/>
Anyway. In my opinion they aren&#8217;t very good. They do have one song I like, though. It&#8217;s called &#8220;Split&#8221; and you can find it on their myspace page, here:<br/>
<a href="http://www.myspace.com/themarymajor">The Mary Major</a><br/>
Others members of Beseech formed a band called Those We Don&#8217;t Speak Of (TWDSO, henceforth), and their story is a little more interesting. Also, their music is better. Among the musicians who also joined the band was singer Sara Löfgren, an established singer songwriter. That interests me because it pretty much never happens here. Their home page seems to be down (I&#8217;ll try and shed some light on that in a moment), but you can find some music here:<br/>
<a href="http://trig.com/twdso"></a><a href="http://www.myspace.com/twdso">TWDSO at MySpace</a><br/>
I quite like it. Not a lot of subtlety to be found, no, but there&#8217;s a propulsive quality to the music I enjoy very much. Also I&#8217;m a complete sucker for a powerful female voice over the top of a driving heavy rhythm.<br/>
But wait&#8230; there&#8217;s more. It seems Sara Löfgren left the band due to pregnancy and was replaced by another established solo artist. This time one Emma Varg, and you can listen to her here:<br/>
<a href="http://www.myspace.com/emmavargmusic">Emma Varg at MySpace</a><br/>
She also has a (mostly) working home page, here:<br/>
<a href="http://www.emmavarg.com">Emma Varg</a><br/>
<a href="http://www.emmavarg.com"></a>&#8230;which says she is looking for new members to join her band&#8230; and that was circa February 2008. Also, no mention of TWDSO and a lot of media links are broken on the site. Confusing, no? I&#8217;ll come back to that, because first I want to talk about her music. Again, I like it, for much the same reasons as previously mentioned. There&#8217;s also a brazen quality to her lyrics I like&#8230; and the closest we get to that in the UK is the Sugar Babes singing &#8220;..who do you want me to be, to make you sleep with me&#8230;&#8221;<br/>
I find I really want to listen to this new band, but am a little starved of information. Emma Varg&#8217;s MySpace says that she&#8217;s taking over on a temporary basis until she gets her new band members, but another interview suggested she was a permanent replacement. I almost suspect this new band will have a different name, that would explain the missing / broken home pages.<br/>
I also learned a new Swedish music related word today: Melodeath. I have resolved to find out more about it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclecticism]]></title>
    <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/05/eclecticism/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-05T15:02:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/05/eclecticism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seems the Facebook app does not do what it&#8217;s supposed to. Never mind, I shall content myself with the (better) Wordpress interface. Maybe I&#8217;ll look into writing a Facebook app which interfaces with my RSS feed. That would be cool.</p>

<p>I thought I would write a music related post, since I found a couple of things on YouTube which piqued my interest. First an entirely serious one:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vIhJC2-UNZA]</p>

<p>When I first heard this on the radio I thought it sounded so fresh they must be a new band. But no, they&#8217;ve been around quite a while, I even knew other songs by them. Unfortunately I don&#8217;t like many of them, but you can&#8217;t have everything. Apparently.</p>

<p>Next, something quite different. Helen played me this at a dinner party on Saturday night for the comedy value. I went looking for it on YouTube, mostly out of curiosity regarding the identity of the female singer, and found a live version. Promise me you&#8217;ll listen to at least some of it, and not just hit stop as soon as the guitars start. It might make you smile.</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nAR4ieUrxUM]</p>

<p>I think I genuinely like this. It helps that I actually like ABBA. I think they wrote really good songs. I also love cross genre covers, and this is definitely that. The female singer&#8217;s voice really works for me as well. I had a look for some of their other stuff, but it&#8217;s really not good, not good at all. It seems they split and formed two entirely new bands, both of which are a slight improvement, though.</p>

<p>Told you I had eclectic taste. Here are a couple more for your edification:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OyZqpRxnHWg]</p>

<p>A soft one to start off with. Dido is so much better live. In my opinion her voice is perfect, but sounds overly processed on her recordings.</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YgrMfRYCRgw]</p>

<p>Bit of a heavier one, there. This is about as heavy as my taste in music gets. I love the singer&#8217;s voice, though. If you&#8217;re confused by this wait for the chorus. If you don&#8217;t have the pertinence for that, try this one by the same band:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wAfRW_RMK4M]</p>

<p>See? The band, if you&#8217;re interested, are called &#8220;In Flames&#8221;. Look up a song called &#8220;Dead End&#8221; if you want to know what happens when a Swedish metal (death metal? pop metal? disco metal? death pop disco metal?) band collaborates with a Swedish pop singer song writer&#8230;</p>

<p>How about another soft one? Okay, but I&#8217;m going to get it from an unexpected place:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Waw61eE9FyY]</p>

<p>Yes, that was Slipknot. Bet you didn&#8217;t see that coming.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll skew a bit heavier again, but not too far.</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hiHBiRRB1Mw]</p>

<p>I&#8217;m a little disappointed that YouTube couldn&#8217;t supply &#8220;Father&#8217;s Daughter&#8221; from &#8220;Like a Bolt of Lightning&#8221;, but this will do.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m tempted to throw in a bit of Massive Attack, a bit of Evanescence, a bit of Killswitch Engage&#8230; but this post really could go on for ever, so I&#8217;ll stop it here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Starting again... again.]]></title>
    <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/03/starting-again-again/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-03T22:36:54+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/03/starting-again-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Blogging.</p>

<p>By my count I&#8217;ve had three previous attempts (on different services), none of which has entirely worked out. The problems which cause this to be are multiple, but two in particular tend to stand out. Firstly, I tend to write long rambling posts which take a lot of effort, and secondly I tend to not believe that anyone is actually reading them.</p>

<p>So I&#8217;ve come up with the two pronged strategy to try and solve this. First of all, I&#8217;m going to try and make it easier for me to blog. Thus, I&#8217;m switching to WordPress. Why does this make things easier? Well, it means that I can use their software to blog from my iPhone (which will theoretically also lead to shorter posts) and I can also use the web interface.</p>

<p>Thus I can blog from (literally) anywhere, where as before I could only do it from my home computer, as I was using iWeb. I still think iWeb is an awesome program, but I was using a small portion of it&#8217;s functionality, and thus a more bespoke solution becomes a better idea.</p>

<p>Secondly, I&#8217;m going to try and advertise it a bit better. So the particular web interface I&#8217;m using is the WordPress facebook application, which should drop a thingy into my friends&#8217; feeds when I write a new post. Maybe some will read it. Hopefully not too many will find it massively annoying. I like this synergy, it&#8217;s certainly not something I could accomplish using iWeb.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m going to transfer over my previous film reviews, but stripped down without the header and the footer, and make this blog a bit prettier over the next couple of days. I&#8217;m also going to finish the my digital life post I start an age ago, so come back, ya&#8217; hear?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
