<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-18T17:53:30+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Simplifying the Landscape]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/12/01/simplifying-the-landscape/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-01T09:28:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/12/01/simplifying-the-landscape</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the end of the <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/22/now-in-eye-popping-3d/">last post</a> I wrote about the actual implementation of my Clockwork Aphid project, I said the next step was going to be display simplification. At that point I&#8217;d generated a few landscapes which were just starting barely starting to test the limits of my computer, though they were nothing like the size or complexity I had in mind. That said, it was looking at landscapes containing 1579008 polygons and it was obvious that not all of these needed to be put on screen. Moreover, because my landscapes are essentially made up of discrete samples (or nodes): I needed to reduce the number of samples which were displayed to the user, otherwise my performance was really going to tank as the landscapes increased in size.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Shamus Young talked about terrain simplification <a href="http://www.shamusyoung.com/twentysidedtale/?p=142">some time ago</a> during his original terrain project. This seemed as good a place as any to start, so I grabbed a copy of <a href="http://citeseer.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/summary?doi=10.1.1.14.4771">the paper</a> he used to build his algorithm. I didn&#8217;t find it as complicated as it appears he did, but this is probably because I&#8217;m more used to reading papers like this (I must have read hundreds during my PhD, and even wrote a couple), so I&#8217;m reasonably fluent in academicese. It was, as I suspected, a good starting point, though I wouldn&#8217;t be able to use the algorithm wholesale as it&#8217;s not directly compatible with the representation I&#8217;m using. Happily, my representation does make it very simple to use the core idea, though.</p>

<p>If you <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/19/youre-speaking-my-landscape-baby/">remember</a>, my representation stores the individual points in a sparse array, indexed using fractional coordinates. This makes it very flexible, and allows me to use an irregular level of detail (more on that later). Unlike the representation used in the paper, this means a can&#8217;t make optimisations based on the assumption that my data is stored in a regular grid. Thankfully, the first stage of the simplification algorithm doesn&#8217;t care about this and examines points individually. Also thankfully, the simplification algorithm uses the same parent/child based tessellation strategy that I do.</p>

<p>The first step is decide which points are &#8220;active&#8221;. This is essentially based on two variables:</p>

<ul>
<li>The amount of &#8220;object space error&#8221; a point has (i.e. how much it differs from its parents);</li>
<li>The distance between the point and the &#8220;camera&#8221;.</li>
</ul>


<p>A local constant is also present for each point:</p>

<ul>
<li>The point&#8217;s bounding radius, or the distance to its furthest child (if it has children);</li>
</ul>


<p>I&#8217;m not sure if I actually need this last in my current implementation (my gut says no, I&#8217;ll explain why later), but I&#8217;m leaving it in for the time being. Finally, two global constants are used for tuning, and we end up with this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/simplificationequation21.png"></p>

<p>Where:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>i</em> = the point in question</li>
<li><em>λ</em> = a constant</li>
<li><em>ε<sub>i</sub></em> = the object space error of <em>i</em></li>
<li><em>d<sub>i</sub></em> = the distance between <em>i</em> and the camera</li>
<li><em>r<sub>i</sub></em> = the bounding radius of <em>i</em></li>
<li><em>τ</em> = another constant</li>
</ul>


<p>This is not entirely optimal for processing, but a little bit of maths wizardry transforms this like so:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/simplificationequation31.png"></p>

<p>This looks more complicated, and it&#8217;s less intuitive to see what it actually does, but from the point of view of the computer it&#8217;s a lot simpler, as it avoids the square root needed to calculate the distance between the point and the camera. Now we get to the fun part: diagrams! Consider the following small landscape, coloured as to the granularity of each of the points (aka the distance to the node&#8217;s parents, see <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/22/fractal-errata/">this post</a>):</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/allpoints.jpg"></p>

<p>Next, we&#8217;ll pick some arbitrary values for the constants mentioned above (ones which work well for explanatory purposes), and place the viewpoint in the top left hand corner, and we end up with this the following active points (inactive points are hidden):</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/activepoints.jpg"></p>

<p>Now, we take the active points with the smallest granularity, and we have them draw their polygons, <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/22/now-in-eye-popping-3d/">exactly as before</a>, which looks like this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/smallestpolygons.jpg"></p>

<p>When we come to draw the polygons of the next highest granularity you&#8217;ll see that we have a problem, though. The previous set of polygons have encroached on their territory. To avoid this, each node informs its parents that it is active and then the parent doesn&#8217;t draw any polygons in the direction of its active children. If we add in the polygons drawn by the each of the other levels of granularity, we now end up with this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/filledpolygons.jpg"></p>

<p>Oh no! There&#8217;s a hole in my landscape! I was actually expecting that my simplistic approach would lead to more or less this result, but it was still a little annoying when it happened. If I was a proper analytical type I would next have sat down and worked over the geometry at play here, then attempted to find a formulation which would prevent this from happening. Instead, though, I stared at it for a good long while, displaying it in various different ways, and waited for something to jump out at me.</p>

<p>Eventually it did, and thankfully it was a very simple rule. Each parent stores a list of the directions in which it has active children in order to prevent overdrawing (as mentioned above). The new rule is that a node is also considered active if this list is non-empty. With this addition, our tessellated landscape now look alike this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/backfilledpolygons.jpg"></p>

<p>Presto! A nice simple rule which fills in all of the gaps in the landscape without any over or under simplification, or any overdrawing. I suspect this rule also negates the need for the bounding radius mentioned above, though I have not as yet tested that thought. To recap, we have three simple rules:</p>

<ol>
<li>A node is active if the object space error/distance equation says it is;</li>
<li>A node is active if any of its children are active;</li>
<li>Polygons are tessellated for each active point, but not in the direction of any active children.</li>
</ol>


<p>But what does this look like in actual eye poppingly 3D landscapes? Well, here&#8217;s an example, using the height based colouring I&#8217;ve used before:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/simplifiedlandscape.jpg"></p>

<p>I&#8217;m quite pleased with this, though what I&#8217;m doing here is still quite inefficient and in need of some serious tuning. There are a couple of further simplification tricks I can try (including the next step from the (paper) paper). More to come later. Honest.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mercury Rising]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/09/20/mercury-rising/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-20T10:00:44+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/09/20/mercury-rising</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Monday the 5th of September was Freddie Mercury day. The day he would have turned 65, had he lived. This makes me feel a little old, but that&#8217;s not the point. The day&#8217;s <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KX2BQM0D01M">Google doodle</a> (pointed out to me with furious glee by one of my coworkers) led me to YouTube and numerous videos of Queen performing live. As I often do, I&#8217;d forgotten just how good they were. I spent much of the day fighting the urge to pump my fist and throw shapes at my desk*. Since I had so much fun with this, I&#8217;m going to pepper this post with some of the videos I found the most fun. Anything under the videos and written in italics is a comment on the video itself, and not strictly related to the rest of this post.</p>

<!-- more -->




<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/LncAQR47eZo" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><em>If you have to start somewhere, you might as well start here. File under: moments which made history.</em></p>

<p>As I was walking to the cinema yesterday to see <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com/post/10360864080/tinker-tailor-soldier-spy">Tinker Tailer Soldier Spy</a>, I found myself thinking back to the Queen videos, but also to the <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/07/film-related-blog-post/">post</a> I previously wrote about how much I hated the last two Transformers films, and how much I adored Fast 5. I started wondering if a person&#8217;s taste in music might be reflected in their taste in film. I have fairly eclectic fast in music. I like a bit of <em>Dido</em>, a bit of <em>Bjork</em>. I love me some <em>Avenged Sevenfold</em> and some <em>In Flames</em>. I&#8217;m as likely to throw on a bit of <em>Massive Attack</em> as I am a bit of <em>Linkin Park</em>. Today I might be listening to <em>At The Drive-In</em>, where as on my walk yesterday my choice of backdrop was <em>Spiritual Beggars</em>. Like my mother before me, I&#8217;m also a bit of a Queen fan.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/oozJH6jSr2U" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><em>Obviously I have to include this one. Queen at their operatic best.</em></p>

<p>When challenged to name my favourite films, I&#8217;ve been picking the same five for quite some time (in no particular order):</p>

<ul>
<li>Fight Club;</li>
<li>American Beauty;</li>
<li>Donnie Darko;</li>
<li>Amelie;</li>
<li>The Matrix.</li>
</ul>


<p>I might also offer up three others I really love:</p>

<ul>
<li>Out of Sight;</li>
<li>Pitch Black;</li>
<li>X-Men**.</li>
</ul>


<p>Perhaps I might also add the first <em>Pirates of the Caribbean</em> film (or maybe <em>Zoolander</em>) to that list. Be that as it may, I&#8217;d say the list is reasonably eclectic. Not entirely evident in this list is my love of a really good action movie. <em>Bad Boys</em>. <em>The Transporter. Rambo (2008). Fast 5. Demolition Man. Army of Darkness. Welcome to the Jungle. The Long Kiss Goodnight. Die Hard.</em> I&#8217;m not going to try and match items from my musical taste to each of the films I&#8217;ve named here, because I don&#8217;t think the analogy is that exact, but I think Queen serves as an excellent peer to these action films.</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/kXOOwNS2qk0" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><em>I love this intro. That is how you work a crowd.</em></p>

<p>Freddie Mercury did not so much walk around the stage as stay perfectly still at the centre of everyone&#8217;s vision while the stage moved around him. He worked the crowd like a master while knocking every single note right out of the stadium. It wasn&#8217;t just about him, though. The band behind him was as tight as a gnat&#8217;s arse. Everything clicked together like the internals of a cuckoo clock. Queen songs were not generally high art, but they flowed brilliantly and they just <em>took hold</em> of you.</p>

<p>This is how a good action film should be. I want the characters to chew the scenery and have it feel right. I want the characters to be fleshed out enough to feel worthwhile. They don&#8217;t have to be Lester Burnham or Jack Foley, but I do need to give a shit about what happens to them. The plot should feel, if not possible, then plausible. If something doesn&#8217;t quite make sense then it should be okay because I&#8217;m having too much fun to care. I want to laugh joyously at the outrageousness of it. I want to feel like pumping my fist along with the protagonists&#8217; success and then leave the cinema with a huge smile on my face. I&#8217;ll listen to some Emilíana Torrini soon, there&#8217;ll be time enough for that later. Right now, <em>we are the champions</em>, baby!</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/pCA6b36pCro" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p><em>A beautiful, melancholic and very appropriate song. Seems like a good place to stop.</em></p>

<p>* For the record: conversation with my coworkers has revealed to me that had I done so, I could simply have told them I was listening to a bit of Queen and this otherwise odd behaviour would have become at least marginally understandable.</p>

<p>** Yes, the first one. It has a wonderful lightness of touch and flow, which, though it doesn&#8217;t excuse the film&#8217;s complete lack of a third act, does make it very dear to me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revisiting the Language Issue]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/09/14/revisiting-the-language-issue/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-14T10:00:14+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/09/14/revisiting-the-language-issue</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some time ago, I wrote a <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/09/youre-speaking-my-language-baby-part-1-introduction/">series</a> <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/10/youre-speaking-my-language-baby-part-2-java/">of</a> <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/11/youre-speaking-my-language-baby-part-3-c/">posts</a> <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/12/youre-speaking-my-language-baby-part-4-objective-c/">about</a> <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/13/youre-speaking-my-language-baby-part-5-conclusion/">language</a> choice for my Clockwork Aphid project. In the end I decided to start the project in Java, this being the language I&#8217;m most comfortable with. Once the project reaches a stable state, with some minimum amount of functionality, the plan is to port it to C++ for comparison purposes, this being the language which is likely to provide the best performance.</p>

<p>I still plan on doing this, but I&#8217;ve also decided to add a couple of extra candidate languages to the melting pot and get an even broader comparison. The first of these languages is Go, a relatively new language developed at Google. This is not coincidence. I&#8217;ve been doing some reading about it lately and finding a lot of things I really like. It has the potential to provide the benefits of both Java <em>and</em> C++, whilst avoiding many of the pitfalls. This is definitely a good thing. It will also give me chance to dogfood (there&#8217;s <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/26/dogfood-nom-nom-nom/">that word</a> again!) some more Google technology.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>One of Go&#8217;s features which I really like is implicit interfaces. Allow me to explain. In most regular statically typed object orientated languages, such as Java (which I&#8217;ll use for this example), you can abstract functionality using something like an interface. For example, let&#8217;s say I have a class which looks like this:</p>

<figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'><span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">Counter</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kt">int</span> <span class="n">value</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kt">int</span> <span class="nf">get</span><span class="o">()</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">value</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Here we have defined an class which declares a single method which returns an integer value. I might then make use of this an instance of this class elsewhere:</p>

<figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'><span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">Printer</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kt">void</span> <span class="nf">update</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">Counter</span> <span class="n">counter</span><span class="o">)</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">System</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">out</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">println</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">counter</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">get</span><span class="o">());</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>All is good with the world, unless I decide I want to change the behaviour of the code. Perhaps I want the value to increment after each call, for example. I could extend the Counter class and change its behaviour that way:</p>

<figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'><span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">IncrementingCounter</span> <span class="kd">extends</span> <span class="n">Counter</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kt">int</span> <span class="nf">get</span><span class="o">()</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">value</span><span class="o">++;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>I can now pass an instance of this new class into the update method of the Handler. Done. Right? Well&#8230; no. This is a bit of a clumsy way to go about this. It doesn&#8217;t scale and it&#8217;s not always possible. A better way to handle this is to use an interface:</p>

<figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'><span class="kd">interface</span> <span class="nc">CounterInterface</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kt">int</span> <span class="nf">get</span><span class="o">();</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This specifies the interface of the methods, but not their implementation. We can then change the Printer class to use this interface, rather than the concrete class:</p>

<figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'><span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">Printer</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kt">void</span> <span class="nf">update</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">CounterInterface</span> <span class="n">counter</span><span class="o">)</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">System</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">out</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">println</span><span class="o">(</span><span class="n">counter</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="na">get</span><span class="o">());</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Now any class which implements this interface can be passed to the Printer. So, going to back to our original example:</p>

<figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='java'><span class='line'><span class="kd">class</span> <span class="nc">Counter</span> <span class="kd">implements</span> <span class="n">CounterInterface</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kt">int</span> <span class="n">value</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="kt">int</span> <span class="nf">get</span><span class="o">()</span> <span class="o">{</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">value</span><span class="o">;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="o">}</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="o">}</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>We can now make any number of alternative implementations (incrementing, decrementing, random, fibronatchi…) and as long as they implement the interface they can be passed to the printer. This is fine if you&#8217;re in control of the implementation, and even more fine if you&#8217;re in control of the interface as well. There are times, however, when you&#8217;re in change of neither. Things can get a little messy and you may have to find a way of pushing a round peg through a square hole.</p>

<p>In dynamically typed languages, such as Python and Ruby, things work a little differently. These languages are often referred to as being &#8220;duck&#8221; typed, as they make the assumption that if something &#8220;looks like a duck and quacks like a duck, treat it as though it&#8217;s a duck.&#8221; In this case we wouldn&#8217;t bother with any of the interfaces and our Printer class would look more like this:</p>

<figure class='code'> <div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='python'><span class='line'><span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">Printer</span><span class="p">:</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">update</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">counter</span><span class="p">):</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="k">print</span> <span class="n">counter</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">get</span><span class="p">()</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>So long as the counter object has a method called get() we don&#8217;t have a problem. Everything will be fine. This is much simpler, and is one of the things which makes Python very quick to program in, but it does have problems. The main problem (for me, at least) is specification. Without examining the source code, I can&#8217;t see what sort of object I have to pass into the update method. If the method has been manually commented then there&#8217;s no problem, but this is an incredible tedious thing to have to do. In the Java code I can see the type right there in the auto-generated documentation, and even if the writer has written no comments at all (what a bastard!) I can still get a good idea of what I need to pass into the method.</p>

<p>Go takes a different approach. It&#8217;s statically typed, and it has interfaces, but a class doesn&#8217;t need to state that it implements an interface. This is implicit and automatic. If a class has the methods defined in an interface, then it is automatically considered to implement it. You get the flexibility of Python with the specification and predicability of Java. This is just one of the things in Go which I think is a really good idea.</p>

<p>On the other hand, I think functional programming is a really stupid idea. I find the languages to be completely horrendous. I feel they must be created by the sort of people who think Linux is user friendly. I consider them curiosities whose only merit is academic. It appears to me that their major use case is to make programming appear more obscure than it actually is and to abstract way the programmer&#8217;s knowledge of what the computer is actually doing.</p>

<p>You may be surprised to learn, then, that the third language I&#8217;m going to be trying to port Clockwork Aphid into is Scala, a functional programming language. The reason for this is simple: while I personally believe that functional programming (FP) is rubbish, many people disagree. Not a majority, but certainly a very vocal minority. Within Google this minority is very vocal in indeed. The word &#8220;fundamentalists&#8221; might be appropriate to describe them. When someone believes something that hard it makes me very curious. This is turn tends to lead me towards testing my own beliefs. Sometimes I discover something new and exciting which I was missing out on previously*, and sometimes my initial suspicions are confirmed**. We&#8217;ll see which way it goes with Scala.</p>

<p>* Such as the Harry Potter books, which I had stubbornly refused to read until just before the first film was released.<br/>
** Such as when I noticed that the Twilight books had taken up the first four places on the Waterstone&#8217;s chart and decided I aught to find out what all the fuss was about.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Ol' Homestead]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/09/11/the-ol-homestead/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-11T16:59:41+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/09/11/the-ol-homestead</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You may or may not be aware that, though I now lived in London and previously lived in Edinburgh, I&#8217;m originally from South Yorkshire. Since I visited my parents this weekend for my father&#8217;s 60th birthday*, I though I&#8217;d take a moment to talk about a couple of Yorkshire related titbits which have crossed my mind recently.</p>

<p>The first is the fact that no matter how far you go from your your roots, they have a way of inserting themselves into your life in unexpected places. The other day (or &#8220;t&#8217;other day&#8221; if we&#8217;re going to be properly Yorkshire about this) I was walking through Waterloo train station on my way to meet some friends for dinner. There&#8217;s a theatre attached to the station which is showing &#8220;The Railway Children&#8221;, and thus it has been named &#8220;The Yorkshire Theatre&#8221;. Next to the theatre is a booth organised by &#8220;Visit Yorkshire&#8221;, which is essentially the Yorkshire Tourist Board. As is often the case with these booths, it has a couple of large posters showing sights intended to entice you to… well… visit Yorkshire.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So far, so normal, but the beautiful yet ruined abbey in one of the pictures looked very familiar indeed. In fact, it looked a lot like the very beautiful yet ruined abbey just outside my otherwise almost entirely unremarkable home town. A little bit of Googling later and I confirmed that, sure enough, there was a great big picture of Roche Abbey sitting in Waterloo train station. See for yourself:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.ntopsearch.com/media/images/f/f/ffba50d6-a214-4204-8fe8-9562dae62447/ffba50d6-a214-4204-8fe8-9562dae62447.jpg"></p>

<p>Maltby was once a proud coal mining town, but those days are very much gone. Now it&#8217;s mostly a hub for people who commute into the surrounding larger towns and cities. There&#8217;s not a lot here. To my knowledge, not even a Starbucks or Subway. Thus, it was a pleasant surprise to see one of the local sights held up next to the Jorvic Viking Centre as one of the main attractions in Yorkshire. Go us.</p>

<p>Something which is potentially less of an attraction in Yorkshire is the people. They&#8217;re not unfriendly, but but they can seem a little cold, and don&#8217;t aways warm to a person as quickly as they might. Know this, though: if I Yorkshireman calls you friend, he <em>means</em> it**. There is also strong streak on competitiveness in the Yorkshire folk, and a fierce pride in working class roots, though it feels as though this is being eroded in Yorkshire as it is everywhere in the UK. Some years ago, Monty Python sent this up almost perfectly in what I consider to be the finest comedy sketch every written:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Xe1a1wHxTyo" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>(There&#8217;s also an alternative version <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-eDaSvRO9xA">here</a>)</p>

<p>I say best written because the performance does not, in my opinion, quite live up to the writing. The delivery is fantastic, but most of the accents aren&#8217;t quite right. But still, <em>beggars can&#8217;t me choosers</em>. Also: <em>waste not, want not</em>, and <em>close your mouth, there&#8217;s a bus coming</em>.</p>

<p>* This makes me feel old, but I suspect it makes him feel older&#8230;<br/>
** The same, of course, goes for the ladies of Yorkshire, but &#8220;Yorkshireman&#8221; scans so much better than any unisex pronoun I could think of.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dogfood, Nom Nom Nom]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/26/dogfood-nom-nom-nom/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-26T09:00:04+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/26/dogfood-nom-nom-nom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dog food, the common noun, is reasonably self explanatory (pro tip: it&#8217;s food for dogs). Dogfood the verb or dogfooding the verbal noun, though, might require a little bit of explanation.</p>

<p>At the root of it is this: if you make dog food, you should feed it to your own dogs. There are essentially two reasons for this:</p>

<ol>
<li>If you don&#8217;t personally test it, how will know if it&#8217;s any good?</li>
<li>If your dogs don&#8217;t eat it, why the hell should anyone else&#8217;s?</li>
</ol>


<p>The same principle applies to software.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Even more so in fact, as it&#8217;s something you&#8217;re more able to test directly. As a simple example: in Google, we use Google docs for most documentation purposes (design docs, presentations, etc.). I&#8217;m willing to bet that folks at Apple use iWork for much the same purpose. I&#8217;m absolutely certain that Microsoft employes use Office, excepting those times when it&#8217;s necessary to write a document in the blood of a green eyed virgin upon the pressed skin of an albino goat.</p>

<p>This process is called dogfooding. You use the software internally before it&#8217;s released to users, ensuring that it gets a lot more test usage. As an added bonus, developers who actually use the software they create are more likely to create software that&#8217;s actually worth using. That&#8217;s not always the case, of course, since most developers don&#8217;t really fall into the &#8220;average users&#8221; category. Case in point: upgrading my computer to Lion broke my installation of Steam. I fixed it with a quick command line incantation, then performed a couple more in order to make <a href="http://www.moddb.com/mods/the-stanley-parable">The Stanley Parable</a> functional under OSX. Most computer users would not be comfortable doing something like this, nor should they have to.</p>

<p>As well as using your company&#8217;s products at work, it&#8217;s generally a good idea to use them at home. It&#8217;s always good to have a feel for what your company actually does and get more experience with it. I&#8217;ve used Google search more or less exclusively for at least ten years. That&#8217;s not really a hard choice. It gives the best results. Likewise, I started using Google Chrome is my main web browser pretty much as soon as it was available for the platforms I used (in my last job that was actually Windows, OSX and Linux). I use iPhone in preference to Android, however, though I do have an upgrade due me towards the end of the year and it&#8217;s not completely inconceivable that I might switch. For the time being at least, I&#8217;m definitely sticking with Wordpress, so I won&#8217;t get to play with Blogger, Google Analytics or AdSense, either.</p>

<p>As well as dogfooding Google products at work, we also dogfood technologies and platforms. This sounds fairly obvious, but it&#8217;s not always the case with companies who create platform technology. Microsoft, for instance, used to be famous for not using the technologies they provided to developers internally, though they are getting better now. Some of Google&#8217;s technologies are open source, and thus available for everyone to use. <a href="http://code.google.com/p/google-guice/">Guice</a> and <a href="http://code.google.com/p/protobuf/">Protocol Buffers</a> are pretty good examples of this. Guice is amazing, by the way. This being the case, there&#8217;s nothing to stop me using them on personal projects, should that be appropriate. Personal projects such as Clockwork Aphid, for example.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll talk about which particular Google technologies I think might be useful in later blog posts, but since I brought it up, I suppose I should probably say something about Clockwork Aphid. I&#8217;ve blown the dust off the code, tweaked a couple of things and got a feature I&#8217;d left half finished back on track. I tried switching my current implementation from jMonkeyEngine version 2 to version 3, only to find that while it does appear a lot faster and improved in several other ways, the documentation is pretty crappy, and it&#8217;s less… functional.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll talk about that more later, but for now just know that things are once again happening.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who Likes Short Shorts?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/24/who-likes-short-shorts/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-24T11:38:07+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/24/who-likes-short-shorts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I think I love almost everything about this short film. That being the case, I&#8217;ll quit my chin wagging and just get on with showing it:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/4drucg1A6Xk" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Mucho kudos to Dan Trachtenburg, Danielle Rayne, and everyone else envolved. No get back to it. I want more!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book Related Blog Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/23/book-related-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-23T10:00:02+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/23/book-related-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finally broke.</p>

<p>I’ve been saying for some time that if the Kindle, or a similarly capable eReader, went under the £100 mark I would splash out and buy one. Until quite recently I had been quite tempted, but this condition was never satisfied. Had I seen one for sale in a bricks and mortar store while I was over in the US of A, I think I probably would have just snapped it up, dollar to stirling exchange rates and relative prices being what they are. But I didn’t, so I didn’t.</p>

<p>Then, suddenly, out of the blue, I just happened to be on the Amazon Kindle page by shear chance, in no way fighting the urge to just say “sod it” and bloody well buy one, when I noticed the word “refurbished” in the pricing options. More interesting to me were the numerals to the right of the word. Eighty of your British pounds.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Snap.</p>

<p>To cut a fairly short story down to the bare minimum: I have a Kindle now. The fact that it’s refurbished doesn’t bother me in the slightest. In actual fact this would tend to mean that it has passed a more rigorous set of tests, and still has the full guarantee. Also, it was cheaper. Did I mention that?</p>

<p>So what do I think of this bit of kit? It’s very pleasing indeed, and plays very nicely with my tendency to read books which might more accurately be called “tomes”. Right now that’s George R. R. Martins long and impatiently awaited “A Dance With Dragons”, a book which, if you fell asleep whilst holding it above your face, might conceivably knock you into some sort of Inception esque deeper dream. The kindle, however, has about the size and weight of a molskine journal, making it small enough to fit into some pockets, and light enough to be carried comfortably in the hand or slung in a bag.</p>

<p>It has that slightly strange blinky page turn which is common to the current generation of eInk displays, but that doesn’t really bother me at all. At times it reminds me of shifting black and white sand, particularly when changing to and from the screen savers, which I actually find quite pleasing. I’d like it if they play this up in future versions, rather than just making the page turn quicker, but I suspect that would be a bit of a waste of resou… I mean… er… valuable functionality indicative of a mature company sure of its own capabilities and comfortable with its place in the world. It seems only right that such a company should furnish us with an eReader which acts like something straight out of the <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Diamond-Age-Neal-Stephenson/dp/0241953197/ref=ntt_at_ep_dpt_12">Diamond Age</a>, no?</p>

<p>It’s not all sweetness and light, though. I do have two significant complaints. Firstly, when you turn the device off it shifts into a randomly selected screen saver image from a pool which is preloaded on the device. This is not what I want it to do. I want it to show the cover of the book which I’m actually reading. At this point you may have figured out that my complaints are not, in fact, all that significant at all. This one does annoy me a disproportionate amount though. It just seems so obvious.</p>

<p>The second, equally earth shaking, complaint relates to the progress information along the bottom of the screen. This gives the percentage progress through the book together with a progress bar. I’m told the dots on the progress bar represent chapters, but when the book you’re reading is about a bazillion pages long this is less than helpful. Something iBooks does which I really like is tell you how many pages remain of the current chapter. If I’m reading in bed, for instance, then this is  exactly the information I’m looking for. I suspect there is a way of showing more information here, but I haven’t found it yet.</p>

<p>Something else which pushed me towards the purchase of this particular object of desire was the imminent release of new books by three of my favourite authors.</p>

<p>The first is &#8221;<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Reamde-Neal-Stephenson/dp/1848874480/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1314052707&amp;sr=8-1">Reamde</a>&#8221; by Neal Stephenson. I usually love Stephenson, and the synopsis really makes it sound as though he might be firing on all cylinders:</p>

<blockquote><p>Across the globe, millions of computer screens flicker with the artfully coded world of T&#8217;Rain - an addictive internet role-playing game of fantasy and adventure. But backstreet hackers in China have just unleashed a contagious virus called Reamde, and as it rampages through the gaming world spreading from player to player - holding hard drives hostage in the process - the computer of one powerful and dangerous man is infected, causing the carefully mediated violence of the on-line world to spill over into reality. A fast-talking, internet-addicted mafia accountant is brutally silenced by his Russian employers, and Zula - a talented young T&#8217;Rain computer programmer - is abducted and bundled on to a private jet. As she is flown across the skies in the company of the terrified boyfriend she broke up with hours before, and a brilliant Hungarian hacker who may be her only hope, she finds herself sucked into a whirl of Chinese Secret Service agents and gun-toting American Survivalists; the Russian criminal underground and an al-Qaeda cell led by a charismatic Welshman; each a strand of a connected world that devastatingly converges in T&#8217;Rain.</p></blockquote>


<p>Sounds insane, right? This is another monster of a book, but right now there is no Kindle edition listed, disappointingly. Still, I have my fingers crossed. The next is Terry Pratchett&#8217;s latest. I hate to say it, but Pratchett&#8217;s last couple of books haven&#8217;t really been up to his usual standard, in my opinion. &#8221;<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Snuff-Discworld-Sir-Terry-Pratchett/dp/038561926X/ref=pd_sim_b_6">Snuff</a>&#8221; is a Vimes book, though, so I have high hopes:</p>

<blockquote><p>It is a truth universally acknowledged that a policeman taking a holiday would barely have had time to open his suitcase before he finds his first corpse.  </p><p>And Commander Sam Vimes of the Ankh-Morpork City Watch is on holiday in the pleasant and innocent countryside, but not for him a mere body in the wardrobe. There are many, many bodies and an ancient crime more terrible than murder.  </p><p>He is out of his jurisdiction, out of his depth, out of bacon sandwiches, and occasionally snookered and out of his mind, but never out of guile. Where there is a crime there must be a finding, there must be a chase and there must be a punishment.  </p><p>They say that in the end all sins are forgiven.  </p><p>But not quite all&#8230;</p></blockquote>


<p>Finally, we have &#8221;<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Manhattan-Reverse-Peter-F-Hamilton/dp/0230750303/ref=pd_sim_b_1">Manhattan in Reverse</a>&#8221;, a book of short stories by Peter F. Hamilton. No one does overblown space opera quite so well as Hamilton, in my opinion, but his short stories can be a little spotty. I have no complaints about getting a bit more Paula Mayo, though, so count me in.<br/>
The fun thing, though, is that I found the second two books on the suggestions list for the first. Amazon, methinks you have a little too much the measure of me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Kaiser Chiefs Do NOT Get to Say They Called This...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/14/the-kaiser-chiefs-do-not-get-to-say-they-called-this/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-14T23:32:12+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/14/the-kaiser-chiefs-do-not-get-to-say-they-called-this</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well. These are certainly interesting times to be living in London. Interesting times to be living in England full stop, in fact. In particular, I definitely picked an ideal time to move to Clapham.</p>

<p>I have a bad habit of being more or less completely oblivious to what&#8217;s going on in the world, unless it happens in either the tech or movie industries. I subscribe to those blogs and news sites, but I rarely read the paper or turn on the news, so something has to land with quite a thud, more or less in my lap, for me to notice it much of the time. When a waitress walks into the restaurant in which I&#8217;m eating and announces that riots have kicked off just outside the station I arrived via around twenty minutes earlier, though, <em>that</em> is something I notice. Likewise, when I can hear the sirens from my bedroom window and see the helicopters flying overhead, I pay attention.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Politics is something I don&#8217;t really talk about on this blog, and often avoid discussing in real life. Here, my passion far out ways my knowledge, and this combination amounts to quite the metaphorical JCB when it comes to digging oneself metaphorical hole. That said: I feel recent events merit some comment. Others have already done so, and with eloquence which exceeds my own. <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2011/aug/11/london-riots-davidcameron">Russell Brand</a> (yes, that Russell Brand; whom I continue to find myself impressed with as a writer, scarily enough) and <a href="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/peteroborne/100100708/the-moral-decay-of-our-society-is-as-bad-at-the-top-as-the-bottom/">Peter Oborne</a> being two who&#8217;ve stood out to me. Fair warning: I&#8217;ve read these articles and the writers&#8217; opinions have informed my own.</p>

<p>Frankly: something stinks in British society right now, and it has been ripe for quite some time. It&#8217;s only that this summer has finally circulated the odour more fully. The particular element of this bouquet which stands out to me the most is entitlement. We have a whole lot of people in Britain right now who think you receive things because you&#8217;re entitled to them. That you become a musician or a celebrity by appearing on a reality television show. That the world owes you and if you&#8217;re not receiving then it&#8217;s okay to just reach out and take. That where possible you should cheat the system and ring out every last drop that you can. Ask not what you can do for your country, but what your country can do for you.</p>

<p>Now, I&#8217;ve never really known hardship. Not true hardship which my grandparents would recognise it as such. I once had calluses upon my hands, but now they&#8217;re soft and if I want to use the phrase &#8220;I work wi&#8217; me &#8216;ands&#8221; I have to add &#8220;on a keyboard,&#8221; sotto voce. I&#8217;ve been close to personally destitute more than once, but I could always have solved the problem with a phone call and an ingestion of pride. Realistically, I have no <em>real</em> first hand knowledge of just how bad it can get. Those who rioted last week, were not, for the most part, stealing food, though. They were stealing Nike trainers and 42&#8221; televisions.</p>

<p>42 inches. That&#8217;s a big television. It fired off a question in my head: What is the difference between a looter who steals (say) £800 worth of television during a riot, and a <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/newstopics/mps-expenses/5330816/Sir-Gerald-Kaufmans-1800-rug-and-an-8865-claim-for-a-television-MPs-expenses.html">politician</a> who bills the state for an £8000 Bang &amp; Olufsen television?</p>

<p>I think the main difference is that the politician doesn&#8217;t make you worried about your own physical safety. If you were to choose which of these two people you wished to encounter in a dark alley, you would probably choose the second. It&#8217;s one hell of a lot easier to look down upon the former too, isn&#8217;t it? To see their act as that of a barbarian, rather than a scampish little white collar criminal. I put it to you, though, that while there may be many deep differences between the individuals, the differences between the two specific acts in question are mostly superficial. In both cases the individual decided they were entitled to something which they had not earned, and then obtained it through the most expedient means available to them.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m not trying to excuse those who rioted or looted in any way. I don&#8217;t deny that many of them may have had legitimate grounds for protest, but you kind of loose the high ground when you knock over The Car Phone Warehouse and run off with a crate of iPhones. What I&#8217;m saying is this: what we saw this month was a symptom, and what scares me the most is that I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re even close to a diagnoses of the actual disease, let alone any real notion of what the cure might be.</p>

<p>One last point, and I think this is important. I think Peter Oborne got something dead wrong in the article I linked to above. Specifically, in the tittle: &#8220;The moral decay of our society is as bad at the top as the bottom,&#8221; and more specifically in his use of the words &#8220;top&#8221; and &#8220;bottom&#8221;.</p>

<p>&#8220;Bottom&#8221; is a dangerous word to use here. A divisive word, and the divides in our society are almost certainly part of the problem. We really need a lot more &#8220;us&#8221; and a lot less &#8220;them&#8221;.</p>

<p>&#8220;Top&#8221;, though, is just plain the wrong word. Britain is, on paper, a monarchy. Functionally, though, we&#8217;re a parliamentary democracy. This means that our politicians are <em>not</em> above us. They are not a ruling aristocracy, regardless of what the Tories would prefer. They work for us. They are, at most, our equals.</p>

<p>If you have a comment to make, regardless of whether you agree of disagree, I encourage you to leave it below. If it&#8217;s uncivil I am going to either delete it or make fun of you, though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Film Related Blog Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/07/film-related-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-07T11:27:03+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/07/film-related-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“Given that you’ve just told us that the second one is one of the worst films you’ve ever seen,” asked Pete, “why on earth did you feel the need to go and see the third one?”</p>

<p>It was a good question. In all fairness I do not have good explanation as to why I paid actual money to see <em>Transformers: Dark of the Moon</em> in the cinema. I suppose I was relying mostly on hope. I mean, we’re talking about a film which is, at its core, about giant robots fighting. It really should be quite hard to get that wrong. The plot doesn’t need to be much, it just has to work. The first Transformers film just about held together, and I had a reasonable amount of fun with it. There was something extremely soulless about it, though. Something clearly went wrong somewhere, but I thought there was potential.</p>

<p>So I went to see the second film. I thought perhaps it would be better. Maybe it would hold on to the good bits of the first film and shore up everything else. It had Tony Todd as the villain, after all. Surely that meant nothing could go wrong?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It was basically gibberish. Not just gibberish, though: offensive gibberish. I felt as though the film assumed I was an idiot. Some blindingly obvious details were explained in ridiculous detail, whilst the plot had more holes than… well… plot. Half the movie just plain didn’t make any sense. On the one hand it seems to think you’re so stupid you need things explaining to you, on the other it thinks you’re so oblivious that that you’ll ignore massive inconsistencies and holes in the plot. Half the film just felt like dead space. If I go to see a film called “Transformers” that’s what I expect to to see. Giant robots which turn into cars and such. I don’t want five minutes of a pointless character’s even more pointless mother accidentally getting high on hash brownies and the ensuing “hilarity”.</p>

<p>Was there action in the film? Yes. Was it good? Some of it. Did it make up for the rest of the film’s shortcomings? Hell no. To some extent, that’s not even the worse part, though. The worse part is that the actual Transformers aren’t even really in the film that much. The film mostly follows Shia’s character and… two other robots. Skidz and Mudflap are “comic relief”, sort of like how Jar Jar was “comic relief” in <em>The Phantom Menace</em>. They are… stupid, ignorant, illiterate and really, really annoying. That might be tolerable if they at least did something moderately cool. If, out of nowhere, they turned out to be quite bad ass. They don’t. The kindest word I can really use to describe them is “bumbling”. Are they racist? I’m not going to get into that. I felt like I was watching cringeworthy stereotypes closely resembling the scene in Bad Boys II when Will Smith and Martin Lawrence go a bit “ghetto”. Others would say that makes <em>me</em> the racist. I don’t know. I’ll let you make your own <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=91tLruQjd2s">mind up</a>.</p>

<p>So why in the name of all that is good and pure did I go and see the third film? The trailer looked quite good. It also looked as though the Transformers were actually in it. Perhaps there would be some really good action, and perhaps this time around it might also have a script.</p>

<p><em>sigh</em></p>

<p>Not as such. There <em>is</em> some really great action in the film. Spectacular, even. There’s a car chase mid way through which is stunning. Balletic, even. The level of artistry which has gone into its creation is really quite staggering. The rest of the film, though? Gibberish. Again. Half of it literally makes no sense. The plot manages to be both paper thin and self contradictory. It’s also weird. Things I didn’t need to see:</p>

<ul>
<li>Dr. Ken straddling Shia and declaring himself “deep wang”;</li>
<li>Bumble Bee pushing over and ticking an orange John Malkovich;</li>
<li>Shia’s parents. Again. This time his Mum wants to give him a sex manual.</li>
</ul>


<p>“It’s an action film, though!” you might declare.</p>

<p>To which I reply: “So?”</p>

<p>There is no rule which says an action film can’t have a good plot and compelling characters. I love a good action film. I put it to you that Fast 5 was such a film. It was, in my opinion, a near perfect film. Note my use of the indefinite article there, because that’s important. No film is perfect, and there is no one perfect film, even when we’re talking about ideals. But Fast 5 had a plot which fit together quite well, in my opinion. It had actual characters. Broadly drawn character for the most part, to be sure, but with enough nuance to make them work. It was so much fun that when the characters stopped for an inappropriate street race or spent much of the third act flagrantly ignoring the laws of physics, I just plain didn’t care. I was having too much fun. On more than one occasion it confounded my expectations. <del>The Rock</del> Dwayne Johnson pretty much <em>eats</em> every single scene he’s in. I spent most of the film with a huge grin on my face. When I didn’t have have the grin it was usually because I was laughing. There were a couple of places where I had to stop myself from clapping.</p>

<p><em>That</em> is what I’m looking for in an action film, and don’t think that is in any way an unreasonable expectation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sound of One Hand Clapping...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/07/18/the-sound-of-one-hand-clapping/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-18T20:29:21+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/07/18/the-sound-of-one-hand-clapping</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#8230;would make significantly more noise than I have on this blog, as of late.</p>

<p>There are a couple of reasons for this. The main one is that I don&#8217;t actually have the internet in my new flat yet, and won&#8217;t for another 9 days. Bloody Virgin Media. Serves me right for not going with media which has a bit more experience, I suppose. I&#8217;m writing this at work, which is something I really don&#8217;t like to do, but it&#8217;s very much the end of the day and I&#8217;m in late because I started late. I figure: a quick post can&#8217;t hurt.</p>

<p>Another reason is that my life has been incredibly complicated for the last couple of weeks. I have been bounced around all over the place. I also missed a flight, an expensive mistake I may devote a blog entry to at some point, now that my (partially self directed) rage has subsided, since it has some comedy value.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>More importantly: my paternal grandmother died. There&#8217;s really no way to sugar coat that fact. To head off inevitable questions:</p>

<p>Yes, we were close. In point of fact she basically raised me. I probably loved her more than anyone else in the entire world. I was also her only grandchild.</p>

<p>Yes, I am okay. I will be okay. I knew that day was coming. She had been ill in one form or another for basically my entire life and the years were being increasingly unkind.</p>

<p>No, that did not make it any easier. I cried for more or less the entire funeral, and I have no qualms (zero!) about broadcasting that fact over the internet. I was very glad to have my family and some close friends who knew my Nan there with me.</p>

<p>It is not my intention for this post to be macabre, though. For one thing my grandmother would not have wanted that. I mainly wanted to just check-in and indicate that this blog is still around, and more posts will be forthcoming. Especially now that: a) I have my computer back, and b) <a href="http://www.shamusyoung.com/twentysidedtale/?p=11874">Shamus Young</a> and <a href="http://www.sea-of-memes.com/">Michael Goodfellow</a> are making significantly more progress than I on their procedural generation projects. I am jealous of this.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll be back with more to say soon. Future topics of conversation will include: why I hate RyanAir, donuts, and dog food. Yes, dog food.</p>

<p>RIP Cath / Kath Johnson*</p>

<p>* Funny story about my Nan: no one is 100% sure of what her first name actually was.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For Boobs, Mikael?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/09/for-boobs-mikael/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T02:22:45+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/09/for-boobs-mikael</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Warning: this post contains a picture which includes boobs. Be prepared for that. If your manager is looking over your shoulder, don&#8217;t click; or at least have an excuse ready. If you&#8217;re offended by the sight of boobs&#8230; well&#8230; I&#8217;m sorry. But I probably don&#8217;t know how to talk to you in that case, anyway. Lastly: if you&#8217;re American, you&#8217;re not supposed to see this, <a href="http://www.aintitcool.com/node/49952">for some reason</a>.</p>

<p>Please, use your desecration. Oh yes, and think of the children. But not while looking at the boobs. That would be strange.</p>

<p>Anyway.</p>

<p>Ready?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It&#8217;s the new teaser poster for David Fincher&#8217;s adaptation of Stieg Larsson&#8217;s fantastic <em>The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo</em>:</p>

<p><a href="http://dragontattoo.com/"><img class="center" src="http://geektyrant.com/storage/post-images-2011/girlwithadragonTatnsfw.jpeg"></a></p>

<p>Note: I&#8217;ve nabbed this picture from WikiPedia. It&#8217;s small so that it counts as fair use (apparently). If you click it, you&#8217;ll be taken to the films official website, where you can see a bigger version, though you might have to pinky swear that you&#8217;re old enough to see it. The site also has the teaser trailer, but I&#8217;ll get to that.</p>

<p>Update: It seems they&#8217;ve taken it off the official site. You can find it at the Total Film website <a href="http://www.totalfilm.com/news/rooney-mara-goes-topless-in-girl-with-a-dragon-tattoo-poster">here</a>.</p>

<p>I like this poster quite a bit, though I am slightly confused as to whether the tag line is supposed to be:</p>

<blockquote><p>Evil shall with evil be expelled.</p></blockquote>

<p>Which kind of feels as though it needs a comma to me (though I&#8217;m not 100% certain where), or:</p>

<blockquote><p>Evil shall be expelled with evil.</p></blockquote>

<p>Which perhaps scans slightly better, but is definitely not how you would normally reads words written in that arrangement. In some ways I think I prefer the slightly more archaic feel of the first one.</p>

<p>Update 2: The version of the trailer on the official site has been updated. It&#8217;s definitely the first one.</p>

<p>I <a href="http://harveynick.wordpress.com/2009/09/20/just-cant-recommend-highly-enough/">outright love</a> the book this is based on (and was confused as all hell when <a href="http://www.dougalstanton.net/blog/index.php/2010/09/02/three-books-swedish-crime-allegorical-tales-and-first-person-shooters/">Dougal didn&#8217;t</a>). I did really enjoyed the original Swedish adaptation, but I have high hopes for any David Fincher film and this is no exception. I&#8217;m not thinking of it as a remake, more a reinterpretation.</p>

<p>I think Daniel Craig is really good casting for Mikael Blomkvist, and I&#8217;m pretty impressed with the way Rooney Mara is looking as Lisbeth Salander. In the books, at least, the point is made that Lisbeth would be incredibly attractive if she wasn&#8217;t far, far too thin. Mission accomplished. I can&#8217;t wait to hear them speaking, though it is going to be strange without the Swedish accent. Craig is uniformly fantastic, and Mara definitely held her own, and even stood out, in <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com/post/9851518911/the-social-network">The Social Network</a>.</p>

<p>What was also released recently was the teaser trailer, which looks a little bit like this:</p>

<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/QrQ433ChAQM" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>This is definitely a trailer for people who&#8217;ve read the book, I think. I saw it in the cinema with <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com/post/9851924500/x-men-first-class">X-Men First Class</a>, and the guy sat next to me had a fairly strong negative reaction of the &#8220;what the hell was that?&#8221; variety. To me, though, it looks great. Fincher&#8217;s artistry is legendary and I think this film is going to have a lot of impact. It&#8217;s going to be dark, and <em>very</em> difficult to watch in places. This is a story about incredibly complex and compelling characters. This does not mean that they are nice people, and their story is a difficult one. If I had to pick a word to describe what I think this film will be like, it would be: <em>uncompromising</em>.</p>

<p>I look forward to taking my double espresso with a teaspoon of milk this Christmas, even if I do feel as though I need to take a bath afterwards.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full Nerd II: Nerd Harder]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/06/full-nerd-ii-nerd-harder/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-06T02:36:54+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/06/full-nerd-ii-nerd-harder</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It seems that people really enjoyed my post about the <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/03/in-which-i-go-full-nerd-2/">computer history museum</a>. At the time I wrote it, I was worried that it might constitute just a little bit too much nerd, so I held back on my initial impulse to put in more pictures and gush enthusiastically about how awesome it all was.</p>

<p>With hindsight, perhaps I can afford to ignore that particular mental stopcock, at least for a little while. I do not, I regret to tell you, have anymore pictures of <em>the</em> teapot. I do intend to buy myself a Melitta teapot at some point quite soon, however, so that it may sit in my flat and act as a most nerdy in-joke.</p>

<!-- more -->




<blockquote><p>&#8220;Tea, anyone?&#8221;  <br/>&#8220;Yes, please.&#8221;  <br/>Pause.  <br/>&#8220;Why are you grinning like that?&#8221;</p></blockquote>


<p>I do, however, have pictures of many other fun things. Let&#8217;s start with a reference to my current employer:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2561/5798552483_0c9a55f471.jpg"></p>

<p>This is one of the original Google server racks. At one point, if you typed a query into the Google homepage, this is where the magic happened. If you have any familiarity at all with how servers usually look, you might be scratching your heading and thinking that this one does not look entirely right. Let me help you with that:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3596/5799103540_e8c797886d.jpg"></p>

<p>Yes, you can see all of the components. No, that is not normal. Yes, each individual server would normally have its own case. No, under normal circumstances sheets of cardboard would not be used as the insulation between motherboard and shelf. Yes, that is an awful lot of servers to fit into a single rack. Yes again, that would require very good air circulation, but you&#8217;ll have a bloody difficult time finding a case that gives better circulation than no case at all. No, you would not expect a server to bow in the middle like that&#8230;</p>

<p>Two things the early Google was known for: providing the best search results; and being very, very frugal when it came to equipment purchasing.</p>

<p>Let&#8217;s talk about something a bit more fundamental, though. Hard disks, for example. The one in the computer I&#8217;m writing this on has a capacity of around 120 GB (depending on how you measure a giga byte, but that&#8217;s a different story). Wikipedia tells me that is measures around 69.85 mm × 15 mm × 100 mm, so quite small. This is also a hard drive:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2432/5798550925_2b0852594f.jpg"></p>

<p>Assuming I haven&#8217;t gotten mixed up here somewhere, this is the worlds first hard disk, and is made up of 50 24&#8221; disks, holding a grand total of 5 million characters. Now, if  each of those characters is a one byte ASCII character (or similar) that&#8217;s approximately 5 MB, or 0.005 GB. Quite the difference in storage density, no?</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s a (slightly) more recent example of a hard disk, one which I&#8217;m told is actually still in use to some extent:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2057/5798550747_4ba81989e3.jpg"></p>

<p>Now, if my understanding is correct, this next piece looks like a hard drive, but is much closer in function to RAM:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2197/5798550973_6d011d98a4.jpg"></p>

<p>What&#8217;s particularly neat is that it&#8217;s based on an original design by the regrettably late, extremely great, and utterly brilliant Alan Turing.<br/>
The museum has an entire section devoted to the evolution of storage, and it&#8217;s quite fascinating. Another of the forebears of modern RAM is magnetic core memory, which looks like this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5023/5798550969_307c5c0b9b.jpg"></p>

<p>Now that&#8217;s quite cool, but I&#8217;d say that it&#8217;s also quite pleasing to the eye. I think I&#8217;d happily frame that, mount it, and have it hanging from the wall in my flat (somewhere close to the teapot). People walk through castles and talk in hushed tones of all the many things &#8220;these stones&#8221; have seen. All of the stories they might tell, if they could only speak. But this&#8230; unlike your average rock, this is unquestionably <em>memory</em>, and memory which lived through very exciting times in the development of our society. Here&#8217;s something I look at and wonder what stories it might be able to tell, and what stories it has been forced to forget.</p>

<p>There are many things at the Computer History Museum which are very cool and certainly raise a smile (as well as an appreciative thought as to how far things have come). There are also things which just plain stop you in your tracks; the Difference Engine, for example. Well, at the risk of repeating myself, I&#8217;m going to post another picture of it, this time from the other side, so you can see a little bit more of the mechanism:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5154/5799104044_672ed38476.jpg"></p>

<p>Now there&#8217;s a thing I would really and truly <em>love</em> to have in my flat. Ideally in a more coffee table friendly size, of course.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Different Kind of Tourism]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/05/a-different-kind-of-tourism/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-05T07:04:39+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/05/a-different-kind-of-tourism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If a person were to walk from downtown Mountain View (in so far as Mountain View has a town to be down of) to the Computer History Museum, and then kept going, they might find themselves wandering into Shoreline Business Park. This is where you would find the silicon in this part of the valley.</p>

<p>Of course, there isn&#8217;t actually a lot of touristing to do in your average industrial park. We&#8217;re in Silicon Valley here, though, surely there must be something to see? Well&#8230; there are signs for reasonably exciting tech companies, with logos and everything&#8230; for example:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3005/5799103956_bc27e02f68.jpg"></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Here&#8217;s a fun one. 23 and Me is either a very cool company, or an utterly terrifying one, depending on your point of view. The basic idea is that you send them some of your spit (and some money). They use this to do some basic DNA profiling and tell you about your genetic predisposition towards certain diseases, your genetic predisposition to certain drugs, and a limited amount regarding your actual genetic ancestry. This all comes wrapped up in a neat web interface which updates as new discoveries are made. I&#8217;m generally of the the view that this is pretty cool.</p>

<p>Further in we find even more companies, at least one of which you might have even heard of:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3123/5799103942_418f7a2a37.jpg"></p>

<p>LinkedIn is basically a professional version Facebook. Sort of a fancy online business card holder, networking centre, recruitment system and industry conference all rolled into one. As such, it allows you to show your respectable side to your business contacts, whilst still being able to display that photo set proving that you <em>can</em> get your entire fist in your mouth to your friends. It can be quite useful, but more on that in a moment. I had no idea who the other companies on the sign are, and have not, as yet, felt too much of a need to enlighten myself.</p>

<p>There is, of course, another tech company with a fairly large presence in this business park, but I can&#8217;t for the life of me remember their name. Oh, wait, yes. I remember:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2536/5799103924_e8db3349eb.jpg"></p>

<p>When in doubt, follow the street signs. While I&#8217;m sure it is helpful to have signs pointing to <em>stuff</em> (other examples in this estate include &#8220;movies&#8221; and &#8220;amphitheatre&#8221;) hanging above the road, making them indistinguishable from street signs is bloody confusing, in my opinion.</p>

<p>Google is, of course, the whole reason I&#8217;m in this town, and in fact in this country for these two weeks. For the record, I was recruited via LinkedIn, so it definitely does have it&#8217;s uses. One of the reasons for this wander was to get a general idea of the lay of the land surrounding the Googleplex. My overall opinion: it&#8217;s big. Luckily, the Google bikes were very much in evidence:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5302/5798555777_9a73976a1c.jpg"></p>

<p>Often being found looking slightly forlorn in the strangest places. I&#8217;m fairly sure the local teens play a bit of cat and mouse with security guards and joyride around the park on them at weekends. This one was close to one of the volleyball courts:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5276/5799104166_5e5af56a28.jpg"></p>

<p>There actually is a reasonable amount to see, wandering around the campus. Google really does live up to a lot of its hype. One of the more famous landmarks of the campus was actually bloody difficult to find, though. It took a serious amount of detective work, comparing photos from the web to views from Google Maps, but I finally tracked down the &#8220;Android Lawn&#8221;:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2158/5798559713_a16b044a86.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3533/5798559919_da0f44242b.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2757/5798560063_64d6567a61.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2016/5798560409_d1608f766e.jpg"></p>

<p>As it turned out, if I&#8217;d just stood up and looked over my right shoulder from the place I was performing all of this furious Googling, I probably would have just spotted the damn thing. Such is life. Strangely enough, I was feeling a little hungry at this point, so I headed home.</p>

<p>Finally, it is important to note that while all of this touristing around is fun, and Google is a fuzzy and well meaning company, you should never forget that these are serious guys, doing a serious job. One most always strive to live up to the standard set by those who come before you, and always act in a professional and responsible manner when surrounded by such a high caliber of people.</p>

<p>Seriousness. Responsibility. Decorum.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3543/5799108082_ceb1e2603d.jpg"></p>

<p>That is all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Process and the Platform]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/03/the-process-and-the-platform/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-03T05:24:55+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/03/the-process-and-the-platform</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The effort required to actually publish that <a href="http://harveynick.wordpress.com/2011/06/03/in-which-i-go-full-nerd-2/">last post</a> was&#8230; considerable. Several factors contributed to this:</p>

<ul>
<li>I have slow internet access at my hotel;</li>
<li>Currently, my only (full) computer is my work laptop;</li>
<li>This doesn&#8217;t have iPhoto installed (this is mostly for reasons of simplicity, I&#8217;d probably get it if I asked).</li>
</ul>


<p>In the end, I wrote the text of the post in Evernote on my iPad (using an external keyboard), since I&#8217;m supposed to install an absolute minimum of third party software on the laptop. Next, I did a copy paste into BlogPress, a blogging app which lets you insert images inline. In theory the official WordPress app also does this, except that the upload always fails for me. As you may have gathered, I inserted the images here. This also rescales them, so you don&#8217;t need to upload all 12 megapixels. Next, I uploaded it to my actual blog as a draft, and used the web interface to fix any formatting errors and add any extra formatting, since BlogPress doesn&#8217;t allow bold or italic text (that I&#8217;ve found). That done, I hit the publish button, and: presto!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Needless to say, this is not an ideal workflow. I like using Evernote for writing the actual text (on both iPad and Mac) because it has about the right amount of functionality and it backs everything up and synchronises it between all of my devices. I like having that always available record which I can look back over and search as I see fit. I also like being able to drop one device, pick up another and keep working on the same document more or less seamlessly.</p>

<p>Digression: I also like that I can use it as a permanent record of my notes. Before I moved down to London I was part way through scanning my notebooks from my PhD into Evernote. Evernote runs OCR on the images, finds the text (when my handwriting makes this feasible) and make it searchable. Brilliant. It&#8217;s like being able to carry all of my old note books around with me, all of the time.</p>

<p>What Evernote doesn&#8217;t allow you to do is freely mix text and images, however. The WordPress interface does (obviously), but that leaves me with the problem of uploading the images. This is where the low bandwidth and lack of iPhoto were became problems. I suspect the cleanest workflow would be to immediately upload an album to Flickr (or other photo sharing site) and then use the appropriate URL to include the image in the blog post. Searching through the iPhoto library manually sure as hell isn&#8217;t ideal, and that&#8217;s the only real option for doing it image by image in the web interface.</p>

<p>The most pleasant experience I&#8217;ve had for putting together blog posts with both text and pictures was actually iWeb, and by a metric mile. iWeb uses the built in OSX controls and lets you select images according to meta-data and what they look like, rather than their file name, as though you were working with a file system specifically designed for serving you images. The iPad does more or less the same thing, in fact, so that part wasn&#8217;t actually too bad. Using iWeb leaves you with very limited options for your blog, however. It&#8217;s made me think I should look at using a dedicated program, such as <a href="http://www.red-sweater.com/marsedit/">MarsEdit</a>, for writing my posts, or at least for the final stages.</p>

<p>Ideally, I need to find a decent workflow, which doesn&#8217;t break down when I&#8217;m away from home and likely to actually have semi interesting things to blog about, but doesn&#8217;t restrict me when I am at home. Ideally, it should allow me to jump between different machines with a minimum of effort, and not require me  to always add the final touches from the same machine. The workflow should also not break down when no internet connection is available. Text is fairly easy. Images make things more difficult, especially if the images were recorded using my own camera.</p>

<p>Lastly, I&#8217;m giving some consideration to porting this blog over to Blogger (only if I can transfer all of my posts and comments, however). It&#8217;s not a coincidence that I now work for the company responsible for Blogger&#8217;s infrastructure. Becoming more familiar with that platform can only really be a good thing for me here. Blogger also gives me a couple of options which WordPress doesn&#8217;t, though. Thoughts?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[...In Which I Go Full Nerd]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/03/in-which-i-go-full-nerd-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-03T01:43:18+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/03/in-which-i-go-full-nerd-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Jet lag is a funny thing. Right now it actually seems to be working in my favour; it&#8217;s managed to knock a couple of bad habits out of me. Specifically, these happen to be the not entirely unrelated habits of going to bed too late (then making it later by reading for a good long while) and getting up too late. Right now I seem to be fighting to keep my eyes open by around nine, and then being wide awake by seven. Which is more or less the position I found myself in on Sunday. Since day one at Google camp was a couple of days away I thought I&#8217;d check out my immediate surroundings.</p>

<p>This may come as a bit of a surprise to you, but there isn&#8217;t actually a lot to do in Mountain View. One of the things there is to do, however, is the computer history museum, which I&#8217;d been told is exactly as awesome as it sounds. In case my meaning isn&#8217;t clear: really awesome. There is no sarcasm here. Look at my face. Awesome. This is not my sarcastic face. Awesome. Face. Awesome.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I have a rental car, but the brakes scare the shit out of me, and the place didn&#8217;t look too far away, so I decided to walk. Now, I&#8217;d been warned that no one walks in America, but I wasn&#8217;t quite prepared for it to be true. I must have walked 5 miles on Sunday and saw a grand total of perhaps 3 other pedestrians, and found that drivers looked at me as though I was a crazy person. I think perhaps one reason for this might be that the pavements (or sidewalks, if you like) are&#8230; well&#8230; shit. Anytime you have a height difference of more than an inch between two slabs&#8230; that&#8217;s bad.</p>

<p>Slightly thankful that there were no other pedestrians to see me trip, I arrived at the building in question. Externally, it&#8217;s kind of neat. You might mistake it for the headquarters of some hip new tech startup. If it wasn&#8217;t for the big sign saying &#8220;Computer history Museum&#8221; outside, obviously. Inside, though, it reminded me quite of bit of the Science Museum (&#8220;which science museum?&#8221; &#8220;The Science Museum&#8221;). It&#8217;s nowhere near as grandiose, and has a much narrower focus, but the comparison feels apt.</p>

<p><a href="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/e01ff01b-d1b9-454d-afd7-cbc96bdfc9ed6.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/e01ff01b-d1b9-454d-afd7-cbc96bdfc9ed6.jpg"></a></p>

<p>The scope of the exhibits is quite impressive, starting with slide rules and abaci, moving though Babbage (oh, I&#8217;ll come back to Babbage), on to Turing and right up to the present day. Here are a couple of examples of things which made me smile:</p>

<p><a href="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/ab03b781-9c94-46de-851f-711679d9a0e90.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/ab03b781-9c94-46de-851f-711679d9a0e90.jpg"></a></p>

<p>The Altair 8800, quite an important machine in the history of Microsoft, of which the fictionalised version of Steve Jobs in Pirates of Silicon Valley says &#8220;I never had any problem with the Altair&#8230; until I tried to use it.&#8221;</p>

<p><a href="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/b17fcbeb-6b46-46e5-93f7-91c5995b999d1.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/b17fcbeb-6b46-46e5-93f7-91c5995b999d1.jpg"></a></p>

<p>You know what&#8217;s better than that, though? A computer made out of wood. If you bought an <em>Apple I</em> you received a box of parts and some schematics. You hade to supply the case yourself. You know what else is awesome? UNIX is awesome:</p>

<p><a href="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/11d69f5d-3b06-4df6-bc7a-0b85aaf6ca362.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/11d69f5d-3b06-4df6-bc7a-0b85aaf6ca362.jpg"></a></p>

<p>You see? There&#8217;s a badge and everything. What says awesome more than a badge? Oh wait, I know:</p>

<p><a href="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/7a115add-1257-44eb-9fa7-6dc114378d8f3.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/7a115add-1257-44eb-9fa7-6dc114378d8f3.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Oh yeah. That&#8217;s right. I bet you wish you were cool enough to have that licence plate. As a side note: I wonder if anyone does have that licence plate, since I assume this one isn&#8217;t real. Furthermore: what kind of car would you put that on? This is fodder for <em>Pimp My Ride</em> right here. They should get on that (&#8220;Yo, we heard you like UNIX&#8230;&#8221;).</p>

<p>There was a lot more at the museum. Too much, in fact. I arrived about an hour after it opened and literally left as they locked the door behind me. I probably skipped about half of the section on the internet, and only had time for a brief look at the exhibit on the history of computer chess. Did I mention that they have half of Deep Blue? They also have something else very, very cool, and that&#8217;s one of the two Babbage <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Difference_engine">Difference Engines</a> which we only very recently developed the capability to actually build:</p>

<p><a href="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/a677c6d3-c432-4285-9d81-1085791eeed14.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/a677c6d3-c432-4285-9d81-1085791eeed14.jpg"></a></p>

<p>You really can&#8217;t do justice to this thing in a photograph. It&#8217;s beautiful. A marvel of engineering, it actually works exactly as Babbage said it would, and he built it entirely on paper. In 1849. Somebody should build an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analytical_engine">Analytical Engine</a>. That, my friends, would truly be something.</p>

<p>One last thing:</p>

<p><a href="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/c4843570-b8d8-4251-bf11-2e49bc097e955.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://harveynick.files.wordpress.com/2011/06/c4843570-b8d8-4251-bf11-2e49bc097e955.jpg"></a></p>

<p>I think this might be THE teapot.</p>

<p>Update: <a href="http://www.plan28.org/">Someone</a> is building an analytical engine!</p>

<p>Another update: there is a follow up post <a href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/06/full-nerd-ii-nerd-harder/">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Morning.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/02/this-morning/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-02T05:14:19+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/02/this-morning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;re going to have to wait a little while longer for the Computer History Museum, Silicon Valley Wandering and San Francisco based updates I had in mind, since I still haven&#8217;t found a good way of adding the images I wanted to. In the meantime, I thought I&#8217;d tell you about my morning, in a similar (if significantly smaller in scope) fashion to <a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/201x/2010/04/12/Google-Vignettes">Tim Bray&#8217;s semi-famous post</a>.</p>

<p>Now, Google is very transparent internally, but also has fairly strict rules about what you can and can&#8217;t talk to people about, regardless of whether you&#8217;re talking to your friends, your family, random people on the street, or potentially random people on the information super highway (that&#8217;s you). I haven&#8217;t entirely gotten my head around them yet, so I&#8217;m limiting myself to things you could find out by yourself, either via the internet, by wandering around in the general vicinity of a Google office, or being invited in as a lunch guest. This latter option is not too uncommon; it&#8217;s actually something we&#8217;re encouraged to do (up to a point).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Be that as it may, this morning I drove in to the campus, and parked in a nice easy space a reasonable distance from the building. I&#8217;m not entirely used to driving on the <del>right</del> wrong side of the road and I&#8217;m not going to take any chances, so I was looking for a space with no other cars around. Someone had left one of the Google bikes next to where I parked, so I jumped on, rode straight past the the building my class was due to be in (I&#8217;m here for training) and headed over to one I knew had a cafe which served a decent breakfast.</p>

<p>Side note: the Google bikes are distinctive in many fashions, one of which is that they lack brakes. This is good knowledge to have, and personally I would have liked to have found out when I was a little further away from the speed bump. Now you know. You&#8217;re welcome.</p>

<p>I stood the bike up near the door, next to a pack of its siblings, and badged my way into the building. The breakfast did not dispoint, and I actually broke down and grabbed a smallish portion of the french toast /crispy bacon / maple syrup combo which always tests my willpower (but thankfully doesn&#8217;t seem to be an option at the London office). It was, on the whole, a very good breakfast. It does, however, leave me with a bit of a dilema: do I return to this cafe tomorrow, or try a different one?</p>

<p>As I was leaving, a girl walked her bike into the cafe and propped it up while she filled a takeaway container with yummy, yummy breakfast food. Then, as I was gabbing a coffee before my class, a guy wandered past with his St. Bernard. Google is a very different kind of a workplace, that&#8217;s for sure. Did I mention the building my classes were in yesterday has a four lane bowling allay and a dance studio?</p>

<p>After that, I&#8230;  <strong>REDACTED</strong>  &#8230;all of which was very interesting. In all seriousness, though: I&#8217;m getting a lot out of this trip.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A brief update]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/31/a-brief-update/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-31T05:57:45+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/31/a-brief-update</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Most people can definitively trace at least one or two traits directly back to one of their parents. In my case I can definitely lay the blame for two at the feet of my father:</p>

<ol>
<li>I know the rules of cricket inside out;</li>
<li>Walking right across town doesn&#8217;t faze me in the slightest.</li>
</ol>


<p>The first isn&#8217;t really important right now (unless you need to know the specifics of the leg before wicket rule STAT), while the second is the result of a father who likes to walk. A lot. In fact many of my childhood holidays consisted of a series of walks across various British cities, often culled from the pages of an impressively large (and impressively modular) Reader&#8217;s Digest walkers guide&#8230; to British cities.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Thus, for the past two days I eschewed the use of my rental car and went wandering. Yesterday (that&#8217;s Sunday) I wandered around Mountain View itself and today I took a train to San Francisco and did the same thing there. I want to tell you about it. I plan to tell you about it. SOme of it is actually worth telling you about. But I want to throw some of the pictures I took into the mix, and right now I don&#8217;t have a good way of doing that. The Google provided free WiFi which covers the entire of Mountain View is very useful indeed, but it&#8217;s not super fast and thus not ideal for uploading a bunch of pictures.</p>

<p>Tomorrow I&#8217;m heading into the office for day one of my Google training (I&#8217;m told there&#8217;s some awesome Kool-Aid, so I&#8217;m looking forward to trying that) and I think I may have access to a slightly better connection there (just a hunch), so I&#8217;ll see what I can do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fourteen Days in the Valley]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/29/fourteen-days-in-the-valley/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-29T00:52:36+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/29/fourteen-days-in-the-valley</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I can see the mountains, but I suppose that&#8217;s only to be expected. I am in Mountain View, after all.</p>

<p>As of today, I&#8217;m in Silicon Valley for my &#8220;noogler training,&#8221; something which most companies would just refer to as an induction. At Google, though, there&#8217;s a bit more to it than that. There are a lot of tools and technologies to learn, because so much of what we use is built in house, and there is a lot of culture to adapt to, because most companies don&#8217;t function the way Google functions. Hence, all new hires get shipped over to the mothership, partly to centralise all of this learning, and partly (I suspect) because the Googleplex is really, really cool. I&#8217;ve been told I must try all of the cafes and slides.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The flight over was truly awful. It felt like crossing the Atlantic in the jet plane equivalent of a council tower block. My entertainment system was broken, so I had to relay on what I had with me. Fortunately, I had prepared for this eventuality and loaded my iPad up with some films and TV shows, and the iPad has a much nicer screen, anyway. What I wasn&#8217;t prepared for, though, was how shit the cabin crew were going to be. I must have pushed the call button thirty times during the flight and they did not respond once. I always had to flag someone down or walk to the galley. Before you ask: it did occur to me that maybe my call button was malfunctioning, but no: the crew confirmed that it was working. Perhaps, then, they were busy? Some of the time yes, I&#8217;m sure, but I also watched them standing around chatting as I pushed the button. Not cool, British Airways, not cool.</p>

<p>Speaking of happier things, I arrived in San Francisco and proceeded to the hire car stand to be greeted with a huge queue. I don&#8217;t want to oversell how long the queue was, but some of these people had tents. After moment realisation dawned, though: since I work for Google I automatically have Hertz #1 Gold status, so I walked straight past that queue to the garage&#8230; and proceeded to wait in a shorter queue. Still, I call that a win.</p>

<p>As of right now I&#8217;m sitting in my very pleasant hotel room trying to decide what to do for a couple of hours before I can legitimately go to sleep. Aside from getting dinner, of course. That&#8217;s the next problem. I&#8217;m probably a little strung out right now, so if this post reads a little incoherent, let&#8217;s just go ahead and assume that&#8217;s the reason why, m&#8217;kay?</p>

<p>Tomorrow I&#8217;m going to go for a bit of an explore. I&#8217;ll let you know if I find anything exciting. Stay classy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's the Downside?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/26/whats-the-downside/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-26T21:44:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/26/whats-the-downside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m reading a Peter F Hamilton book right now. His work isn&#8217;t perfect, but I like it. He achieves a fairly staggering level of scale, whilst corralling a considerable number of characters who are worth your time* and develop naturally, if exceptionally. His books are, however, frikkin&#8217; gigantic. This one is 725 pages long, and is shorter than a lot of his other work. It&#8217;s not ideal for reading on journeys, and you wouldn&#8217;t want to pack more than one of them for a long trip. It&#8217;s also not like PFH is the only long winded author I read. See also Robyn Hobb, Neal Stephenson and Brandon Sanderson. I don&#8217;t <em>only</em> read huge Sci-Fi/Fantasy epics, but I do <em>often</em> read them.</p>

<p>Additionally, I have stacks and stacks of books, even taking into account that I divested myself of a lot before leaving Edinburgh. When I move into my new flat**, I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;m going to have space for them. If I could stop that collection growing too much, that would be ideal, but I have no plans to stop reading or buying new reading material.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>On the surface, to me at least, the ideal solution to this would be a kindle (or, I suppose, some other eBook reader). All of a sudden, Pandora&#8217;s Star is now the same Size as Cat&#8217;s Cradle. Crytonomicon is the same size as Memoirs of a Geisha. Plus, it doesn&#8217;t matter how far I&#8217;m traveling or how little space I have, i can basically pack as many books as I&#8217;d like. Likewise, the book collections would not (physically) expand in size.</p>

<p>But what about the books I have already? Do I just keep them, rammed onto the shelf space I have? Do I instead charity shop*** them? Do I replace / duplicate some or all of them with the eBook version? There&#8217;s no ideal solution here.</p>

<p>The publisher is never going to give you the eBook just because because you own the paper copy, and likewise I suspect the majority of people of aren&#8217;t going to want to pay full price for an eBook they already own. Plus, books are not quite so easy to format shift as CDs.<br/>
So, here&#8217;s what I propose: you take your book to a shop and pay them a nominal fee (say £1). They then give you the eBook version of your book, in the format of your choice. The book itself gets recycled. The shop and the publisher then split both the cash and the revenue from the recycling. You&#8217;ve format shifted your book, with only a small outlay. The publisher has benefited from this transaction. No new copies of the book have been magicked into existence (also good for the publisher). Lastly, raw material for recycled paper has been obtained. What&#8217;s the downside?</p>

<p>* Well, he  does now, anyway. Much as I loved the Night&#8217;s Dawn trilogy, Joshua was <em>way</em> more interesting than either the sum or the product of the rest of the characters.<br/>
** Which is in Clapham, for those of you who are playing at home. The Richmond flat was gorgeous, but size / price ratio was just too small.<br/>
*** I see no reason not to use that as a verb.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day One]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/23/day-one/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-23T22:29:36+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/23/day-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is going to be short. Suffice to say: almost everything you&#8217;ve heard about working for Google is true. That being the case, there is no slide in my office. I&#8217;m told they have them in Mountain View and Zurich, however, and I&#8217;ll apparently be visiting both this year (Mountain View next week!).</p>

<p>The food / restaurants / kitchens are awesome in a &#8220;we&#8217;ve thought of everything you need&#8221; kind of way. The people are really nice, but also intimidatingly smart. For a tech firm, a lot of them are girls as well, which makes for a more balanced working environment.</p>

<p>On the whole it was a good first day, though mostly consisting of administration. I&#8217;m itching to get into the code!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
