<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Foodie | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/foodie/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-19T21:28:10+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perilously Close to Perfection]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/04/19/perilously-close-to-perfection/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-19T17:09:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/04/19/perilously-close-to-perfection</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A friend told me about a restaurant he'd visited on a trip to New York. There was essentially no menu. You walked in, you are seated, and you are asked a single question:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>"How would you like your steak cooked?"</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Then they bring you an utterly fantastic steak with fries and bernaise sauce. They do this <em>one</em> thing, they do it incredibly well, and they do it cheaply because they can take advantage of economies of scale.</p>

<p>I love this mindset of setting out to do something as utterly right as humanly possible. The example I had previously was a cafe in Edinburgh called Loudon's. This is obviously the result of someone setting out to create as perfect a cafe as possible. It's incredibly well laid out. Lots of tables, but not even a little bit cramped. So much so, in fact, that the presence of parents with small children doesn't ruin the atmosphere. They just get lost in the space. This is not enough by itself, obviously. The coffee is also very good and the food is absolutely first rate. Don't even get me started on either the quantity or the quality of the cakes.</p>

<p>So where am I going with this? Well, this last week during a short(ish) break in Austria, I found another one.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>Bad weather led us to take a day trip into Salzburg, which we wandered around aimlessly for a few hours. Getting dinner in town pushed us to a late train… but where to get dinner and what to do to entertain ourselves for a few hours. Someone mentioned a brewery one of our PMs (Product Managers) had recommended. A brewery with attached drinking hall which serves food. Apparently they served the best beer he'd ever tasted. Even coming from a PM* this is the sort of claim which needs to be be tested… and what the hell, it was on the way to the station (ish) anyway.</p>

<p>So we take a wander to this brewery… and I'm here to tell you that I'm very glad that we did. We walked in. We were asked (at this point) three questions:</p>

<ol>
<li>How many people?</li>
<li>Smoking or non-smoking?</li>
<li>How many beers would you like?</li>
</ol>


<p>Beautiful. We were shown to a table in a fairly massive room (one of three). Simple chairs simple tables. A friendly buzz, but in no way crowded.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/18/IMG_1171.jpg"></p>

<p>Within minutes the very same guy had reappeared at our table carrying <em>eight litres of beer</em>. How good was this beer? It was pretty awesome. Frankly I'm still craving it. How much was this beer? I'll come back to that.</p>

<p>There was no table service for food, but just outside of the room was, for all intents and purposes, a small food market.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/19/IMG_1169.jpg"></p>

<p>I wondered back and forth for a little while before deciding on half a roast chicken with a small pretzel on the side. Huge grin firmly affixed on face (as Spartacus might say) I proceeded to gleefully wash this meat and starch based feast down with more of that wonderful beer.</p>

<p>Some hours later we stood, fully satiated and mildly inebriated. We waited with beer baited breath to see what the bill would say. How much was this beer?</p>

<p>€6.70 a litre.</p>

<p>You're basically paying that for a <em>pint</em> in London, and it's probably not as good. Not even close. For me, they really knocked this one out of the park.</p>

<p>If you're in Salzburg, by all means see the kirk (it's beautiful), drop by the castle (it's really interesting… though you might want to stay out of the creepy marionette museum) and eat a slice of Sachertorte (it's tasty). But when you're looking for some hearty food and perhaps an adult beverage or three, you really need to drop by the church of beer, meat and starch. You'll be glad you did.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/18/IMG_1166.jpg"><!-- header_img /images/blog/2013/04/18/IMG_1166.jpg --></p>

<p>* You can't trust 'em ;-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Hestontastic!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/24/its-hestontastic/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-24T22:08:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/24/its-hestontastic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Strangely, I don't think my good lady actually thought I'd attempt to make any of the actual recipes when she bought me a copy of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heston_Blumenthal">Heston Blumenthal</a>'s "<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Further-Adventures-Search-Perfection-Blumenthal/dp/0747594058/ref=pd_bxgy_b_img_b">Further Adventures in Search of Perfection</a>" for Christmas last year. Sometimes I worry about how little she appears to know me. A chili con carne recipe which takes three days to prepare is exactly the sort of challenge I'm practically incapable of resisting. A black forest gateau that requires the use of a hoover? I say "bring it on!"</p>

<p>I do intend to have a crack at those ones, but I thought I'd ease my way in with the Bolognese recipe from "<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Search-Perfection-Heston-Blumenthal/dp/0747584095">In Search of Perfection</a>," which takes a mere ten hours to prepare and requires no special tools.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>We invited round two friends whom we have cause to thank and don't see nearly enough of, and I gave it my best shot. Here's the maestro himself, explaining how it's done:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6pR5kVyemdY" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Mj9K6iSmafc" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UMx4HUKaA9k" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>In the interests of honesty, here are the things I did differently:</p>

<ul>
<li>My good lady is allergic to celery, so I took it out;</li>
<li>Every butcher I tried practically laughed in my face when I asked for minced ox tail, so I used good steak mince;</li>
<li>I don't hold with serving a meat sauce with spaghetti, so I used pappardelle (thick ribbons);</li>
<li>I also served it with some particularly good garlic bread of my own devising.</li>
</ul>


<p>I should also point that the video is missing a couple of minor steps. If you want to actually make it, I recommend buying the book. If you have no desire to make it whatsoever, I recommend buying the book. Both books. They are fascinating reads. If you can't read, I recommend buying the book. It also has good pictures. I'm a little confused if that's the case, though.</p>

<p>At this point you're probably wondering if the sauce is good enough to warrant the expenditure of an entire day to make it? In short: yes. Abso-fucking-lutely. It was amazing. Will I make it again? Probably, though certainly not often. I might make it sometime when my good lady isn't in town and I can include the celery without the risk of her death (the sauce is not quite that good). Perhaps I'll even try begging and pleading with one of the local butchers to get some minced ox tail or a better substitute.</p>

<p>What I will definitely do is use some of the individual techniques. The tomato base may well become a sauce for meatballs, and the caramelized onions will almost certainly get used in a gravy or two.</p>

<p>Across the entire of both books are sixteen recipes. One down.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It Kneads the Dough]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/04/it-kneads-the-dough/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-04T19:06:02+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/04/it-kneads-the-dough</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like bread. I like it lot. So I was quite pleased when my parents gave me their bread machine and associated recipe book a couple of years ago. Their reasoning was (believe it or not) that I was the only one actually able to make bread with it. Their own attempts closely resembled articles suitable for construction, rather than ones suitable for mastication.</p>

<p>So I've used it on and off since then. Sometimes the bread was good (the sweet potato bread, for example, is awesome), sometimes it was bad (chick pea bread: no, no, no). Just lately I've been using it with renewed vigour, since I've resolved to avoid mass produced bread. Why (you might ask)? The short answer is that the methods used are damaging to the environment, in some respects the economy, and also to the digestive tract of the person who consumes it (which in my case would be me). The long answer is <a href="http://www.dolectures.co.uk/speakers/andrew-whitley">here</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Out of curiosity I decided to have a crack at the San Francisco sour dough recipe in the book. This takes about a week to make in total, uses no yeast (none that <em>you </em>add, anyway), and only uses the machine for the kneading and some of the mixing.</p>

<p>On the whole I'm not that impressed with it. I don't actually know what sour dough is supposed to taste like (oops), but this one doesn't taste that great and didn't rise very well. That last one could be my fault, since I definitely messed up some of the timing.<br/>
Ahem.</p>

<p>Usually with a bread machine, the timing goes something like this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Put ingredients in the machine and push go.</li>
<li>Wait a couple of hours (about four in the case of my machine, depending on the recipe).</li>
<li>Remove bread from machine.</li>
</ol>


<p>That, you see, is the brilliance of it. It's very simple and requires a distinct lack of effort on your part (aside from a scrupulous accuracy in the measurements). With the sour dough it's more like this:</p>

<ol>
<li>Mix some stuff in a bowl.</li>
<li>Wait three days.</li>
<li>Add some stuff to the bowl.</li>
<li>Wait two days.</li>
<li>Add some more stuff to the bowl.</li>
<li>Wait twelve hours.</li>
<li>Put the contents of the bowl and some other things in the machine and push go on the dough setting.</li>
<li>Wait the time it takes to start mixing plus ten minutes.</li>
<li>Turn off the machine.</li>
<li>Wait eight hours.</li>
<li>Add some more stuff to the machine</li>
<li>Run an complete dough cycle (about two hours).</li>
<li>Take the dough out of the machine and knock it back.</li>
<li>Wait two hours.</li>
<li>Put it in the oven.</li>
<li>Wait twenty-five minutes.</li>
<li>Turn the oven down.</li>
<li>Wait ten minutes.</li>
<li>Remove bread from the oven.</li>
</ol>


<p>Couple this <em>small</em> amount of added complexity with the fact that I discovered I was missing a key ingredient around step 11 (which due to the timing was at 6 am)*, what you end up with is a near complete loss of the simplicity, an inferior product, and a dirty flappy paddle bread tin thing which is even harder to wash than it would have been if you'd actually baked the bread in it.</p>

<p>The point, in case you were starting to doubt that I had one, is that from now on I shall only be making relatively simple breads in the machine (and they can bloody well cook in there, as well). For fancier, more exciting breads I think I may well tread the same path as <a href="http://www.dougalstanton.net/blog">Dougal</a> (who pointed me in the direction of the above video), buy myself a copy of <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Dough-Richard-Bertinet/dp/1856267628/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1231095568&amp;sr=8-1">this</a> and prepare to get my hands dirty.</p>

<p>* Erm... and fell asleep for an hour too long around step 14.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
