<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: trailers | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/tags/trailers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-21T21:10:55+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking Forwards]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/07/18/looking-forwards/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-18T17:02:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/07/18/looking-forwards</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Cineworld unlimited card is a wonderful thing, especially given that I no longer have a student card (I am still a student, technically. Don't ask). It encourages you to take a much more "what the hell," type attitude to heading to the cinema, and I love me some cinema. That being the case, I thought I'd write a (probably) quick post covering the films coming out this year that I'm pretty certain I'll be going to see.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So, in particular order (aside from the one in which they occurred to me):</p>

<p>Inception (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/wb/inception/">trailer</a>) - There are some director's who pretty much guarente I'll go see a film. Christopher Nolan is one of them. Likewise, there are some actor's who pretty much guarente I'll go and see a film. Ellen Page is one of them. Also: this film look awesome.</p>

<p>The Social Network (<a href="http://movies.yahoo.com/premieres/20889647/standardformat">trailer</a>) - David Fincher is another one of the directors who almost guarantees I'll go see a film. Aaron Sorkin is a writer who pretty much guarantees I'll go see a film. I didn't think I was interested in a film about Facebook, but it turns out that I really, really am. Watch the trailer.</p>

<p>Machete (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/fox/machete/">trailer</a>) - I didn't think much of Death Proof, but I loved me some Planet Terror, and this looks like it's coming from the same headspace.</p>

<p>Tron Legacy (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/disney/tronlegacy/">trailer</a>) - I think I might have already mentioned this one.</p>

<p>The Town (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/wb/thetown/">trailer</a>) - Ben Affleck might be a genius. Perhaps you didn't know that. You might assume that it was Matt Daemon who did most of the heavy lifting when it came to writing Good Will Hunting. But did you go see Gone Baby Gone? Because he wrote (well, adapted) and directed that and it was <em>spectacular</em>. I'm hoping he's done it again.</p>

<p>The Expendables (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/lions_gate/theexpendables/">trailer</a>) - A cast made up almost entirely of action legends? Written and directed by the man who brought us Rambo? I'm there. If you didn't watch Rambo (the most recent one), perhaps you should. It is incredibly, unflinchingly violent. But it's a film about violence and you might be surprised by how much it has to say.</p>

<p>Scott Pilgrim vs. The World (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/universal/scottpilgrimvstheworld/">trailer</a>) - I love it. I love the style. I love the sense of humour. I love the ideas. I'll be very surprised I don't giggle with glee all the way through this one.<br/>
R.E.D. (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/summit/red/">trailer</a>) - I'm not even going to try explaining this one. Just watch the trailer.</p>

<p>Knight and Day (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/fox/knightandday/">trailer</a>) - I don't know about you, but I mostly go to the cinema to be entertained. This looks like it will be super entertaining. Side note: I might not like Tom Cruise on a person, but I don't think I've ever disliked him in a film.</p>

<p>The Green Hornet (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/sony_pictures/thegreenhornet/">trailer</a>) - This looks all kinds of silly. These ingredients (superhero + martial arts + star of Knocked Up + director of Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind) should not go together. But I bet the first person to eat a peanut butter and jam sandwich said the same thing.</p>

<p>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hollows (<a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/wb/harrypotterandthedeathlyhallows/">trailer</a>) - I expect to be disappointed by this one. I have been by every other one of these films. But that doesn't mean I didn't enjoy them (except the second one). I'm looking forward to the conclusion of the first set of adaptations of these books.</p>

<p>There are more, but that'll do for now. What do you guys think? Any of these look good? Any look great? Any look awful? Anything you're particularly looking forward to?</p>

<p>As a slight aside, I'm also HarveyNick on Tumblr and Twitter, and I'm thinking of moving the 15 words or less film review to Tumblr instead of here, as it seems to fit better. Can anyone think of a reason I shouldn't (it'll still get cross posted to Facebook).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trailer Trash]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/03/15/trailer-trash/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-15T22:30:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/03/15/trailer-trash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every once in a while, a film trailer comes along that I can’t seem to stop myself watching repeatedly. I like trailers in general, which is definitely part of the problem, but some of them really grab hold of me. Two good examples of this are the final theatrical trailer for the recent <a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/paramount/startrek/">Star Trek reboot</a>, and one of the trailers for <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c9tnZRs4tNE">The Two Towers</a> (the one with the orchestral version of he awesome theme song from Requiem for a Dream, and words cannot express how disappointed I was when that music wasn’t in the actual film).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>You might be noticing a dramatic music related theme here, but visuals and dialogue are important too. It all has to click together. You’ve heard it said, I’m sure, that part (or even half) of the the pleasure of a present is in the unwrapping. Same thing, right here. Which brings me back to the latest object of desire I’m metaphorically tugging at the ribbon of. It’s the shiny new trailer for <a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/disney/tronlegacy/">Tron Legacy</a>, long awaited sequel to the 1982 cyber cult classic. I have something of a weakness for stories which which turn computer programmers* into heroes anyway (I’m sure you couldn’t possibly imagine why), but everything in this trailer works for me. There <em>was</em> an initial warning sign, to wit: one of the principle protagonists would appear to be the son of the original hero.</p>

<p>Shit. Where have I seen that recently?</p>

<p>But wait... Maybe he’s <em>not</em> a complete tool of a character, because I absolutely love the delivery of the one line line he really gets in the trailer. Bruce Boxleitner too, returning from the original, but then I already knew he could handle a bit of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Sheridan_(Babylon_5)">gravitas</a>. After a bit of initial set up, the trailer is basically all about the visuals, and what visuals they are. For a start, one of them is a visual of the gorgeous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olivia_Wilde">Olivia Wilde</a> (13 from House). It all looks very cool and it all makes me very curious indeed. For some reason, I especially love the way the music distorts as the main title is revealed. In case you hadn’t guessed: I’m quiet excited about this one. Let me know what <em>you</em> think.</p>

<p>* Apparently, “software engineer” is the more politically correct term, but screw you, I know what I am. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
