<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: Edinburgh | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/tags/edinburgh/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-24T23:31:09+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[s/@seebyte\.com/@google\.com/g]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/22/sseebyte-comgoogle-comg/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-22T22:58:08+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/22/sseebyte-comgoogle-comg</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes. That's right. I did it. I used a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sed">sed</a> expression as post title.</p>

<p>I've been very quiet as of late, though in my defence I've been very busy for a few months. In the middle of that I had a potentially life changing decision to make, and then I was dealing with the ramifications of the choice I made.</p>

<p>As you may have gathered from the post title (even if it mostly looks like crazy speak to you), the choice was whether I should accept a job at Google or not. Believe it or not, it was a choice, and a fairly hard one. There are various reasons for this. I'm not going to go into all of them, though I will go into some, but let's start with a little bit of background.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It started with the receipt of a LinkedIn message with the subject "Hello from Google." and ended with me standing in a car park being offered a very good job. Regarding what happened in between: the Google interview process is lengthy and pretty hardcore. Reputedly the most hardcore in the entire of the tech industry. But having a <a href="http://harveynick.wordpress.com/2010/11/10/the-boardroom/">gruelling four and a half hour viva</a> a little over a week before your main interview can make it seem like a walk in the park, albeit a mentally tiring one.</p>

<p>So then I was left with a choice. I could stay at my good job at a small but growing company with a lot of potential, at which I knew I had some prospects. I'd still be working in an industry which I know, and which to some extent knows me. I'd stay in a city I love (and have loved since the moment I set eyes upon it ten years ago), surrounded by a wonderful group of friends.</p>

<p>Alternatively I could accept an incredible opportunity to work at one of the most exciting companies in the world, which is famous for treating its employees incredibly well, and has projects which excite me more than I can adequately express in words. But I'd be changing industries and I good portion of my existing knowledge might be useless (or more useless, as the case may be). I'd have to move to London, a city I like but don't know that well, and feel slightly intimidated by. As luck would have it, though, I do have a group of close friends living in London, who are also awesome.</p>

<p>It was a very hard choice, and it came down to a couple of things:</p>

<ul>
<li>A former colleague put it to me that if I turned this offer down I'd hate myself for it every time I had a bad day (or spent a year putting my life on hold for a field trip which was consistently two weeks away from happening);</li>
<li>Another colleague suggested that I would be swallowed up by Google. A tiny cog in a huge machine. Which is potentially true... and a little scary. But... the other analogy people use here is "small fish in a big pond." There's a distinction to be made: fish grow, cogs don't. Unless you put yourself in a bigger pond, you'll never find out if you have the potential to get any bigger.</li>
<li>It would be nice to not work for the oil companies and the military. Not necessarily because either party is evil, but because of the shear amount of red tape involved.</li>
<li>I'd been feeling as though I'd been stuck in a rut for a while, and really wanted to shake things up somehow.</li>
<li>It's frickin' GOOGLE!</li>
</ul>


<p>So. Here I am. In London. Staying in wicked temporary accommodation. Tomorrow is my first day at my shiny new Google job, and right now I should really go to bed!</p>

<p>PS More updates coming soon I swear, though it may be a month before I can get back to my Clockwork Aphid project, for logistical reasons.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Journey Home]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/26/the-journey-home/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-26T11:39:40+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/26/the-journey-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Authors note: This post was actually written on Sunday. As it turns out, writing it on the iPad was no problem at all, but actually posting it (with the picture and links) was a different matter entirely.</em></p>

<p>You know, the train journey from Edinburgh to Doncaster is really quite beautiful, for the most part. A reasonable amount of it happens within sight of the sea and most of the rest passes through open country. The Yorkshire dales is a landscape I find quite pleasing to look out over, unless I'm driving through it, in which case I find to to mostly feel endless. Some of the towns you pass through have more charm than others, of course. Newcastle isn't without its fans, and Berwick-Upon-Tweed is gorgeous, but I can't see anyone wanting to put <em>Doncaster</em> on a postcard any time soon.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Why the sudden reflection? I'm on the way down to visit my parents for a couple of days and for the first time in years I'm not taking a "real" computer with me. The implication here, of course, is that I'm taking something which is not a real computer, or at least something which some don't consider to be one. I picked up an iPad on my recent work trip down under (AU$ was doing quite well against USA$ at the time, which knocked a considerable amount of the price as far as I was concerned) and that's a gadget I have with me. Yes, I'm typing this on an iPad. I actually typed the majority of <a href="http://harveynick.wordpress.com/2010/10/08/wow-oh-wow/">this post</a> on it as well, using the on-screen keyboard, and it wasn't too bad at all. The biggest problem was that it reduced to effective screen area so much. Right now, though, I'm using a bluetooth keyboard for the typing. The iPad itself is resting on the crappy little shelf  attached to the seat in front (angled using one of <a href="http://www.macally.com/EN/Product/ArticleShow.asp?ArticleID=320">these</a> cases, which I highly recommend), while the keyboard is sitting on my knee, actually under the shelf. All in all, this setup is one hell of a lot more comfortable than a laptop would be in these circumstances. So that's definitely a win.</p>

<p>I didn't buy this thing to replace a laptop exactly, though. That would be silly. Nor did I intend to replace a smart phone with it. That makes no sense. What, then, is it actually for? This seems to be the number two reaction to seeing the thing in my experience. Number one being "cool!" and "it looks just like a giant iPhone!" being quite high up the list, as well. No, what I intended to replace with this gizmo is one of these:</p>

<p><a href="http://www.moleskine.com/"><img class="center" src="http://www.learnius.com/lcoblog/wp-content/uploads/2008/02/moleskine-pile.png"><!-- header_img http://www.learnius.com/lcoblog/wp-content/uploads/2008/02/moleskine-pile.png --></a></p>

<p>As a general rule, I need to write thinks down more. I should probably make more notes of ideas and such which occur to me when I'm not in a position to do anything about them, and I find that todo lists are basically a necessity when it comes to keeping myself organised. Paper is pretty good for this, as a general rule. I'm pretty fond of my squared paper moleskin journal and when it comes to just scribbling things down I'd say it's pretty much unsurpassable. But, and there's usually a but, carrying it around at all times isn't exactly practical and it doesn't have an erase (or move) function, which isn't ideal when you suddenly realise that the diagram you've been working on for the last half an hour really needs to be about an inch to the left if you're actually going to fit the whole thing on the page.</p>

<p>If you're using <a href="http://www.evernote.com/">Evernote</a> for your notes, though, then jotting things down with a phone (which I do carry at all times) becomes an option. Throw in a couple of other applications and scribbling, brainstorming and generally playing with ideas does become a legitimate possibility. A possibility contained in something no larger than a Moleskin, which does have an erase, and indeed a shift-a-bit-to-the-left, function. Todo lists are a different matter, though, and I'm going to come back to those later.</p>

<p>As a final note here, it should probably be quite obvious that I'm not going to be doing any clockwork aphid related work in the next couple of days, as hacking is not currently a legitimate possibility on the iPad. Someone really needs to write an app which interfaces with Eclipse (or any other IDE) on your desktop and turns it into a context sensitive programmer's assistant keyboard type thing, though. Expect good things to show up towards the end of the week, however.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
