<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Listen | HarveyNick]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/listen/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-05T01:02:01+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serendipitous Nostalgia]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/13/serendipitous-nostalgia/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-13T23:31:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/13/serendipitous-nostalgia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I was walking home from work and absent-mindedly listening to music, when I noticed that that my supposedly shuffled iPod was displaying a definite preference for one band in particular. A band I haven't really spared a seconds thought in some years. As I walked I hatched a plot a write a blog post regarding the nostalgia this inspired. So I arrived home and thought to have a look on youTube for some reference material to post...</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There is a reason I have a marked preference for the combination of a heavy rock music and female vocals, and her name is Aimee Echo. In the late nineties she fronted a band called Human Waste Project with vocals which managed to be both sugary sweet and ragged at the same time. My youthful self took notice. My youthful self also attended a festival called the "Ozzfest" with his friend Rich and said friend's father, where he found Human Waste Project to be a late addition to the bill. My youthful self promptly had the back of head damn near blown off by one of the best live shows he had (or was ever to) see.</p>

<p>As it turned out, that was to be their second to last show. Aimee Echo left the band, who sounded like this:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/xGLglF2MuEo" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>and formed a new one, called at first Hero and then theSTART, who sounded more like this:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/J-K64wVAn5U" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Though I like this second song, I find that the raw edge is missing from her voice. This is probably due to the more electronic sound of the new band and thus the requisite multi-tracking of a voice I don't feel requires it. The point is I don't like the second band as much, not least because this is the only song of there's I found which has much of a chorus.</p>

<p>So where was I... ah yes, I was searching youTube for content to post. What I found was a lot of presumably live videos. I saw one for "Dog", thought "sweet!" and clicked. The video loaded. Aimee Echo was talking into the mike. "So a long time ago... there was a band in the nineties... called Human Waste Project... and we are them..."</p>

<p>Hang on... this is a new video... and then the opening riff gave me goose bumps...</p>

<p>I'm aware the sound quality is <em>awful</em> on the video, but here it is:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/V-fFg3b76j0" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>A bit of frantic web searching promptly revealed that yes, gloriously, the band were back to together. At least to some extent. They'd played two shows in 2008 (well... more like one and a half, since the first one was actually the encore from a theSTART show) and were rehearsing for a reunion tour.</p>

<p>It's when things like this come together that I'm given to smile inwardly and think that perhaps there is someone "up there" who likes me.</p>

<p>For what it's worth, another lady who had an (arguably stronger) effect on my musical taste is Sandra Nasic. So, for the sake of completeness, here's a couple of videos of her singing with her (now defunct) band, "Guano Apes", and another of her providing guest vocals on an Apocalyptica song.</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ifASH53DNXQ" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XvfYrKo1KGs" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/wCeMJR33fkg" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Apocalyptica, in case you were wondering, are a group of Finnish 'cello players, who once exclusively played Metalica covers, but now play original material. Here's another one, this time with Corey Taylor:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/OCqUR_iActA" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>I think that's enough music for now. Tootles.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flip side]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/30/flip-side/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-30T20:54:06+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/30/flip-side</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two updates in one day shocker!</p>

<p>The last one was a little downcast, though, and I felt a need to pass on something awesome by way of balance. Here it is:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sxNmeMklFk8" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Perhaps you're thinking "Huh? Who's this guy?" or "What's with the cake?". You've been missing out if that's the case. Jonathan Coulton (for that is the man's name) is a computer programmer turned unlikely rock star (You scoff? He has a song in Rock Band. I'm having trouble thinking of a better benchmark), who's become something of a geek standard thanks to the somewhat unlikely nature of his subject matter (one song has Pluto's moon singing its condolences regarding its loss of planet status).</p>

<p>The song itself is the song over the closing credits of the game Portal, which is, quite frankly, an absolute fucking work of art. You probably know that I'm several different flavours of nerd and so JC's* stuff appeals to me on a fairly base level , but I'm not a hardcore gamer. I have above average social skills, leave the house regularly and I prefer making love to playing computer games. There. I said it, and with a completely straight face. But that game is complete genius, through and through. I think Valve do amazing work in everything they do, and the fact they got JC* to write the song for the closing credits of one of their games makes me grin from ear to ear.</p>

<p>Check out some more of his stuff, it might make you smile. If you do and it does, leave a comment telling me about it, because that would make me smile**.</p>

<p>Update: His website is here <a href="http://www.jonathancoulton.com">http://www.jonathancoulton.com</a> And you can buy (and download for free) all his music there.<br/>
That is all.</p>

<p>* No, not <em>that</em> JC<br/>
** At the risk of me smiling so widely that the top of my head falls off.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclecticism]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/05/eclecticism/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-05T15:02:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/08/05/eclecticism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seems the Facebook app does not do what it's supposed to. Never mind, I shall content myself with the (better) Wordpress interface. Maybe I'll look into writing a Facebook app which interfaces with my RSS feed. That would be cool.</p>

<p>I thought I would write a music related post, since I found a couple of things on YouTube which piqued my interest. First an entirely serious one:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/vIhJC2-UNZA" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>When I first heard this on the radio I thought it sounded so fresh they must be a new band. But no, they've been around quite a while, I even knew other songs by them. Unfortunately I don't like many of them, but you can't have everything. Apparently.</p>

<p>Next, something quite different. Helen played me this at a dinner party on Saturday night for the comedy value. I went looking for it on YouTube, mostly out of curiosity regarding the identity of the female singer, and found a live version. Promise me you'll listen to at least some of it, and not just hit stop as soon as the guitars start. It might make you smile.</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/nAR4ieUrxUM" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>I think I genuinely like this. It helps that I actually like ABBA. I think they wrote really good songs. I also love cross genre covers, and this is definitely that. The female singer's voice really works for me as well. I had a look for some of their other stuff, but it's really not good, not good at all. It seems they split and formed two entirely new bands, both of which are a slight improvement, though.</p>

<p>Told you I had eclectic taste. Here are a couple more for your edification:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/OyZqpRxnHWg" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>A soft one to start off with. Dido is so much better live. In my opinion her voice is perfect, but sounds overly processed on her recordings.</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/YgrMfRYCRgw" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Bit of a heavier one, there. This is about as heavy as my taste in music gets. I love the singer's voice, though. If you're confused by this wait for the chorus. If you don't have the pertinence for that, try this one by the same band:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/wAfRW_RMK4M" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>See? The band, if you're interested, are called "In Flames". Look up a song called "Dead End" if you want to know what happens when a Swedish metal (death metal? pop metal? disco metal? death pop disco metal?) band collaborates with a Swedish pop singer song writer...</p>

<p>How about another soft one? Okay, but I'm going to get it from an unexpected place:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Waw61eE9FyY" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Yes, that was Slipknot. Bet you didn't see that coming.</p>

<p>I'll skew a bit heavier again, but not too far.</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/hiHBiRRB1Mw" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>I'm a little disappointed that YouTube couldn't supply "Father's Daughter" from "Like a Bolt of Lightning", but this will do.</p>

<p>I'm tempted to throw in a bit of Massive Attack, a bit of Evanescence, a bit of Killswitch Engage... but this post really could go on for ever, so I'll stop it here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
