<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Globetrotter | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/globetrotter/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-22T00:49:49+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wandering Around London]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/05/17/wandering-around-london/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T21:57:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/05/17/wandering-around-london</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apologies, once again, for the radio silence. Over the past couple of months there have been some complications in my private life, and a remarkable amount of my attention has been taken up with figuring out where exactly I'm going to be living after my current lease runs out (more on that later, perhaps).</p>

<p>Be that as it may, after almost a year, I did find some time to go wandering around the city I now call home. Whilst I took every opportunity to make a brisk constitutional around Edinburgh, I'd never managed to really do this in London. Part of the reason, I think, is while that you can essentially wander across central Edinburgh in an hour or two, this is really not the case in London. Nipping across town via public transport can take <em>hours</em>.</p>

<p>Recently, though, two excellent excuses presented themselves. Firstly, my father came to visit for a few days and professed an interest to go take a good look at <a href="http://www.kew.org/">Kew Gardens</a>, the Japanese themed portion in particular.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First stop was the <a href="http://www.kew.org/visit-kew-gardens/garden-attractions-A-Z/Pagoda.htm">Pagoda</a>:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0402.jpg"></p>

<p>This is a fairly impressive and imposing building, at least from a distance. Close up it's curiously less so. I think it's the red brick construction which does it. I've never visited Japan, but this seems a slightly inappropriate building material to me. My father, who has, concurred.</p>

<p>Next was the <a href="http://www.kew.org/visit-kew-gardens/garden-attractions-A-Z/japanese-gateway.htm">Japanese Gateway</a> which, in conjunction with the weather, gave me an excellent opportunity to try out the HDR mode on my phone's camera. Here it is without the benefit of HDR:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/17/IMG_0408.jpg"></p>

<p>…and here it is with the HDR turned on:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0409.jpg"></p>

<p>I'll be listing that featuring under "worthwhile" from here on out. At this point it's probably worth confirming a slightly frustrating fact which I suspect is now true of many people: the camera on my phone has completely killed any use of my point and shoot camera. It's extremely convenient (being as I <em>always</em> have it with me) and, since my last upgrade, actually very capable. The only thing it lacks is zoom, which is a trade off I'm willing to make. If I plan on going on a serious photo taking excursion at any point in the future I may bite the bullet and pick up a decent digital SLR. The point and shoot just feels like a weird middle gear at this point.</p>

<p>Back to Kew Gardens, though. Tucked off to one side and not especially well advertised is the Bonsai house. It's small, but quite cool, and something my dad specifically wanted to see (Bonsai being a hobby of his).</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0448.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0450.jpg"></p>

<p>Next, we moved away from the specifically Asian attractions and took a look in the <a href="http://www.kew.org/visit-kew-gardens/garden-attractions-A-Z/Palm-House.htm">Palm House</a>. This really is an impressive building, if uncomfortably hot and humid. Be ready to sweat, all ye who enter here. Besides the tropical plants (which I don't seem to have taken any pictures of), the green house itself has an impressive art deco* construction:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0451.jpg"></p>

<p>Shortly after this, we took the train from Richmond back to my flat, and I had the fun of explaining to my father the difference between underground and overground trains this far out of the centre ("you can tell that's an underground train because it says 'underground' on it…").</p>

<p>A week or two later, I professed a desire to go see <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com/post/19950925968/john-carter">John Carter</a> to friend who suggested we see it in Canary Wharf, allowing us to go wandering around the area beforehand. So we did.</p>

<p>Canary Wharf is one of the parts of London containing buildings which can legitimately be called skyscrapers (I think). I believe it's also London's financial district. Surprisingly, I actually find it a very pleasant place to be. The taller buildings make you feel as though you're walking through canyons, and the area is very clean, though not to the point of feeling antiseptic.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0463.jpg"></p>

<p>At the weekend it's extremely quiet without quite feeling like a ghost town and there are a surprising amount of things to find. These include a large underground mall, some very cool riverside buildings:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/17/IMG_0460.jpg"></p>

<p>…and one or two very cool statue / landmark type things:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0456.jpg"><!-- header_img /images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0456.jpg --></p>

<p>Interestingly, the whole area is also private property, so you might have submit to a vehicle search on the way in. Be that as may, I can recommend it as a reasonable place to wander around at the weekend.</p>

<p>Until next time...</p>

<p>* This is art deco, right?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New (ish) Year, New (ish) Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/03/17/new-ish-year-new-ish-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T11:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/03/17/new-ish-year-new-ish-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2011 was an interesting year for me. A lot changed. I turned 30. After 10 years of residency I moved away from Edinburgh, a city I love dearly, and took a job in London. With <a href="/blog/tags/google">Google</a>. As a result, I no longer work with <a href="/blog/tags/autonomous-underwater-vehicles">Autonomous Underwater Vehicles</a> for a living. Instead I build web services. Quite the change, I'm sure you'll agree. In the early months of the year I finally completed the corrections to my <a href="/blog/tags/phd">PhD</a>, and then in the summer: I graduated. It took 6 years (all together) but I am now Dr. Nick Johnson. I also <a href="/blog/2011/07/18/the-sound-of-one-hand-clapping/">lost my grandmother</a>, a fact which still brings me to tears on occasion.</p>

<p>In this light, the fact that I decided, towards the end of the year, to shift my blog away from <a href="http://wordpress.org">Wordpress</a> and over to its own domain barely even casts a shadow. I did, though, and as a result you're now reading these words on a site built using <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>, which is hosted at harveynick.com. As you may have noticed, all of the old posts from my <a href="http://harveynick.wordpress.com">wordpress site</a> have been ported over, minus the short film reviews, which you'll find <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com">here</a>. I'm not going to go into how I accomplished this, except to say: I did it the same way <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/2011/09/12/blogging-with-octopress/">Matt Gemmel did</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='It&#8217;s not finished, but it will serve well enough for me to try and start producing actual content again'>
For the most part, this site is stock Octopress. I've played with the fonts, made the heading and background static and added a little more infrastructure (index pages for tags, embed scripts for YouTube and Vimeo videos and a couple of other bits). It's not finished, but it will serve well enough for me to try and start producing actual content again. I do want to make it a bit more visual, particularly the front page, and somehow integrate other content I produce into it. I also want to make it work a little better on mobile browsers and, lastly, make it a little bit more my own. The colours will change, and I'll try to find a background which doesn't require such a large file and isn't so closely associated with Apple.
</span></p>

<p>What will I be writing about though? Well:</p>

<p>I plan to have <a href="/blog/tags/clockwork-aphid">Clockwork Aphid</a> actually doing something of use this year. I'm going to enhance the current Java version up to a point where it can generate interesting landscapes efficiently and in a parallel fashion. I'm then going to then have a crack at porting it to <a href="http://golang.org">Go</a>, which I think may turn out to be an excellent language for writing computer games.</p>

<p>I like films. Perchance you may have noticed. I may chat a bit more in depth about a couple of this year's releases. Just to pick three with a common theme off the top of my head:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>The Amazing Spider-Man</strong>. I went to a preview event for this in Leicester Square a month or two ago and was very impressed with what I saw. I'm hopeful they made a Spider-Man movie in the same way that Christopher Nolan makes Batman movies. Really really.</li>
<li><strong>The Dark Knight Rises</strong>. Speaking of which. This <em>is</em> exciting. It's the last of the trilogy. It's got a lot to live up to, especially since the last film Nolan made was <em>Inception</em>. I wouldn't bet against it, though.</li>
<li><strong>The Avengers</strong>. Now here's a film with some scope. All these characters in one film? With this cast? Written and directed by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joss_Whedon">Joss Mother Fucking* Whedon</a>? Please, please let this film live up to the frankly stupid amount of potential it has.</li>
</ul>


<p>Quite recently, at the aforementioned age of 30, I started playing Dungeons and Dragons with a selection of my colleagues. Well, we're actually playing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pathfinder_Roleplaying_Game">Pathfinder</a>, but let us not quibble about semantics. I'm having a really great time on several different levels. It's an interesting experience for someone who has played computer games for most of their life, but never dabbled in table top RPGs.</p>

<p>I mentioned before that I now have a shiny new PhD, with the letters before and after my name to prove it. I'm of the opinion that the work which led to this is quite interesting (but then I would be). It's also not completely divorced from my Clockwork Aphid project. I'm of a mind to try talking about this some, also.</p>

<p>See you when we get there.</p>

<p>* I think these are his actual middle names.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Ol' Homestead]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/09/11/the-ol-homestead/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-11T16:59:41+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/09/11/the-ol-homestead</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You may or may not be aware that, though I now lived in London and previously lived in Edinburgh, I'm originally from South Yorkshire. Since I visited my parents this weekend for my father's 60th birthday*, I though I'd take a moment to talk about a couple of Yorkshire related titbits which have crossed my mind recently.</p>

<p>The first is the fact that no matter how far you go from your your roots, they have a way of inserting themselves into your life in unexpected places. The other day (or "t'other day" if we're going to be properly Yorkshire about this) I was walking through Waterloo train station on my way to meet some friends for dinner. There's a theatre attached to the station which is showing "The Railway Children", and thus it has been named "The Yorkshire Theatre". Next to the theatre is a booth organised by "Visit Yorkshire", which is essentially the Yorkshire Tourist Board. As is often the case with these booths, it has a couple of large posters showing sights intended to entice you to… well… visit Yorkshire.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So far, so normal, but the beautiful yet ruined abbey in one of the pictures looked very familiar indeed. In fact, it looked a lot like the very beautiful yet ruined abbey just outside my otherwise almost entirely unremarkable home town. A little bit of Googling later and I confirmed that, sure enough, there was a great big picture of Roche Abbey sitting in Waterloo train station. See for yourself:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.ntopsearch.com/media/images/f/f/ffba50d6-a214-4204-8fe8-9562dae62447/ffba50d6-a214-4204-8fe8-9562dae62447.jpg"><!-- header_img http://www.ntopsearch.com/media/images/f/f/ffba50d6-a214-4204-8fe8-9562dae62447/ffba50d6-a214-4204-8fe8-9562dae62447.jpg --></p>

<p>Maltby was once a proud coal mining town, but those days are very much gone. Now it's mostly a hub for people who commute into the surrounding larger towns and cities. There's not a lot here. To my knowledge, not even a Starbucks or Subway. Thus, it was a pleasant surprise to see one of the local sights held up next to the Jorvic Viking Centre as one of the main attractions in Yorkshire. Go us.</p>

<p>Something which is potentially less of an attraction in Yorkshire is the people. They're not unfriendly, but but they can seem a little cold, and don't aways warm to a person as quickly as they might. Know this, though: if I Yorkshireman calls you friend, he <em>means</em> it**. There is also strong streak on competitiveness in the Yorkshire folk, and a fierce pride in working class roots, though it feels as though this is being eroded in Yorkshire as it is everywhere in the UK. Some years ago, Monty Python sent this up almost perfectly in what I consider to be the finest comedy sketch every written:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Xe1a1wHxTyo" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>(There's also an alternative version <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-eDaSvRO9xA">here</a>)</p>

<p>I say best written because the performance does not, in my opinion, quite live up to the writing. The delivery is fantastic, but most of the accents aren't quite right. But still, <em>beggars can't me choosers</em>. Also: <em>waste not, want not</em>, and <em>close your mouth, there's a bus coming</em>.</p>

<p>* This makes me feel old, but I suspect it makes him feel older...<br/>
** The same, of course, goes for the ladies of Yorkshire, but "Yorkshireman" scans so much better than any unisex pronoun I could think of.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Full Nerd II: Nerd Harder]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/06/full-nerd-ii-nerd-harder/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-06T02:36:54+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/06/full-nerd-ii-nerd-harder</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It seems that people really enjoyed my post about the <a href="/blog/2011/06/03/in-which-i-go-full-nerd-2/">computer history museum</a>. At the time I wrote it, I was worried that it might constitute just a little bit too much nerd, so I held back on my initial impulse to put in more pictures and gush enthusiastically about how awesome it all was.</p>

<p>With hindsight, perhaps I can afford to ignore that particular mental stopcock, at least for a little while. I do not, I regret to tell you, have anymore pictures of <em>the</em> teapot. I do intend to buy myself a Melitta teapot at some point quite soon, however, so that it may sit in my flat and act as a most nerdy in-joke.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><blockquote><p>"Tea, anyone?"<br/><br/>"Yes, please."<br/><br/>Pause.<br/><br/>"Why are you grinning like that?"</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I do, however, have pictures of many other fun things. Let's start with a reference to my current employer:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2561/5798552483_0c9a55f471.jpg"></p>

<p>This is one of the original Google server racks. At one point, if you typed a query into the Google homepage, this is where the magic happened. If you have any familiarity at all with how servers usually look, you might be scratching your heading and thinking that this one does not look entirely right. Let me help you with that:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3596/5799103540_e8c797886d.jpg"></p>

<p>Yes, you can see all of the components. No, that is not normal. Yes, each individual server would normally have its own case. No, under normal circumstances sheets of cardboard would not be used as the insulation between motherboard and shelf. Yes, that is an awful lot of servers to fit into a single rack. Yes again, that would require very good air circulation, but you'll have a bloody difficult time finding a case that gives better circulation than no case at all. No, you would not expect a server to bow in the middle like that...</p>

<p>Two things the early Google was known for: providing the best search results; and being very, very frugal when it came to equipment purchasing.</p>

<p>Let's talk about something a bit more fundamental, though. Hard disks, for example. The one in the computer I'm writing this on has a capacity of around 120 GB (depending on how you measure a giga byte, but that's a different story). Wikipedia tells me that is measures around 69.85 mm × 15 mm × 100 mm, so quite small. This is also a hard drive:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2432/5798550925_2b0852594f.jpg"></p>

<p>Assuming I haven't gotten mixed up here somewhere, this is the worlds first hard disk, and is made up of 50 24" disks, holding a grand total of 5 million characters. Now, if  each of those characters is a one byte ASCII character (or similar) that's approximately 5 MB, or 0.005 GB. Quite the difference in storage density, no?</p>

<p>Here's a (slightly) more recent example of a hard disk, one which I'm told is actually still in use to some extent:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2057/5798550747_4ba81989e3.jpg"></p>

<p>Now, if my understanding is correct, this next piece looks like a hard drive, but is much closer in function to RAM:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2197/5798550973_6d011d98a4.jpg"><!-- header_img http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2197/5798550973_6d011d98a4.jpg --></p>

<p>What's particularly neat is that it's based on an original design by the regrettably late, extremely great, and utterly brilliant Alan Turing.<br/>
The museum has an entire section devoted to the evolution of storage, and it's quite fascinating. Another of the forebears of modern RAM is magnetic core memory, which looks like this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5023/5798550969_307c5c0b9b.jpg"></p>

<p>Now that's quite cool, but I'd say that it's also quite pleasing to the eye. I think I'd happily frame that, mount it, and have it hanging from the wall in my flat (somewhere close to the teapot). People walk through castles and talk in hushed tones of all the many things "these stones" have seen. All of the stories they might tell, if they could only speak. But this... unlike your average rock, this is unquestionably <em>memory</em>, and memory which lived through very exciting times in the development of our society. Here's something I look at and wonder what stories it might be able to tell, and what stories it has been forced to forget.</p>

<p>There are many things at the Computer History Museum which are very cool and certainly raise a smile (as well as an appreciative thought as to how far things have come). There are also things which just plain stop you in your tracks; the Difference Engine, for example. Well, at the risk of repeating myself, I'm going to post another picture of it, this time from the other side, so you can see a little bit more of the mechanism:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5154/5799104044_672ed38476.jpg"></p>

<p>Now there's a thing I would really and truly <em>love</em> to have in my flat. Ideally in a more coffee table friendly size, of course.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Different Kind of Tourism]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/05/a-different-kind-of-tourism/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-05T07:04:39+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/05/a-different-kind-of-tourism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If a person were to walk from downtown Mountain View (in so far as Mountain View has a town to be down of) to the Computer History Museum, and then kept going, they might find themselves wandering into Shoreline Business Park. This is where you would find the silicon in this part of the valley.</p>

<p>Of course, there isn't actually a lot of touristing to do in your average industrial park. We're in Silicon Valley here, though, surely there must be something to see? Well... there are signs for reasonably exciting tech companies, with logos and everything... for example:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3005/5799103956_bc27e02f68.jpg"><!-- header_img http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3005/5799103956_bc27e02f68.jpg --></p>

<p>Here's a fun one. 23 and Me is either a very cool company, or an utterly terrifying one, depending on your point of view. The basic idea is that you send them some of your spit (and some money). They use this to do some basic DNA profiling and tell you about your genetic predisposition towards certain diseases, your genetic predisposition to certain drugs, and a limited amount regarding your actual genetic ancestry. This all comes wrapped up in a neat web interface which updates as new discoveries are made. I'm generally of the the view that this is pretty cool.</p>

<p>Further in we find even more companies, at least one of which you might have even heard of:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3123/5799103942_418f7a2a37.jpg"></p>

<p>LinkedIn is basically a professional version Facebook. Sort of a fancy online business card holder, networking centre, recruitment system and industry conference all rolled into one. As such, it allows you to show your respectable side to your business contacts, whilst still being able to display that photo set proving that you <em>can</em> get your entire fist in your mouth to your friends. It can be quite useful, but more on that in a moment. I had no idea who the other companies on the sign are, and have not, as yet, felt too much of a need to enlighten myself.</p>

<p>There is, of course, another tech company with a fairly large presence in this business park, but I can't for the life of me remember their name. Oh, wait, yes. I remember:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2536/5799103924_e8db3349eb.jpg"></p>

<p>When in doubt, follow the street signs. While I'm sure it is helpful to have signs pointing to <em>stuff</em> (other examples in this estate include "movies" and "amphitheatre") hanging above the road, making them indistinguishable from street signs is bloody confusing, in my opinion.</p>

<p>Google is, of course, the whole reason I'm in this town, and in fact in this country for these two weeks. For the record, I was recruited via LinkedIn, so it definitely does have it's uses. One of the reasons for this wander was to get a general idea of the lay of the land surrounding the Googleplex. My overall opinion: it's big. Luckily, the Google bikes were very much in evidence:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5302/5798555777_9a73976a1c.jpg"></p>

<p>Often being found looking slightly forlorn in the strangest places. I'm fairly sure the local teens play a bit of cat and mouse with security guards and joyride around the park on them at weekends. This one was close to one of the volleyball courts:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5276/5799104166_5e5af56a28.jpg"></p>

<p>There actually is a reasonable amount to see, wandering around the campus. Google really does live up to a lot of its hype. One of the more famous landmarks of the campus was actually bloody difficult to find, though. It took a serious amount of detective work, comparing photos from the web to views from Google Maps, but I finally tracked down the "Android Lawn":</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2158/5798559713_a16b044a86.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3533/5798559919_da0f44242b.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2757/5798560063_64d6567a61.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2016/5798560409_d1608f766e.jpg"></p>

<p>As it turned out, if I'd just stood up and looked over my right shoulder from the place I was performing all of this furious Googling, I probably would have just spotted the damn thing. Such is life. Strangely enough, I was feeling a little hungry at this point, so I headed home.</p>

<p>Finally, it is important to note that while all of this touristing around is fun, and Google is a fuzzy and well meaning company, you should never forget that these are serious guys, doing a serious job. One most always strive to live up to the standard set by those who come before you, and always act in a professional and responsible manner when surrounded by such a high caliber of people.</p>

<p>Seriousness. Responsibility. Decorum.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3543/5799108082_ceb1e2603d.jpg"></p>

<p>That is all.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
