<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Globetrotter | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/globetrotter/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-11T22:26:26+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Whilst Not Running in Australia (With Photos!)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/08/11/whilst-not-running-in-australia/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-11T14:10:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/08/11/whilst-not-running-in-australia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In throwing up a few pictures of my trip down under in that <a href="blog/2013/04/07/running-the-first-time/">previous running related post</a>, I realised I hadn't really posted much else about that particular trip to the inter webs. I also realised that picking through those photos is a bit of a bad idea, because I'd forgotten just how much I enjoyed Perth.</p>

<p>I tend to say that I "spent about 10 weeks in Australia in 2010." I use this slightly odd wording because I actually had two trips out there with a short break in-between. That break was partly due to logistics and also because the customer decided to finally announce they wanted me on site a little under six weeks before the single date for the entire of 2010 for which I refused to be anywhere other than St Andrews, Scotland. This was the date of a good friend's wedding, at which I was to be a groomsman (among the biggest honours which has ever by extended to me) and thus it was not even on the negotiating table. "Don't worry," they said. "Our operations calendar is such that we won't need you for more than a couple of weeks." I'm sure you can see where this is going…</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>First of all let me assure you that travelling from Edinburgh to Perth in cattle class is no fun what so ever. Especially via what appears to be a budget carrier. Twenty seven hours in the metaphorical saddle left me staggering out of Perth airport and into a rental car at around 4am.</p>

<p><em>Side note: this was the first time I'd made use of a rental car whilst by myself. If you ever find yourself in this situation and you're given the option of a sat nav: take it.</em></p>

<p>I found my way to my beachside motel, stripped the bed down to check for spiders (yes, I was bloody paranoid), re-dressed it, and then fell asleep for something in the region of 12 hours. This was jet lag on an epic scale. Having prised myself out of bed and checked in with the customer the next day I had a bit of time at liberty. I was also quite close to King's Park, one of the things the internet had recommended. I figured it was worth half an hour of my time...</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/08/11/DSC00782.JPG"></p>

<p>Three or four hours later I got back in the car. King's Park is, not to put too fine a point on it, utterly beautiful. Walking around it I found one delightful surprise after another.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/08/11/DSC00829.JPG"></p>

<p>It's perched on a hill close to the river and the central business district, giving you a a fantastic view of what's actually a very attractive city anyway.</p>

<center>
<img src="/images/blog/2013/08/11/DSC00816.JPG"><!-- header_img /images/blog/2013/08/11/DSC00816.JPG -->
</center>


<p>This was also where I saw my first free roaming parrot. At the time I thought this was incredibly special. Later I would discover that Perth has parrots in the same way London has pigeons.</p>

<p>After this it was back to work for a week or so. I did, however, get to spend some time hanging out at a beautiful secluded beach with incredibly clear water…</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/08/11/DSC00872.JPG"></p>

<p>…shame about the factory piers to either side, though. With the beach trials completed I was shipped out for the first of four trips to Karratha in the North of Western Australia, which is very hot, very red and has very beautiful sunsets.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/08/11/DSC00904.JPG"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/08/11/P1000253.JPG"></p>

<p>It also has a gas refinery, which (believe it or not) is essentially the setting for a <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0803061/">2011 romantic comedy</a>.</p>

<p>Back in Perth I found some time to do more touristing, this time with a cohort in tow. Caversham Wildlife Park is a good place to get up close and personal with some kangaroos:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/08/11/DSC00969.JPG"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/08/11/DSC00971.JPG"></p>

<p>You can also pet a koala here, though I remain firmly convinced it had no idea we were even there.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/08/11/DSC00964.JPG"></p>

<p>Case in point: this koala is almost certainly walking in the exact opposite direction to the one you would expect:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/08/11/DSC00966.JPG"></p>

<p>...and I'm going to split this in half here, and return with some attempts at more arty shots in a later post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Perilously Close to Perfection]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/04/19/perilously-close-to-perfection/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-19T17:09:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/04/19/perilously-close-to-perfection</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A friend told me about a restaurant he'd visited on a trip to New York. There was essentially no menu. You walked in, you are seated, and you are asked a single question:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>"How would you like your steak cooked?"</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Then they bring you an utterly fantastic steak with fries and bernaise sauce. They do this <em>one</em> thing, they do it incredibly well, and they do it cheaply because they can take advantage of economies of scale.</p>

<p>I love this mindset of setting out to do something as utterly right as humanly possible. The example I had previously was a cafe in Edinburgh called Loudon's. This is obviously the result of someone setting out to create as perfect a cafe as possible. It's incredibly well laid out. Lots of tables, but not even a little bit cramped. So much so, in fact, that the presence of parents with small children doesn't ruin the atmosphere. They just get lost in the space. This is not enough by itself, obviously. The coffee is also very good and the food is absolutely first rate. Don't even get me started on either the quantity or the quality of the cakes.</p>

<p>So where am I going with this? Well, this last week during a short(ish) break in Austria, I found another one.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>Bad weather led us to take a day trip into Salzburg, which we wandered around aimlessly for a few hours. Getting dinner in town pushed us to a late train… but where to get dinner and what to do to entertain ourselves for a few hours. Someone mentioned a brewery one of our PMs (Product Managers) had recommended. A brewery with attached drinking hall which serves food. Apparently they served the best beer he'd ever tasted. Even coming from a PM* this is the sort of claim which needs to be be tested… and what the hell, it was on the way to the station (ish) anyway.</p>

<p>So we take a wander to this brewery… and I'm here to tell you that I'm very glad that we did. We walked in. We were asked (at this point) three questions:</p>

<ol>
<li>How many people?</li>
<li>Smoking or non-smoking?</li>
<li>How many beers would you like?</li>
</ol>


<p>Beautiful. We were shown to a table in a fairly massive room (one of three). Simple chairs simple tables. A friendly buzz, but in no way crowded.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/18/IMG_1171.jpg"></p>

<p>Within minutes the very same guy had reappeared at our table carrying <em>eight litres of beer</em>. How good was this beer? It was pretty awesome. Frankly I'm still craving it. How much was this beer? I'll come back to that.</p>

<p>There was no table service for food, but just outside of the room was, for all intents and purposes, a small food market.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/19/IMG_1169.jpg"></p>

<p>I wondered back and forth for a little while before deciding on half a roast chicken with a small pretzel on the side. Huge grin firmly affixed on face (as Spartacus might say) I proceeded to gleefully wash this meat and starch based feast down with more of that wonderful beer.</p>

<p>Some hours later we stood, fully satiated and mildly inebriated. We waited with beer baited breath to see what the bill would say. How much was this beer?</p>

<p>€6.70 a litre.</p>

<p>You're basically paying that for a <em>pint</em> in London, and it's probably not as good. Not even close. For me, they really knocked this one out of the park.</p>

<p>If you're in Salzburg, by all means see the kirk (it's beautiful), drop by the castle (it's really interesting… though you might want to stay out of the creepy marionette museum) and eat a slice of Sachertorte (it's tasty). But when you're looking for some hearty food and perhaps an adult beverage or three, you really need to drop by the church of beer, meat and starch. You'll be glad you did.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/18/IMG_1166.jpg"><!-- header_img /images/blog/2013/04/18/IMG_1166.jpg --></p>

<p>* You can't trust 'em ;-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Categories and Goals]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/03/25/categories-and-goals/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-25T22:53:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/03/25/categories-and-goals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's good to have goals. Even if you fail to meet them. Sometimes especially when you fail to meet them. It's quite widely publicized that at Google we're expected to score 0.7 (on a scale where 0 is a complete failure and 1 means all targets were met) when assessing our OKRs (objectives and key results). Generally this is good. It means you're always striving, always raising your eyes, hitting the top of the tree by aiming for the sky.</p>

<p>In my personal life, though, this probably isn't the best approach. Be that as it may, this year I have goals.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>1. Get myself in shape.</p>

<p>Also known as: project "look good naked". There's a bit more to it than this, of course. There's also a bit of a story behind it, which I'll probably tell in a later post. I also have some ideas around this area which might turn into something else. If I'm going to set goals, I need a way to measure success, after all.</p>

<p>Talking about this here leaves me with a slightly odd problem, though. When I relaunched this blog I adjusted all of my category names to be descriptive nouns, which means a can auto-generate the part of the about text (on the right) which references them. I don't know what the appropriate noun is for someone who participates in and thinks about fitness related activities. This is a stupid problem to have, but it is a problem, nevertheless.</p>

<p>2. Get my House in order.</p>

<p>In the literal sense. One of the reasons things went dark on this blog last year is that I actually took the plunge and bought a flat. This ate a lot of my time and left my life in a bit of an inconsistent state for a month or so. Now I'm in, though, and having spent a winter in the place I've taken stock. It needs some work. It needs to be warmer when the weather is cold. It needs a bit more personality… and some of the really odd design decisions made by the previous owners need to be reversed.</p>

<p>It's also a whole new playground for me to seek adventures in. My Clockwork Aphid project was a casualty of the upheaval in my life last year and I'm not sure how much attention it'll get this year… because this year I'd also like to start playing with home automation. Nothing crazy. No robot butlers; but we'll see.</p>

<p>3. Read. Travel. Watch. Write.</p>

<p>This one is more straight forward. I'd like to start more closely measuring how much a read, travel, watch (mainly in terms of films) and write, on this blog an elsewhere.</p>

<p>Reading is straightforward, I think. I read a lot. On my way to work, before bed, in coffee shops at the weekend, But I'm curious to try and keep tabs on what I'm reading and how much. It frustrates the hell out of me that my kindle can't easily supply me with the information.</p>

<p>One of my friends has a goal for this year that she will get out of Edinburgh at least once every month. That's not a bad goal to have at all. For me, I'd just like to see and experience more of the wider world in general, but also the part of it which I inhabit.</p>

<p>As for watching films and keeping tabs on what I saw… well… I already have <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com">a place to keep tabs on that</a>. Simple. This is mostly a matter of "keep it up".</p>

<p>Lastly: writing. Er… yes. I don't have such a great record with this one. Obviously I want to get back to posting regularly on this blog… but I'd also like to try and do something with the two screenplays I wrote during university (and the pile of partially developed ones). I used to regularly do some sort of creative writing and lately I'm starting to feel the lack of it in my life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wandering Around London]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/05/17/wandering-around-london/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T21:57:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/05/17/wandering-around-london</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apologies, once again, for the radio silence. Over the past couple of months there have been some complications in my private life, and a remarkable amount of my attention has been taken up with figuring out where exactly I'm going to be living after my current lease runs out (more on that later, perhaps).</p>

<p>Be that as it may, after almost a year, I did find some time to go wandering around the city I now call home. Whilst I took every opportunity to make a brisk constitutional around Edinburgh, I'd never managed to really do this in London. Part of the reason, I think, is while that you can essentially wander across central Edinburgh in an hour or two, this is really not the case in London. Nipping across town via public transport can take <em>hours</em>.</p>

<p>Recently, though, two excellent excuses presented themselves. Firstly, my father came to visit for a few days and professed an interest to go take a good look at <a href="http://www.kew.org/">Kew Gardens</a>, the Japanese themed portion in particular.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First stop was the <a href="http://www.kew.org/visit-kew-gardens/garden-attractions-A-Z/Pagoda.htm">Pagoda</a>:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0402.jpg"></p>

<p>This is a fairly impressive and imposing building, at least from a distance. Close up it's curiously less so. I think it's the red brick construction which does it. I've never visited Japan, but this seems a slightly inappropriate building material to me. My father, who has, concurred.</p>

<p>Next was the <a href="http://www.kew.org/visit-kew-gardens/garden-attractions-A-Z/japanese-gateway.htm">Japanese Gateway</a> which, in conjunction with the weather, gave me an excellent opportunity to try out the HDR mode on my phone's camera. Here it is without the benefit of HDR:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/17/IMG_0408.jpg"></p>

<p>…and here it is with the HDR turned on:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0409.jpg"></p>

<p>I'll be listing that featuring under "worthwhile" from here on out. At this point it's probably worth confirming a slightly frustrating fact which I suspect is now true of many people: the camera on my phone has completely killed any use of my point and shoot camera. It's extremely convenient (being as I <em>always</em> have it with me) and, since my last upgrade, actually very capable. The only thing it lacks is zoom, which is a trade off I'm willing to make. If I plan on going on a serious photo taking excursion at any point in the future I may bite the bullet and pick up a decent digital SLR. The point and shoot just feels like a weird middle gear at this point.</p>

<p>Back to Kew Gardens, though. Tucked off to one side and not especially well advertised is the Bonsai house. It's small, but quite cool, and something my dad specifically wanted to see (Bonsai being a hobby of his).</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0448.jpg"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0450.jpg"></p>

<p>Next, we moved away from the specifically Asian attractions and took a look in the <a href="http://www.kew.org/visit-kew-gardens/garden-attractions-A-Z/Palm-House.htm">Palm House</a>. This really is an impressive building, if uncomfortably hot and humid. Be ready to sweat, all ye who enter here. Besides the tropical plants (which I don't seem to have taken any pictures of), the green house itself has an impressive art deco* construction:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0451.jpg"></p>

<p>Shortly after this, we took the train from Richmond back to my flat, and I had the fun of explaining to my father the difference between underground and overground trains this far out of the centre ("you can tell that's an underground train because it says 'underground' on it…").</p>

<p>A week or two later, I professed a desire to go see <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com/post/19950925968/john-carter">John Carter</a> to friend who suggested we see it in Canary Wharf, allowing us to go wandering around the area beforehand. So we did.</p>

<p>Canary Wharf is one of the parts of London containing buildings which can legitimately be called skyscrapers (I think). I believe it's also London's financial district. Surprisingly, I actually find it a very pleasant place to be. The taller buildings make you feel as though you're walking through canyons, and the area is very clean, though not to the point of feeling antiseptic.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0463.jpg"></p>

<p>At the weekend it's extremely quiet without quite feeling like a ghost town and there are a surprising amount of things to find. These include a large underground mall, some very cool riverside buildings:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/17/IMG_0460.jpg"></p>

<p>…and one or two very cool statue / landmark type things:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0456.jpg"><!-- header_img /images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0456.jpg --></p>

<p>Interestingly, the whole area is also private property, so you might have submit to a vehicle search on the way in. Be that as may, I can recommend it as a reasonable place to wander around at the weekend.</p>

<p>Until next time...</p>

<p>* This is art deco, right?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New (ish) Year, New (ish) Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/03/17/new-ish-year-new-ish-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T11:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/03/17/new-ish-year-new-ish-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2011 was an interesting year for me. A lot changed. I turned 30. After 10 years of residency I moved away from Edinburgh, a city I love dearly, and took a job in London. With <a href="/blog/tags/google">Google</a>. As a result, I no longer work with <a href="/blog/tags/autonomous-underwater-vehicles">Autonomous Underwater Vehicles</a> for a living. Instead I build web services. Quite the change, I'm sure you'll agree. In the early months of the year I finally completed the corrections to my <a href="/blog/tags/phd">PhD</a>, and then in the summer: I graduated. It took 6 years (all together) but I am now Dr. Nick Johnson. I also <a href="/blog/2011/07/18/the-sound-of-one-hand-clapping/">lost my grandmother</a>, a fact which still brings me to tears on occasion.</p>

<p>In this light, the fact that I decided, towards the end of the year, to shift my blog away from <a href="http://wordpress.org">Wordpress</a> and over to its own domain barely even casts a shadow. I did, though, and as a result you're now reading these words on a site built using <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>, which is hosted at harveynick.com. As you may have noticed, all of the old posts from my <a href="http://harveynick.wordpress.com">wordpress site</a> have been ported over, minus the short film reviews, which you'll find <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com">here</a>. I'm not going to go into how I accomplished this, except to say: I did it the same way <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/2011/09/12/blogging-with-octopress/">Matt Gemmel did</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='It&#8217;s not finished, but it will serve well enough for me to try and start producing actual content again'>
For the most part, this site is stock Octopress. I've played with the fonts, made the heading and background static and added a little more infrastructure (index pages for tags, embed scripts for YouTube and Vimeo videos and a couple of other bits). It's not finished, but it will serve well enough for me to try and start producing actual content again. I do want to make it a bit more visual, particularly the front page, and somehow integrate other content I produce into it. I also want to make it work a little better on mobile browsers and, lastly, make it a little bit more my own. The colours will change, and I'll try to find a background which doesn't require such a large file and isn't so closely associated with Apple.
</span></p>

<p>What will I be writing about though? Well:</p>

<p>I plan to have <a href="/blog/tags/clockwork-aphid">Clockwork Aphid</a> actually doing something of use this year. I'm going to enhance the current Java version up to a point where it can generate interesting landscapes efficiently and in a parallel fashion. I'm then going to then have a crack at porting it to <a href="http://golang.org">Go</a>, which I think may turn out to be an excellent language for writing computer games.</p>

<p>I like films. Perchance you may have noticed. I may chat a bit more in depth about a couple of this year's releases. Just to pick three with a common theme off the top of my head:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>The Amazing Spider-Man</strong>. I went to a preview event for this in Leicester Square a month or two ago and was very impressed with what I saw. I'm hopeful they made a Spider-Man movie in the same way that Christopher Nolan makes Batman movies. Really really.</li>
<li><strong>The Dark Knight Rises</strong>. Speaking of which. This <em>is</em> exciting. It's the last of the trilogy. It's got a lot to live up to, especially since the last film Nolan made was <em>Inception</em>. I wouldn't bet against it, though.</li>
<li><strong>The Avengers</strong>. Now here's a film with some scope. All these characters in one film? With this cast? Written and directed by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joss_Whedon">Joss Mother Fucking* Whedon</a>? Please, please let this film live up to the frankly stupid amount of potential it has.</li>
</ul>


<p>Quite recently, at the aforementioned age of 30, I started playing Dungeons and Dragons with a selection of my colleagues. Well, we're actually playing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pathfinder_Roleplaying_Game">Pathfinder</a>, but let us not quibble about semantics. I'm having a really great time on several different levels. It's an interesting experience for someone who has played computer games for most of their life, but never dabbled in table top RPGs.</p>

<p>I mentioned before that I now have a shiny new PhD, with the letters before and after my name to prove it. I'm of the opinion that the work which led to this is quite interesting (but then I would be). It's also not completely divorced from my Clockwork Aphid project. I'm of a mind to try talking about this some, also.</p>

<p>See you when we get there.</p>

<p>* I think these are his actual middle names.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
