<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gym Rat | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/gym-rat/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-01T22:37:01+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Fitness Story]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/04/01/a-fitness-story/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-01T20:07:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/04/01/a-fitness-story</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During most of university I was in pretty crap shape, but in the second year of my PhD my physical condition got particularly lousy. I caught a bus every morning which left from directly outside my flat and took me directly to the university. I did pretty much no exercise and ate an awful lot of takeaway. A few of my friends remarked that I'd gained weight. "Don't worry," they said "it's fine," in response to my mortified expression, I'm sure "You look well with it". But I knew I looked nothing of the sort.  To paraphrase Eddie Izzard: when I looked in the mirror I sure as hell didn't want to have sex with myself.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>Then, as part of the job which ran in tandem with my studies I spend a couple of weeks working offshore on a maintenance ship. Where there was pretty much nothing to do. A worked, I ate, I slept. I played my way through Grand Theft Auto: San Andreas. But I also started to make use of the small gym on board the ship. Every day at around the same time I would go down, use the rowing machine for a while, use the cross trainer for a bit, maybe fiddle with the pec deck or the lat pulldown machine. Basically: I had no idea what I was doing… but I knew I had to do something.</p>

<p>Back on dry land I signed up for a gym and was given a workout program as part of a complementary training session. I told the trainer I wanted to use the machines and not the free weights, basically because I thought the guys who used the free weights were a bit douchey (based on the evidence I'd seen on the ship and the one time I'd visited the university gym). So for a year or two I diligently hit the gym three evenings a week and gradually increased the amount of weight I was moving around. Equally gradually I also started to like what I was seeing in the mirror.</p>

<p>It didn't last, though. My circumstances changed and I found myself working full time in a different part of the city, while also needing to finish writing my thesis. Getting to the gym in the evenings was now a lot harder… and so started to not happen. I fell back into bad habits and put back on a lot of the weight I'd lost.</p>

<p>I kept trying to get back on the wagon. Twice I started <a href="http://www.nhs.uk/Livewell/c25k/Pages/couch-to-5k-plan.aspx">Couch to 5k</a>, and twice I failed to make it all the way through. The first, ironically, because I was sent to work offshore again in my previous job, and then my second attempt was scuppered by a foot injury. Every once in a while I would manage to drag myself to the work gym down here in London… but I didn't have any sort of a plan and I didn't really make any sort of progress.</p>

<p>Then it happened. This is the part of the story I'm very hesitant about discussing further. It's deeply personal. But it's also key.</p>

<p>I found myself in a rather fantastic situation with a very attractive member of the opposite sex. One I'd wanted to be in for some time. It was, as I'm sure you can imagine, a very positive experience. But it was also mortifying, because I found myself looking at this gorgeous lady and realizing how hard I was trying <em>not</em> to look at myself. The contrast between us was, to me, quite shocking. It was then that I thought to myself (and yes, I'm aware of the cliche) "I have to get myself in shape" and this time I rally, really meant it.</p>

<p>What happened next? Well… fitness wise I got really geeky about it. Really geeky indeed. I'll talk about it more in a different post, but I will say this: I'm definitely making progress, much more successfully than I every did before. Project "look good naked" is in effect, and I'm bringing the technologies.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Categories and Goals]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/03/25/categories-and-goals/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-25T22:53:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/03/25/categories-and-goals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's good to have goals. Even if you fail to meet them. Sometimes especially when you fail to meet them. It's quite widely publicized that at Google we're expected to score 0.7 (on a scale where 0 is a complete failure and 1 means all targets were met) when assessing our OKRs (objectives and key results). Generally this is good. It means you're always striving, always raising your eyes, hitting the top of the tree by aiming for the sky.</p>

<p>In my personal life, though, this probably isn't the best approach. Be that as it may, this year I have goals.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>1. Get myself in shape.</p>

<p>Also known as: project "look good naked". There's a bit more to it than this, of course. There's also a bit of a story behind it, which I'll probably tell in a later post. I also have some ideas around this area which might turn into something else. If I'm going to set goals, I need a way to measure success, after all.</p>

<p>Talking about this here leaves me with a slightly odd problem, though. When I relaunched this blog I adjusted all of my category names to be descriptive nouns, which means a can auto-generate the part of the about text (on the right) which references them. I don't know what the appropriate noun is for someone who participates in and thinks about fitness related activities. This is a stupid problem to have, but it is a problem, nevertheless.</p>

<p>2. Get my House in order.</p>

<p>In the literal sense. One of the reasons things went dark on this blog last year is that I actually took the plunge and bought a flat. This ate a lot of my time and left my life in a bit of an inconsistent state for a month or so. Now I'm in, though, and having spent a winter in the place I've taken stock. It needs some work. It needs to be warmer when the weather is cold. It needs a bit more personality… and some of the really odd design decisions made by the previous owners need to be reversed.</p>

<p>It's also a whole new playground for me to seek adventures in. My Clockwork Aphid project was a casualty of the upheaval in my life last year and I'm not sure how much attention it'll get this year… because this year I'd also like to start playing with home automation. Nothing crazy. No robot butlers; but we'll see.</p>

<p>3. Read. Travel. Watch. Write.</p>

<p>This one is more straight forward. I'd like to start more closely measuring how much a read, travel, watch (mainly in terms of films) and write, on this blog an elsewhere.</p>

<p>Reading is straightforward, I think. I read a lot. On my way to work, before bed, in coffee shops at the weekend, But I'm curious to try and keep tabs on what I'm reading and how much. It frustrates the hell out of me that my kindle can't easily supply me with the information.</p>

<p>One of my friends has a goal for this year that she will get out of Edinburgh at least once every month. That's not a bad goal to have at all. For me, I'd just like to see and experience more of the wider world in general, but also the part of it which I inhabit.</p>

<p>As for watching films and keeping tabs on what I saw… well… I already have <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com">a place to keep tabs on that</a>. Simple. This is mostly a matter of "keep it up".</p>

<p>Lastly: writing. Er… yes. I don't have such a great record with this one. Obviously I want to get back to posting regularly on this blog… but I'd also like to try and do something with the two screenplays I wrote during university (and the pile of partially developed ones). I used to regularly do some sort of creative writing and lately I'm starting to feel the lack of it in my life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
