<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gym Rat | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/gym-rat/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-10T15:40:20+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Further Watching and Reading]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/21/further-watching-and-reading/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-21T20:37:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/21/further-watching-and-reading</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was supposed to go at the end of my last post, but it was running a little long. Basically, here is collection of writings about fitness from around the internet which I've found either useful, thought provoking, or fun.</p>

<p><em>Warning: the blog post features two pictures of women in bikinis. It's totally relevant in context, be in case that isn't safe for your work: be warned.</em></p>

<!-- More -->


<h3><a href="http://www.mensjournal.com/magazine/everything-you-know-about-fitness-is-a-lie-20120504">Everything You Know About fitness is a Lie</a></h3>

<p>I really have to start here, because I think this is possibly the best article about fitness I've ever read. The internet, by and large, seems to agree with me. I'll keep me commentary on it to a minimum. Seriously. Go read it.</p>

<h3><a href="http://matt.might.net/articles/hacking-strength/">Matt Might on Gaining Muscle with Least Resistance</a></h3>

<p><a href="http://matt.might.net/">Matt Might</a> is an assistant professor in Computer Science at the University of Utah. His posts on programming languages are a fairly common sight towards the top of <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/">Hacker News</a>. Then out of nowhere he wrote this post about how he'd gone about getting himself into shape. I don't agree with everything he writes here*, but this is a well written post which is worth reading for three things in particular:</p>

<ol>
<li>His motivations, which I can understand completely, even though I don't have kids of my own;</li>
<li>The improvement in his overall quality of life;</li>
<li>It's basically an ode to the principle of "the best workout program is the one which works for you".</li>
</ol>


<h3><a href="http://www.soheefit.com/cardio-bunny-stop-it-stop-it-now/">Sohee Lee on Why Being a Cardio Bunny is Bad for Your Butt</a></h3>

<p>This one (and the next one) is for you, H. You know who you are.</p>

<p>Here's an article by Sohee Lee, who is actually the online trainer I worked with. That really didn't work out, but I still have a lot of respect for her and the philosophy behind a lot of her writing. The TL;DR here is that if you (girls) want your ass to look like this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.soheefit.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/Screen-shot-2012-01-23-at-12.10.22-AM1.png" title="Definitely copyright Sohee Lee" ></p>

<p>...you should do heavy squats, <em>not</em> cardio. Let's continue along that thread some.</p>

<h3>Miss America's Workout Program</h3>

<p>Now let's talk a little bit about one of Miss Sohee Lee's clients. It seems to be the case that women don't want to lift weights, because they're worried it will make them bulky. I guess that depends on how you define bulky. This is a picture of Mallory Hagan, the current Miss America:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://www.aceshowbiz.com/images/wennpic/mallory-hagan-2013-miss-america-final-competition-04.jpg"></p>

<p>Now, I can only speak for myself here, but I do not look at that picture and think "too bulky." To pull a quote from the West Wing, I look at that picture and think something along the lines of "That's a fine looking woman." If you're thinking the same thing, perhaps you're curious about her training program. I'll let her explain:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/NfnyBOpCZOU" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>I guess the takeaway here is that if you're female, lifting heavy weights isn't going to suddenly make you look like an Olympic weight lifter. If you work incredibly hard you might end looking a bit more like an Olympic heptathlete though, if you catch my drift.</p>

<p>Why do I care? It's not entirely un self serving. I personally think that healthy is more attractive than skinny. See also: <a href="http://www.bodbot.com/Blog/Rise_of_the_Hardbodied_Woman.html">The Rise of the Hard Bodied Woman</a> and <a href="http://i2.cdnds.net/13/12/618x335/movies_star-trek-into-darkness.jpg">Alice Eve in Star Trek Into Darkness</a>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.youtube.com/channel/UCduKuJToxWPizJ7I2E6n1kA">Bro Science Life</a></h3>

<p>Okay, time for a little bit of comedy. Bro Science Life is a YouTube channel featuring a series of fitness / gym related comedy videos. I find most of them utterly hilarious (but then I used to think <a href="http://askaninja.com/">Ask a Ninja</a> was hilarious as well).</p>

<p>The videos are, in particular, making fun of "bro culture", which in my experience does exist, but is not as prevalent as you might think. There's also actually a surprising amount of solid information in the videos, if you can separate the "funny because it's true" from the hyperbole and comedy bro science. <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_0WxyKGD7sU">For example</a>:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/0WxyKGD7sU" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>I think I actually agree with all of that… except for the thing about not using small plates. Slow and steady wins the race.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.strstd.com/">Strength Standards</a></h3>

<p>Lastly here's a site a friend introduced me to, and which I've come to find quite useful. Basically: plug in your gender and weight, then your weight and reps for each of the four primary barbell lifts. It then gives you a theoretical one rep max, and places you on a scale from "Untrained" to "Elite". I find it to be a fairly useful progress tracking tool. Also: I like graphs.</p>

<p>* I wouldn't go anywhere near that "strength training" contraption.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Barbell Training Follow Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/19/barbell-training-follow-up/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-19T18:23:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/19/barbell-training-follow-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So: after writing that giant post about the three main beginners programs I read up on while trying to figure out the best way to get myself into some sort of (non round) shape, I thought I'd switch to a topic on which I can confidently talk with some authority: me.</p>

<p>More specifically, in case you are interested: the program I've ended up putting myself on, the other things which are important and how this all is actually working out for me.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h2>The Program I'm Following</h2>

<p>As I mentioned in my <a href="http://harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/10/a-very-rough-guide-to-beginners-barbell-training-programs/">previous post</a>, I'm currently following the <a href="http://strengthvillain.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=9&amp;t=89">Greyskull LP</a> (Linear Progression) barbell training program, having previously spent a few months on <a href="http://stronglifts.com/">Strong Lifts 5x5</a> and then working with an online trainer for three months (which is another story entirely). Greyskull is made up of a "core program" (which I waffled about at length in my previous post, so will try to avoid repeating myself here) and a set of "plug-ins"* which add exercises or rearrange the program in order to add flexibility or meet specific goals.</p>

<p>I do the core program as previously described and add the following "plug-ins":</p>

<ol>
<li>On bench days I perform two sets of barbell curls, on press days two sets of V-Bar lat pulldowns, though I'll be switching that to weighted chin ups next time around;</li>
<li>On bench days I do two sets of either reverse crunches or knees to elbows, press days two sets of planks;</li>
<li>On "non training" week days I walk for around 40 minutes before breakfast (so completely fasted);</li>
<li>On Saturdays I go for a run. Fifteen minutes of intervals (Thirty seconds on, one minute off, times ten), followed by a fifteen minute steady jog;</li>
<li>Every evening before bed I do chin-up "ladders" (1 rep, 2 reps, 3 reps, 4 reps, 5 reps, 1 rep, and so on).</li>
</ol>


<p>The first of these is lifted directly from Johnny Pain's original forum post describing the program. The second is my replacement for the "neck harness" work also included in the forum post. I don't want a giant neck, but I would quite like to have abs. I also primarily put on fat around my middle and figure anything I can do to shift the muscle/fat ratio in that area is probably a good thing.</p>

<p>The fasted walk idea is suggested in the <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/The-Greyskull-LP-Edition-ebook/dp/B007WNC50Q">Greyskull LP book</a> as something to help with fat loss, and I figure "what the hell, can't hurt". I also like to do something active on my off days, as it seems conducive to keeping in good habits.</p>

<p>The Saturday run is something which was added to my program by the online trainer I worked with, and I found I really enjoyed. Working on stamina (when almost everything else I do is focussed on strength) seems like a good idea as well… especially in terms of being prepared for the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6TiXUF9xbTo">zombie apocalypse</a>. We all know the importance of cardio in those circumstances.</p>

<p>In my experience there is no better exercise than chin-ups for making you feel strong. Sure, you lift the heaviest in deadlift, and shoulder press actually lets you throw something above your head… but neither of these is quite the same as lifting yourself off the ground and into the air. Psychologically, that's huge. (Greyskull LP author) Johnny Pain actually recommends doing sets of chin-ups throughout the day, gradually increasing the number of set and reps, but suggests doing a ladder before bed as an alternative if this isn't practical for you. Option A is not even a little bit practical for me, so option B it is.</p>

<p>In general I'm really happy with this program and how I'm progressing. If my progress slows down, or I seem to need extra work in one area in particular, I'll likely switch to the four day version of the program. Hopefully neither of these will come up for a while, though.</p>

<p>Is this program right for you? Maybe. Maybe not. The ideal workout program is a lot like the ideal diet: it's the one you stick to.</p>

<h2>Other Variables</h2>

<p>It seems pretty logical that working out in the gym makes you stronger. Actually the opposite is true. Working out in the gym makes you weaker, if you're doing it right. When you lift heavy weights you damage your muscles and, in the short term, decrease their capability.</p>

<p>Your muscles don't get stronger until later, while you're asleep. Even then, they only do so if you've taken in adequate nutrition to feed their growth. Thus it's vitally important to ensure you're taking in enough food and getting enough sleep.</p>

<center>
<img src="http://varsitysideline.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/May13_2013.jpg"><!-- header_img http://varsitysideline.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/May13_2013.jpg -->
</center>


<p>Consistently getting quality sleep has always been a bit of a problem for me, but I do the best I can. My diet is more in my control, though. In general, I tend to concentrate on getting enough protein, which means plenty of chicken, fish or (more rarely) steak at lunch and dinner, and plenty of eggs at breakfast. I also tend top this up with one or two protein shakes a day.</p>

<p><em>Oh no! Supplements!</em></p>

<p>I'm generally of the opinion that most fitness related supplements to be complete bollocks, and likely to do you at least as much harm as good. That said, I don't include protein shakes in this category. It's basically food, if mildly suboptimal food. It is convenient, however, and sometime convenience is king. Choose the right brand** and drinking the things doesn't need to be a completely miserable experience, either.</p>

<p>I also try to make sure I get plenty of carbs, especially on days I work out. Yes, carbs. Evil, evil, insulin spiking carbs. I try to cut them out towards the the end of the day, though, a practice for which I've heard several explanations with varying degrees of "BroScience". Here's an example:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>The insulin created by the body to process and absorb carbs eaten stops the use of fat as an energy source. Your body naturally burns the most fat while sleeping, and so going to sleep with elevated insulin levels interferes with fat loss.</p><footer><strong>Micheal Matthews</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.amazon.co.uk/Bigger-Leaner-Stronger-Building-ebook/dp/B006XF5BTG'>"Bigger, Leaner, Stronger"</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>All of this being said: I am still a foodie. I still love eating good food with good food with good friends. Food is still an end in and of itself, and not just a source of nutrients. It's just that now I keep a much closer eye on what I'm consuming 90% of the time.</p>

<h2>How I'm Actually Doing</h2>

<p>Upcoming immodesty alert.</p>

<p>I think I can say at this point that I am without a shadow of a doubt in the best shape of my life. You need to understand here, though, that this is an extremely low bar for me to have lept over. This bar was basically underground.</p>

<p>Right now I am definitely stronger than I have been at any previous point in my life. Again, not hard. I'm definitely not "strong" in the absolute sense, but I am considerably stronger than I was before. Going climbing recently for the first time in years really brought this home.</p>

<p>At school I would collapse the ground after running the 1500m, then proceed to lay there panting and feeling my heart pounding (for some reason) in my butt cheeks. Now I usually end up running for a little under 6km on my Saturday runs, and at some point I plan to run an actual organised 5k. I think my time might actually be quite reasonable.</p>

<p>I'm also going to say that I look better (naked or otherwise) than I have at any previous point in my life. This is REALLY not difficult. At some point in the last ten or fifteen years I moved from the "skinny" category to the "skinny fat" category. That oh so sexy combination of podgy belly, visible ribs, pipe cleaner arms and incipient man boobs. Now I've gone down two waste sizes and clothes are more likely be tight around my chest than my belly. Friends have remarked that I've lost weight and have a bit more in the way of shoulders.</p>

<p>Brad Pitt in Fight Club I am not, but I don't hate what I see when I look in the mirror anymore, either. There are things wrapped around my skeleton which I could describe as muscles without worrying that I might be sniggered at. Stand me next to <strike>The Rock</strike> Dwayne Johnson and I'll still look like I'm made out of plastic spoons and low quality play dough, but I feel like I'm making progress in the right direction.</p>

<p>* Yes, "plug-ins". I'm sure you couldn't possibly imagine why this terminology might appeal to me.</p>

<p>** I tend to use PhD Nutrition Pharma Whey. It actually tastes pretty good... and alright, yes, fine, using a brand with that name kind of amuses me. My Dad likes Reflex, and one of my work colleagues goes for Optimum. Another uses PhD. Your millage may vary. Flavour wise: chocolate or banana, all the way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A (Very) Rough Guide to Beginners' Barbell Training Programs]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/10/a-very-rough-guide-to-beginners-barbell-training-programs/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-10T16:30:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/10/a-very-rough-guide-to-beginners-barbell-training-programs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I promised in my <a href="blog/2013/05/06/do-you-even-lift/">last post</a>, I'd now like to talk a bit about the different weight lifting programs I ended up researching. I spent a fairly silly amount of time here, so I'm hoping that you find it useful.</p>

<p>I'm going to talk about the three primary beginners lifters programs I read up on, tell you what they actually involve… and also what I think the person behind them is trying to sell you.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Disclaimer: I am not an expert on any of this.'>
<em>Disclaimer: I am not an expert on any of this. I am, at best, an amateaur of the sort who tends to read everything he can find about a subject which interests him (translation: a geek). You should consider the majority of what's written here to be opinion and look into these things yourself. I hope I can provide a good jumping off point, though.</em>
</span></p>

<!-- More -->


<p>Pretty much all the programs I've found centre around four barbell lifts. So I figured I'd start by quickly describing them:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Bench press.</em> You know what this one is. It's the one you saw in the montages of all those action movies. Lie with your back against the bench and lift the barbell from your nipples straight up until your arms are fully locked.</li>
<li><em>Shoulder press.</em> Stand with the barbell held approximately level with your shoulders, forearms vertical. Lift the bar directly upwards until your arms are fully locked. This has more nuance than it sounds.</li>
<li><em>Squat.</em> Stand with the bar braced across your shoulders, ideally resting on your lats. Drop down into a squatting position (duh) keeping your feet flat against the floor and pushing your knees apart. Stand, pushing up through your heels.</li>
<li><em>Deadlift.</em> I'm not going to try and explain this one. That's a lawsuit waiting to happen. Here's a video:</li>
</ul>


<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Syt7A23YnpA" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Having thrown a Mark Ripptoe video in this post already, it seems only right that I start with…</p>

<h3>Starting Strength (SS)</h3>

<p>Starting Strength is essentially three things:</p>

<ul>
<li>A barbell lifting program for beginners;</li>
<li>A <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Starting-Strength-3rd-Mark-Rippetoe/dp/0982522738">book</a> which describes the lifts in the program in <em>incredible</em> biomechanical detail;</li>
<li>A series of seminars.</li>
</ul>


<p>The man behind all three of these is one Mark Ripptoe, whose dulcet tones guided you through the deadlift in the video above. Pretty obviously: he wants to sell you a copy of his book (though hard copies are <em>really</em> hard to come by) or possibly a ticket to a seminar. In fairness there is pretty much nothing else like the book out there. It might arguably be more detail than you need, but it's still seriously impressive.</p>

<p>"Rip" is also something of personality. There are <a href="http://startingstrength.wikia.com/wiki/Wit_and_Wisdom_of_Mark_Rippetoe">entire websites</a> dedicates to things he's said. Here's one which made me laugh:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>"I don't go to titty bars much anymore. They have never really appealed to me. Like going into an expensive restaurant, reading the menu for 2 hours, drinking a little, then getting up and leaving without having had anything to eat but paying the bill anyway."</p><footer><strong>Mark Ripptoe</strong> <cite><a href='http://startingstrength.wikia.com/wiki/Wit_and_Wisdom_of_Mark_Rippetoe'>startingstrength.wikia.com/wiki/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>…and here's one which actually has something to do with what I'm supposed to be taking about here:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>"There is simply no other exercise, and certainly no machine, that produces the level of central nervous system activity, improved balance and coordination, skeletal loading and bone density enhancement, muscular stimulation and growth, connective tissue stress and strength, psychological demand and toughness, and overall systemic conditioning than the correctly performed full squat."</p><footer><strong>Mark Ripptoe</strong> <cite><a href='http://startingstrength.wikia.com/wiki/Wit_and_Wisdom_of_Mark_Rippetoe'>startingstrength.wikia.com/wiki/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>I'm going to admit right away that there is more to the actual program than I originally thought there was. I'll describe what I've seen called the "core" program here, but you can find a more complete explanation over at the <a href="http://www.fitocracy.com/knowledge/official-starting-strength-guide-for-fitocrats/">Fitocracy knowledge base</a>.</p>

<p>Each lift in the program is preceded by a warm up, which is the case for ever lift in every program here, even if I don't mention it. You start with the empty bar* and then increase the weight in stages until you reach your work weight.</p>

<p>In the Starting Strength program** you work out Monday, Wednesday and Friday, performing three lifts each day. There are two workouts, which you rotate:</p>

<ul>
<li>Workout A: Squat 3x5, shoulder press 3x5, deadlift 1x5.</li>
<li>Workout B: Squat 3x5, bench press 3x5, power clean 5x3.</li>
</ul>


<p>"Rotate" means that your first week would look like this:</p>

<ul>
<li>Monday: Workout A</li>
<li>Wednesday: Workout B</li>
<li>Friday: Workout A</li>
</ul>


<p>...then your second week would look like so:</p>

<ul>
<li>Monday: Workout B</li>
<li>Wednesday: Workout A</li>
<li>Friday: Workout B</li>
</ul>


<p>...and so on.</p>

<p>Firstly, the numbers after each of the lifts are in the form &lt;sets>x&lt;repetitions>. Secondly, the sharp eyed amongst you will probably have noticed that I snuck an extra lift in there. So, what exactly is a power clean? Basically, it's like a deadlift… but you keep going, explosively lifting the weight up to your shoulders (though not above your head).</p>

<p>Generally speaking weights should be increased gradually after each successful workout, and not usually by more than 2.5kg (except perhaps for the deadlift). Again, see the link to the Fitrocracy knowledge base above for more details, but I would also be quite remiss if I did not mention <a href="http://startingstrength.com/">StartingStrength.com</a>.</p>

<p>Also: anytime you want to see a good demonstration of a barbell lift, try typing "Mark Ripptoe &lt;name of lift>" into YouTube. This is a man who knows what he's talking about.</p>

<h3>Strong Lifts 5x5 (SL)</h3>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='This is the secret training program used by Arnold Schwarzenegger, apparently.'>
Strong Lifts 5x5 is very much a program from the internet. In fact, if you were to go <a href="http://stronglifts.com">stronglifts.com</a> there is a good chance that you might come away with the impression that Mehdi (the guy behind it) is trying to sell you snake oil. This is the secret training program used by Arnold Schwarzenegger, apparently. Ignore that, though, since insofar as I can tell this program is up there with SS for the amount respect it gets for a beginners program. Mehdi wants you to come to his website and make use of the resources there (which are actually pretty good), because he's monetized the site with ads. He would also like you to sign up for the paid "Strong lifts inner circle" members only community.
</span></p>

<p>SL is very similar in structure to SS in that it's the four main lifts plus one extra, with two alternating workouts each featuring three lifts to be performed on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays. The two workouts look like this:</p>

<ul>
<li>Workout A: Squat 5x5, bench press 5x5, Pendley Row 5x5.</li>
<li>Workout B: Squat 5x5, shoulder press 5x5, deadlift 1x5.</li>
</ul>


<p>This time around the fifth lift is the bent over (or Pendley) row, which is basically the exact opposite of the bench press. Yes, this is exactly as awkward as it sounds and, like the deadlift, is a really good way to knacker your back if performed incorrectly. That being the case, I'll let the man Glen Pendley himself explain it to you rather than trying to do the job myself:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZlRrIsoDpKg" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>The other differences to SS are that with SL you perform five sets of five reps at your work weight (deadlift is again one set), and you you have a strictly defined methodology for increasing the weight of your lifts:</p>

<ul>
<li>If you hit five reps on all five sets you add 2.5kg the next time you do the lift (5kg for deadlift);</li>
<li>If you miss any reps, you stay at the same weight;</li>
<li>If you miss reps multiple times, you deload by 10% and then work your way back up.</li>
</ul>


<p>This is the program I originally started doing, largely because it was easier to find a strict definition of what the program actually <em>was</em> than was the case for SS. It worked pretty well for me in the beginning, but as you increase the weight you'll also tend to increase the rest between sets, so after a couple of months I just seemed to be spending forever in the gym. In the end I stopped doing the program to try working with an online trainer, which I might talk about some in a later post.</p>

<h3>Greyskull Linear Progression (GLP)</h3>

<p>Greyskull LP is the beginners lifting program used at the Greyskull Barbell Club on the East Coast of the USA and created by the club's owner, John Sheaffer aka "Johnny Pain", a former student of Mark Ripptoe (remember him?).</p>

<p>What Johnny Pain is trying to sell you is the idea that you might like to train at his gym, and failing that maybe one of his books, such as the very one which <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Greyskull-LP-Second-John-Sheaffer/dp/0615635571">describes the program</a>. You can also find one variation of the program described in some detail by the man himself on <a href="http://strengthvillain.com/forum/viewtopic.php?f=9&amp;t=89#p376">the forums at StrengthVillain.com</a>, though not in anywhere near as much detail as in the book.</p>

<p>Side note about the book: I bought it. I think it's a really good resource and actually quite well written (I laughed out loud more than once), but perhaps not for the feint of heart. Dear old Johnny Pain can get a little bawdy, from time to time.</p>

<p>This is, again, very similar to Starting Strength, but with more of a focus on maintaining the linear progression for as long as possible. This is also a very flexible program, being made of a core program and a set of "plug-ins".</p>

<p>The core program is three days a week, again: Monday, Wednesday and Friday. For your first lift on each day, you alternate bench press and shoulder press. On Mondays and Fridays you then do squats. On Wednesdays: Deadlift. After warming up, you move on to three sets at your work weight. Again like SS, your first two sets are of five reps, however your third set is to failure (or as close to it as you're prepared to go), so basically as may reps as you can do, but at least five. The exception is the deadlift, for which you just perform a single set of as many reps as you can manage.</p>

<p>If you manage to hit at least 5 reps for each of your work sets, you increase the weight. 2.5kg for squat and deadlift, 1.25kg for bench and shoulder press. This last is actually quite tricky, since it involves using "fractional" plates, which most gyms don't carry and I, as yet, have not been able to find a good place to buy. If you fail to hit your five reps on each set you knock 10% off the weight for the next time (rounding down) and start working your way back up.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Seeing that you can now do eights reps at a weight you could only manage five at before drives home that you have gotten stronger and are making progress.'>
The upshot of this is that firstly the relaxed pace (two main lifts a day and small increases in weight) means that you're much less likely to stall and so will continue the linear progression for longer. Secondly, doing the third set to failure mean that you'll build a little more muscle (hypertrophy) and also you'll tend to hit either a reps or weight personal best every time you lift. Deloading can be frustrating in that it feels like moving backwards. Seeing that you can now do eights reps at a weight you could only manage five at before drives home that you have gotten stronger and are making progress.
</span></p>

<p>Given the amount of time I've spent talking about it, you might have worked out that this is the program I'm actually following at the moment. I liked the more gradual approach to increasing the weight here, and I like the additional flexibility of the plug-ins, which I'll talk about in another post.</p>

<p>* Or as close as possible, clearly that isn't going to work for the conventional deadlift. If you <em>do</em> need to start at a lower weight, however, you can improvise by either propping the weights up on spare plates, or perform a <a href="http://www.bodybuilding.com/exercises/detail/view/name/romanian-deadlift">Romanian Deadlift</a> instead.</p>

<p>** Calling it the SS program seems… wrong.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do You Even Lift, Bro?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/06/do-you-even-lift/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T15:24:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/06/do-you-even-lift</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After I arrived in London I decided to take a second stab at Couch to 5k, having abandoned it <a href="blog/2013/04/07/running-the-first-time/">the first time around</a>. The problem now was finding a time and place. At first I tried running in the evenings around Wandsworth Common, conveniently close to where I was staying. That started to feel more than a little unsafe, however, especially on the evenings I got home safe enough to push me through -twilight- dusk and into full dark. I'm fortunate enough to work very close to Hyde Park, however, so I transplanted my runs here and started taking time out of my work day. Running through Hyde Park in the sun is awesome, by the way.</p>

<p>All was fine and dandy until I fell off a surf board during a short break and cracked the top of my foot against the sea bed. I'd twisted myself into a slightly odd position in order to accomplishing this, and so it had the added bonus effect of pushing my foot much further back than it's really supposed to go. By the time I got back to London, my entire foot had turned a lovely combination of purple and yellow. Shit.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>Needless to say, this put a fairly major obstacle in the way of any running that I might try to do, given that it really hurt to even walk. So, once again, the running stopped. In parallel to all of this, however, I'd spent some time clicking around the "connected apps" section on Run Keeper's website and found something called <a href="https://www.fitocracy.com">"Fitocracy"</a>. It was two things rolled into one:</p>

<ol>
<li>A fitness related social network;</li>
<li>A gamification system which awards points and achievements based on fitness activities performed.</li>
</ol>


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Gamification works ridiculously well on my computer game addled brain.'>
Gamification works ridiculously well on my computer game addled brain. Scoring those points (and levelling up!) worked as an excellent motivator for me while I was running. When I signed up to the site I also joined the mailing list. Against all normal logic, some of those emails actually turned out to be quite interesting. A lot of them were member spotlights, and a lot of these members were talking about the fact that it was lifting weights, and not doing cardio, which got them into shape.
</span></p>

<p>
<center>
<a href="http://xkcd.com/940/">
<img src="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/oversight.png"><!-- header_img http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/oversight.png -->
</a>
</center>
</p>


<p>I did some more reading and found myself pointed at <a href="http://reddit.com/r/fitness">/r/fitness</a>, where a lot of people were saying very similar things. Two workout programs were suggested for beginners, <a href="http://startingstrength.com/">Starting Strength</a> and <a href="http://stronglifts.com/">Strong Lifts 5x5</a>. Having made <a href="blog/2013/04/01/a-fitness-story/">the decision to get myself back in shape</a>, I decided I would have a go at one of these programs. As for which, why, and what they entail: that's actually post of its own, because there are actually a couple of other programs I want to talk about as well. Stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Running, The First Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/04/07/running-the-first-time/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-07T22:54:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/04/07/running-the-first-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I decided to drag myself back on to the fitness wagon, it seemed to me that running was the answer. Getting myself to an actual gym clearly wasn't working, but I lived a short walk from a large and beautiful park (oh The Meadows, how I miss you still). I went out and spent what I still consider to be a fair amount of money on a pair of running shoes (Nike+ compatible, obviously). I've had knee issues in the past, which motivated me to err towards the top end of the range, I swear. The presence of the striking red headed shop assistant with her beautiful blue eyes and athletic physique had absolutely nothing to do with my decision.</p>

<p>What was I talking about? Running! Right.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/07/P1000436.JPG"><!-- header_img /images/blog/2013/04/07/P1000436.JPG --></p>

<p>Thusly equipped, I began striking out in the evenings and doing mixed running and walking intervals. Given my complete lack of a plan, I decided to work my way around the Meadows' sign posted mile long circuit, alternately running and walking the segments. After a couple of sessions of this, a few things become clear:</p>

<ul>
<li>I had absolutely no idea what sort of progress I was making. I was gathering no data;</li>
<li>I could only make fairly rough guesses at my actual pace;</li>
<li>I had no plan for how to increase the difficulty of my runs;</li>
<li>I wasn't having any fun. No data equals no graphs. No Graphs equals no fun. Obviously.</li>
</ul>


<p>As luck would have it, it was around that time when I stumbled across an ArsTecnica <a href="http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2009/11/reader-favorites-fitness-tech/">article which mentioned RunKeeper</a>, a combination of a website and (at the time) iPhone app which could be used to plan and track your runs. It would draw your route on a map, and draw all manner graphs of the data you generated. My. Oh. My.</p>

<p>Also mentioned in the review was the <a href="http://www.nhs.uk/Livewell/c25k/Pages/couch-to-5k-plan.aspx">Couch to 5K program</a>, an NHS approved to program to take you from doing no running at all to being able to run 5K in one session over a period of several weeks, with a particular focus on preventing you getting either a) injured or b) bored. Seemed like a plan. I didn't want to be either of those things.</p>

<p>Like any good nerd I didn't go right out and sign up with RunKeeper, but spent a good long while reading reviews of other apps, some of which were C25K specific. RunKeeper won out in the end, though, and I started following the program during my lunch breaks (much more manageable than the evenings if you live in Scotland and don't want to run in the dark). Then the thing I'd been waiting over a year for happened. I got on a plane to Australia to support <a href="http://www.unmanned.co.uk/unmanned-vehicles-news/unmanned-autonomous-underwater-vehicles-uuv-auv-news/seebyte-breaks-record-with-gavia-auv/">Fugro's first foray into autonomous pipeline tracking</a>.</p>

<p>Now I was in Perth (the warm one) with a fair amount of spare time on my hands. Sometimes running around Edinburgh could be a serious chore. Even in summer it's not exactly warm a lot of the time and often times it's a bit on the rainy side. Perth was something else altogether, however. I'd chosen to stay in a small motel in the west of the city because:</p>

<ul>
<li>It was close to where I would be doing my work in the first phase of the job, so my commute would be short;</li>
<li>It was much cheaper than the more central hotels my company would normally have used, so I could spend more of the budget on food.</li>
</ul>


<p>Somehow, the thing which I hadn't factored into my planning was that the motel was also about a minute's walk from the coast road. That was a nice surprise, I can tell you. A long, helpfully flat, road with a minimum of interruptions which winds around a beautiful beach… and, oh yeah, looks sort of like this around sunset:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/07/P1000203.JPG"></p>

<p>Let me tell you: running under these circumstances is not a chore. Don't get me wrong: generally speaking it's something I like having done, rather than something I actually like doing. But these are pretty ideal circumstances. While waiting for the operations to actually get into gear (a common theme with any work in this field) a managed to get in a fair few runs.</p>

<p>I'll tell you what's not ideal for running, though: getting sent to Karratha, a baking hot oil and gas company town in the North of Western Australia, which unlike Perth has a lot of really small things which can kill you really, really quickly. Quickly <em>and</em> painfully.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/07/DSC01052.JPG"></p>

<p>Even less ideal is actually being sent offshore and spending a week or so floating on a small boat. Less ideal still is if that boat turns out to be a catamaran, and this is how you find out that catamarans make you very, very seasick. I'd worked offshore previously and even in bad weather, so I swear I'm not usually that much of a delicate flower when it comes to a bit of pitch and roll… but the evidence doesn't lie. I've never spent more time hugging either a railing or a toilet bowl than I did on that trip. Try working a laptop under <em>those</em> circumstances. But I digress...</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/07/DSC00889.JPG"></p>

<p>The final nail in the coffin of this crack at C25K was actually arriving back in Edinburgh and finding that in summer the weather was far less clement that Perth's winter climate. Going outside and running just plain wasn't something I had the will for.</p>

<p>I don't want to be too unfair to Edinburgh, though. I mean, Perth doesn't have any of this:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/07/P1000458.JPG"></p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/blog/2013/04/07/P1000426.JPG"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
