<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: Micheal Paynter | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/tags/micheal-paynter/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-19T21:28:10+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epic Googleyep and Other Stories]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/17/epic-googleyep-and-other-stories/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-17T14:52:53+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/17/epic-googleyep-and-other-stories</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm currently doing some tests on a couple of different data structure implementations for Clockwork Aphid, so while they're running I thought I'd a bit of time to write a music related post, since I haven't done one in a while. So, contained within are three music related mini posts for your viewing pleasure.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Epic Googleyep</h2>

<p>As you may or may not be aware, I spent a reasonable percentage of this year (about ten weeks) working in Australia. Some of that time was spent working offshore in <a href="http://maps.google.com.au/?ie=UTF8&amp;ll=-20.430874,116.702271&amp;spn=1.429723,1.814117&amp;z=10">this general area</a>. I spent the latter offshore time on a boat called the Unlimited (fun fact: the company which owns this boat has two others: The No Limits... and The Limitless), a 24m catamaran, whitch for much of my trip had its full crew complement of twelve. For those of you counting at home, that's two metres each. It was... a little cramped. It did have a reasonable common area, however, with a great big flat screen TV. Outside the harbor, TV reception was less than good, and it was fairly common that the TV would be left on in an area of good reception, only to have us drift (or actively move) into a much crappier area.</p>

<p>Such was it that I wondered into the mess when a certain music video was trying to come through from the other side. At least 50% of it was static, but what I did hear I quite liked. Much of what I actually saw consisted of a slightly emo looking guy walking through a forest towards the camera, backed by two strikingly attractive and very similar looking ladies (at the time I thought it might have been the same girl twice) in evening dresses, one black and one white. I wanted to know more, but the signal gave out completely before the song finished.</p>

<p>I did not have a lot to go on, so the next time the internet was functional, I fired up Google and brazenly typed in "music video black dress white dress," and... win! I love it when that happens. Here's the video:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/OOfBwSYvIic" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Perhaps this is down to the alluring power of a well cut evening dress and a knowing smile, but&#8230; Damn'>
It's a little bit emo, but I like it. Good tune. Unless you're reading this in Australia you've probably never heard of Micheal Paynter, but likely have heard of the The Veronicas, the two ladies singing in the background. Now... Perhaps this is down to the alluring power of a well cut evening dress and a knowing smile, but... Damn. I've generally thought of them as "pretty" (and sometimes "annoying," musically) but they really are stunning in this video.
</span></p>

<h2>You Are Speaking My Language!</h2>

<p>The title of my previous series of programming language related posts was, in case you hadn't guessed, a reference to this:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/srIKcXWN6F0" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Now, I love Juliette &amp; The Licks, but this really isn't their best song. In actual fact I find this entire album extremely disappointing (with the exception of "I never got to tell you what I wanted to"), where as the other two albums don't really have a bad song on them. The song title fit the posts quite well, however, so I didn't feel I could leave it out. I spent some time on YouTube trying to work out which other song of theirs I should post as well, and ended up coming to the conclusion that this was a safe bet:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/2WDcCT3YeM" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>It's a good song and I love the video. I've also seen plenty of girls walking through Edinburgh at 11am on a Saturday who looked like they might break into this at any moment.</p>

<p>As an additional note here: Juliette Lewis herself confuses the hell out of me. I don't find her attractive no matter how hard I try, but I do find her extremely sexy no matter how hard I try not to.</p>

<h2>Gaga For Gaga</h2>

<p>It's another Lady Gaga cover and I love it!</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/2ga_pr0vuHA" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>This is clearly still Lady Gaga's "Bad Romance," but with a rock opera feel on top, which I feel works very, very well. I can imagine this version of the song sounding amazing sung by Freddie Mercury, but then I suspect that might be the case for most Lady Gaga songs (not coincidentally).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
