<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: ben moody | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/tags/ben-moody/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-17T22:45:19+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Musical Arithmetic]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/15/musical-arithmetic/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-15T12:40:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/15/musical-arithmetic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so here's the formula:</p>

<pre><code>(A - B) + C = D
</code></pre>

<p>And here are the variables:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>A = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UZjf9C6atT4" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Evanescence. More specifically: the original line up (as far as most of the world is concerned). I like Evanescence quite a bit, but that's about 74.2% Amy Lee's voice. The girl has one hell of a pair of lungs on her. I picked this particular song from the first album for reason which may become obvious later. For what it's worth, I think Everybody's Fool and Imaginary are a much better songs.</p>

<p>B = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/bP5wmtOXCQ" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Evanescence again? No. Well... yes, but the current line up. Specifically: Amy Lee herself. I picked this song from the second album (which is much better than the first) because it seems to have the most Amy Lee-ness in it. It doesn't have an actual video, though, so alternatively:</p>

<p>B = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Hqd2FJF8-h8" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>I figure having a deficit of Seether won't affect the sum either way, so this works too.</p>

<p>C = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dUyMvaJwACc" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Former Irish American Idol contestant* Carly Smithson. Once again: A hell of a pair of lungs. Not an entirely dissimilar look, but quite a different vocal style, it would appear. Carly's voice has a bit more blues in it, a bit more sultriness.</p>

<p>D = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/zzTZeeMCUBk" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><a href="http://www.wearethefallen.com/">We are the Fallen</a>, the new band from Ben Moody, two other former members of Evanescence and Carly Smithson. Can you seen why I picked that particular Evanescence song? That's more than a passing resemblance, style wise. There is a second reason I picked it, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kdYa0oeMLfI&amp;feature=related">however</a>. Carly has a less operatic voice, though, and a bit more range in terms of singing style. I love me some female fronted metal, so I'll be keeping an eye on this band.</p>

<p>Okay, here's another one which plays a bit better to her frankly spectacular voice:</p>

<p>D = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/u24NXTBHLYU" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>* That is: she's Irish and was a contestant on "American Idol." There is no such show as "Irish American Idol," so far as I'm aware.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
