<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Music | HarveyNick]]></title>
  <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/categories/music/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-12-27T21:05:13+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://harveynick.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In search of shiny Swedish music]]></title>
    <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/07/in-search-of-shiny-swedish-music/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-07T22:13:49+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/07/in-search-of-shiny-swedish-music</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So in my last (none film review) blog entry I posted a video by a Swedish goth metal band called "Beseech" and then mentioned that they'd split to form two other bands.<br/>
I was bored waiting for code to run today and did a little digging. Seems there's a bit more too it than that. The female singer joined formed another band called The Mary Major, which also has a male singer.<br/>
The male singer from Beseech is called Erik. He has a beard and long hair.<br/>
The male singer from The Mary Major is also called Erik and also has a beard, but has <em>short</em> hair and <em>wears a hat</em>.<br/>
But I am not fooled! Though he dons a disguise, my eyes do not lie! For it is he, the same Penniless Sitar Player! Wait... no... that's not right...<br/>
Anyway. In my opinion they aren't very good. They do have one song I like, though. It's called "Split" and you can find it on their myspace page, here:<br/>
<a href="http://www.myspace.com/themarymajor">The Mary Major</a><br/>
Others members of Beseech formed a band called Those We Don't Speak Of (TWDSO, henceforth), and their story is a little more interesting. Also, their music is better. Among the musicians who also joined the band was singer Sara Löfgren, an established singer songwriter. That interests me because it pretty much never happens here. Their home page seems to be down (I'll try and shed some light on that in a moment), but you can find some music here:<br/>
<a href="http://trig.com/twdso"></a><a href="http://www.myspace.com/twdso">TWDSO at MySpace</a><br/>
I quite like it. Not a lot of subtlety to be found, no, but there's a propulsive quality to the music I enjoy very much. Also I'm a complete sucker for a powerful female voice over the top of a driving heavy rhythm.<br/>
But wait... there's more. It seems Sara Löfgren left the band due to pregnancy and was replaced by another established solo artist. This time one Emma Varg, and you can listen to her here:<br/>
<a href="http://www.myspace.com/emmavargmusic">Emma Varg at MySpace</a><br/>
She also has a (mostly) working home page, here:<br/>
<a href="http://www.emmavarg.com">Emma Varg</a><br/>
<a href="http://www.emmavarg.com"></a>...which says she is looking for new members to join her band... and that was circa February 2008. Also, no mention of TWDSO and a lot of media links are broken on the site. Confusing, no? I'll come back to that, because first I want to talk about her music. Again, I like it, for much the same reasons as previously mentioned. There's also a brazen quality to her lyrics I like... and the closest we get to that in the UK is the Sugar Babes singing "..who do you want me to be, to make you sleep with me..."<br/>
I find I really want to listen to this new band, but am a little starved of information. Emma Varg's MySpace says that she's taking over on a temporary basis until she gets her new band members, but another interview suggested she was a permanent replacement. I almost suspect this new band will have a different name, that would explain the missing / broken home pages.<br/>
I also learned a new Swedish music related word today: Melodeath. I have resolved to find out more about it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclecticism]]></title>
    <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/05/eclecticism/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-05T15:02:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/05/eclecticism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seems the Facebook app does not do what it's supposed to. Never mind, I shall content myself with the (better) Wordpress interface. Maybe I'll look into writing a Facebook app which interfaces with my RSS feed. That would be cool.</p>

<p>I thought I would write a music related post, since I found a couple of things on YouTube which piqued my interest. First an entirely serious one:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vIhJC2-UNZA]</p>

<p>When I first heard this on the radio I thought it sounded so fresh they must be a new band. But no, they've been around quite a while, I even knew other songs by them. Unfortunately I don't like many of them, but you can't have everything. Apparently.</p>

<p>Next, something quite different. Helen played me this at a dinner party on Saturday night for the comedy value. I went looking for it on YouTube, mostly out of curiosity regarding the identity of the female singer, and found a live version. Promise me you'll listen to at least some of it, and not just hit stop as soon as the guitars start. It might make you smile.</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nAR4ieUrxUM]</p>

<p>I think I genuinely like this. It helps that I actually like ABBA. I think they wrote really good songs. I also love cross genre covers, and this is definitely that. The female singer's voice really works for me as well. I had a look for some of their other stuff, but it's really not good, not good at all. It seems they split and formed two entirely new bands, both of which are a slight improvement, though.</p>

<p>Told you I had eclectic taste. Here are a couple more for your edification:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OyZqpRxnHWg]</p>

<p>A soft one to start off with. Dido is so much better live. In my opinion her voice is perfect, but sounds overly processed on her recordings.</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YgrMfRYCRgw]</p>

<p>Bit of a heavier one, there. This is about as heavy as my taste in music gets. I love the singer's voice, though. If you're confused by this wait for the chorus. If you don't have the pertinence for that, try this one by the same band:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wAfRW_RMK4M]</p>

<p>See? The band, if you're interested, are called "In Flames". Look up a song called "Dead End" if you want to know what happens when a Swedish metal (death metal? pop metal? disco metal? death pop disco metal?) band collaborates with a Swedish pop singer song writer...</p>

<p>How about another soft one? Okay, but I'm going to get it from an unexpected place:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Waw61eE9FyY]</p>

<p>Yes, that was Slipknot. Bet you didn't see that coming.</p>

<p>I'll skew a bit heavier again, but not too far.</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hiHBiRRB1Mw]</p>

<p>I'm a little disappointed that YouTube couldn't supply "Father's Daughter" from "Like a Bolt of Lightning", but this will do.</p>

<p>I'm tempted to throw in a bit of Massive Attack, a bit of Evanescence, a bit of Killswitch Engage... but this post really could go on for ever, so I'll stop it here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
