<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Music | HarveyNick]]></title>
  <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/categories/music/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-12-27T22:32:07+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://harveynick.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eclecticism]]></title>
    <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/05/eclecticism/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-05T15:02:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/08/05/eclecticism</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seems the Facebook app does not do what it's supposed to. Never mind, I shall content myself with the (better) Wordpress interface. Maybe I'll look into writing a Facebook app which interfaces with my RSS feed. That would be cool.</p>

<p>I thought I would write a music related post, since I found a couple of things on YouTube which piqued my interest. First an entirely serious one:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vIhJC2-UNZA]</p>

<p>When I first heard this on the radio I thought it sounded so fresh they must be a new band. But no, they've been around quite a while, I even knew other songs by them. Unfortunately I don't like many of them, but you can't have everything. Apparently.</p>

<p>Next, something quite different. Helen played me this at a dinner party on Saturday night for the comedy value. I went looking for it on YouTube, mostly out of curiosity regarding the identity of the female singer, and found a live version. Promise me you'll listen to at least some of it, and not just hit stop as soon as the guitars start. It might make you smile.</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nAR4ieUrxUM]</p>

<p>I think I genuinely like this. It helps that I actually like ABBA. I think they wrote really good songs. I also love cross genre covers, and this is definitely that. The female singer's voice really works for me as well. I had a look for some of their other stuff, but it's really not good, not good at all. It seems they split and formed two entirely new bands, both of which are a slight improvement, though.</p>

<p>Told you I had eclectic taste. Here are a couple more for your edification:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OyZqpRxnHWg]</p>

<p>A soft one to start off with. Dido is so much better live. In my opinion her voice is perfect, but sounds overly processed on her recordings.</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YgrMfRYCRgw]</p>

<p>Bit of a heavier one, there. This is about as heavy as my taste in music gets. I love the singer's voice, though. If you're confused by this wait for the chorus. If you don't have the pertinence for that, try this one by the same band:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wAfRW_RMK4M]</p>

<p>See? The band, if you're interested, are called "In Flames". Look up a song called "Dead End" if you want to know what happens when a Swedish metal (death metal? pop metal? disco metal? death pop disco metal?) band collaborates with a Swedish pop singer song writer...</p>

<p>How about another soft one? Okay, but I'm going to get it from an unexpected place:</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Waw61eE9FyY]</p>

<p>Yes, that was Slipknot. Bet you didn't see that coming.</p>

<p>I'll skew a bit heavier again, but not too far.</p>

<p>[youtube=http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hiHBiRRB1Mw]</p>

<p>I'm a little disappointed that YouTube couldn't supply "Father's Daughter" from "Like a Bolt of Lightning", but this will do.</p>

<p>I'm tempted to throw in a bit of Massive Attack, a bit of Evanescence, a bit of Killswitch Engage... but this post really could go on for ever, so I'll stop it here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
