<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blogger | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/blogger/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-19T22:49:52+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wandering Around London]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/05/17/wandering-around-london/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T21:57:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/05/17/wandering-around-london</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apologies, once again, for the radio silence. Over the past couple of months there have been some complications in my private life, and a remarkable amount of my attention has been taken up with figuring out where exactly I'm going to be living after my current lease runs out (more on that later, perhaps).</p>

<p>Be that as it may, after almost a year, I did find some time to go wandering around the city I now call home. Whilst I took every opportunity to make a brisk constitutional around Edinburgh, I'd never managed to really do this in London. Part of the reason, I think, is while that you can essentially wander across central Edinburgh in an hour or two, this is really not the case in London. Nipping across town via public transport can take <em>hours</em>.</p>

<p>Recently, though, two excellent excuses presented themselves. Firstly, my father came to visit for a few days and professed an interest to go take a good look at <a href="http://www.kew.org/">Kew Gardens</a>, the Japanese themed portion in particular.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First stop was the <a href="http://www.kew.org/visit-kew-gardens/garden-attractions-A-Z/Pagoda.htm">Pagoda</a>:</p>

<p>{% img center /images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0402.jpg %}</p>

<p>This is a fairly impressive and imposing building, at least from a distance. Close up it's curiously less so. I think it's the red brick construction which does it. I've never visited Japan, but this seems a slightly inappropriate building material to me. My father, who has, concurred.</p>

<p>Next was the <a href="http://www.kew.org/visit-kew-gardens/garden-attractions-A-Z/japanese-gateway.htm">Japanese Gateway</a> which, in conjunction with the weather, gave me an excellent opportunity to try out the HDR mode on my phone's camera. Here it is without the benefit of HDR:</p>

<p>{% img center /images/blog/2012/05/17/IMG_0408.jpg %}</p>

<p>…and here it is with the HDR turned on:</p>

<p>{% img center /images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0409.jpg %}</p>

<p>I'll be listing that featuring under "worthwhile" from here on out. At this point it's probably worth confirming a slightly frustrating fact which I suspect is now true of many people: the camera on my phone has completely killed any use of my point and shoot camera. It's extremely convenient (being as I <em>always</em> have it with me) and, since my last upgrade, actually very capable. The only thing it lacks is zoom, which is a trade off I'm willing to make. If I plan on going on a serious photo taking excursion at any point in the future I may bite the bullet and pick up a decent digital SLR. The point and shoot just feels like a weird middle gear at this point.</p>

<p>Back to Kew Gardens, though. Tucked off to one side and not especially well advertised is the Bonsai house. It's small, but quite cool, and something my dad specifically wanted to see (Bonsai being a hobby of his).</p>

<p>{% img center /images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0448.jpg %}</p>

<p>{% img center /images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0450.jpg %}</p>

<p>Next, we moved away from the specifically Asian attractions and took a look in the <a href="http://www.kew.org/visit-kew-gardens/garden-attractions-A-Z/Palm-House.htm">Palm House</a>. This really is an impressive building, if uncomfortably hot and humid. Be ready to sweat, all ye who enter here. Besides the tropical plants (which I don't seem to have taken any pictures of), the green house itself has an impressive art deco* construction:</p>

<p>{% img center /images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0451.jpg %}</p>

<p>Shortly after this, we took the train from Richmond back to my flat, and I had the fun of explaining to my father the difference between underground and overground trains this far out of the centre ("you can tell that's an underground train because it says 'underground' on it…").</p>

<p>A week or two later, I professed a desire to go see <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com/post/19950925968/john-carter">John Carter</a> to friend who suggested we see it in Canary Wharf, allowing us to go wandering around the area beforehand. So we did.</p>

<p>Canary Wharf is one of the parts of London containing buildings which can legitimately be called skyscrapers (I think). I believe it's also London's financial district. Surprisingly, I actually find it a very pleasant place to be. The taller buildings make you feel as though you're walking through canyons, and the area is very clean, though not to the point of feeling antiseptic.</p>

<p>{% img center /images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0463.jpg %}</p>

<p>At the weekend it's extremely quiet without quite feeling like a ghost town and there are a surprising amount of things to find. These include a large underground mall, some very cool riverside buildings:</p>

<p>{% img center /images/blog/2012/05/17/IMG_0460.jpg %}</p>

<p>…and one or two very cool statue / landmark type things:</p>

<p>{% header_img center /images/blog/2012/05/13/IMG_0456.jpg %}</p>

<p>Interestingly, the whole area is also private property, so you might have submit to a vehicle search on the way in. Be that as may, I can recommend it as a reasonable place to wander around at the weekend.</p>

<p>Until next time...</p>

<p>* This is art deco, right?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now We're Blogging with Photos!]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/04/14/now-were-blogging-with-photos/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T10:42:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/04/14/now-were-blogging-with-photos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Fair warning: this is going to be a bit of a programming heavy blog post. It's also going to be quite Mac specific.</em></p>

<p>One of the things I wanted to change about the format of this blog was to make it more visual, specifically with pictures. This first part of this was to add pictures to the front page. There were a couple of options for doing so. I could just scan through an article, look for the first image tag and use this. Alternatively I could add a mechanism which allowed me to choose the image, in a similar manner to the way <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> allows me to choose the except which appears on the front page. I decided to go with option two.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The first part of this was to modify the image tag plug-in like so:</p>

<p>{% codeblock image_tag.rb lang:ruby %}</p>

<p>module Jekyll</p>

<p>  class ImageTag &lt; Liquid::Tag</p>

<pre><code>@img = nil
@header = "" 

def initialize(tag_name, markup, tokens)
  attributes = ['class', 'src', 'width', 'height', 'title']

  if markup =~ /(?&lt;class&gt;\S.*\s+)?(?&lt;src&gt;(?:https?:\/\/|\/|\S+\/)\S+)(?:\s+(?&lt;width&gt;\d+))?(?:\s+(?&lt;height&gt;\d+))?(?&lt;title&gt;\s+.+)?/i
    @img = attributes.reduce({}) { |img, attr| img[attr] = $~[attr].strip if $~[attr]; img }
    if /(?:"|')(?&lt;title&gt;[^"']+)?(?:"|')\s+(?:"|')(?&lt;alt&gt;[^"']+)?(?:"|')/ =~ @img['title']
      @img['title']  = title
      @img['alt']    = alt
    else
      @img['alt']    = @img['title'].gsub!(/"/, '&amp;#34;') if @img['title']
    end
    @img['class'].gsub!(/"/, '') if @img['class']
    if tag_name == "header_img"
      @header = "&lt;!-- header_img #{@img['src']} --&gt;"
    end
  end
  super
end

def render(context)
  if @img
    "&lt;img #{@img.collect {|k,v| "#{k}=\"#{v}\"" if v}.join(" ")}&gt;#{@header}"
  else
    "Error processing input, expected syntax: {% img [class name(s)] [http[s]:/]/path/to/image [width [height]] [title text | \"title text\" [\"alt text\"]] %}"
  end
end
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end</p>

<p>Liquid::Template.register_tag('img', Jekyll::ImageTag)
Liquid::Template.register_tag('header_img', Jekyll::ImageTag)</p>

<p>{% endcodeblock %}</p>

<p>This adds an <code>html</code> comment containing the image path to the page when I use <code>header_img</code> as a <a href="https://github.com/Shopify/liquid/wiki">Liquid</a> tag name rather than the original <code>img</code>. Next I need to do something with this comment. I created an additional Liquid filter which pulls the path out and replaces it with an actual image embed:</p>

<p>{% codeblock harveynick_filters.rb lang:ruby %}</p>

<p>module HarveyNickFilters</p>

<p>  # Used on the blog index to split posts on the <!--more--> marker
  def header_image(input)</p>

<pre><code>if input =~ /&lt;!-- header_img (?&lt;src&gt;(?:https?:\/\/|\/|\S+\/)\S+) --&gt;/
  "&lt;img class=\"header\" src=\"#{$~['src']}\"/&gt;"
else
  ""
end
</code></pre>

<p>  end
end</p>

<p>Liquid::Template.register_filter(HarveyNickFilters)</p>

<p>{% endcodeblock %}</p>

<p>Next I modified my theme to run this filter over the page contents just before the one which creates the except on the front page. I'll leave this as an exercise for the reader. Lastly, I needed to account for the fact that the created image could be just about any size, while I want some uniformity on the front page. Those of you playing at home will have noticed I assigned <code>header</code> as the class of the image. This allows me to control the appearance of the front page images by adding the following to the <code>sass</code> files in my theme (which are used to generate the <code>css</code>):</p>

<p>{% codeblock _styles.scss lang:scss %}</p>

<p>img {
  &amp;.header{</p>

<pre><code>float: left;
width: 250px;
max-width: 50%;
margin-right: 10px;
margin-bottom: 10px;
@media only screen and (max-width: 768px) {
  width: 50%;
  max-width: 250px;
}
@media only screen and (max-width: 400px) {
  width: 100%;
  max-width: 100%;
  margin-right: 0px;
}
</code></pre>

<p>  }
}</p>

<p>{% endcodeblock %}</p>

<p>Presto. Front page images.</p>

<p>Next, I wanted to try and make it easier to include pictures which I myself have taken with an actual camera (or, more likely, my phone). There really isn't any problem when you're linking to images elsewhere on the internet, but things can get a bit stickier when you want to include your own images on an Octopress blog. One option is to use a hosted service, like Flickr or PhotoBucket, but this only works when you have an internet connection. I really love that Octopress allows me to work on my site while offline, and I didn't want to lose this advantage when I'm posting pictures. Thus, I decided to just stick the images in my blog's images folder.</p>

<p>iPhoto is pretty great for organising and sharing photos (with supported services), but definitely doesn't make your life easy if you want to actually get at the image files themselves. That's the first problem. The second is that I also want to resize them to something reasonable for my blog. Lastly I want this to be low hassle. I came to the conclusion that an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/AppleScript">Applescript</a> is what was required, and this is what I came up with:</p>

<p>{% codeblock bloggify.script lang:applescript %}</p>

<p>set blog_path to "~/GitHub/octopress/source"
set images_path to "/images/blog/"
set blog_image_path to blog_path &amp; images_path
set max_width to 992</p>

<p>set {year:y, month:m, day:d} to (current date)
set date_string to "" &amp; y &amp; "/" &amp; two_digits(m * 1) &amp; "/" &amp; two_digits(d)
set folder_path to blog_image_path &amp; date_string &amp; "/"</p>

<p>do shell script "mkdir -p " &amp; folder_path</p>

<p>tell application "iPhoto"</p>

<pre><code>set the_photos to selection
set the_photo to item 1 of the_photos
set image_path to image path of the_photo
set image_name to name of the_photo
</code></pre>

<p>end tell</p>

<p>tell application "Image Events"</p>

<pre><code>set current_image to open image_path
set image_type to current_image's file type
set AppleScript's text item delimiters to "/"
set image_path to last item of text items of image_path
set AppleScript's text item delimiters to ""
scale current_image to size max_width
set new_image to folder_path &amp; image_path
save current_image in new_image as image_type
</code></pre>

<p>end tell</p>

<p>set the clipboard to images_path &amp; date_string &amp; "/" &amp; image_path</p>

<p>on two_digits(the_number)</p>

<pre><code>return (text -2 thru -1 of ((the_number + 100) as string))
</code></pre>

<p>end two_digits</p>

<p>{% endcodeblock %}</p>

<p>Now, Applescript the programming language is completely mental and can be a complete pain in the arse to get right, but Applescript the mechanism is spectacularly powerful. You can do some serious automation with it. This script grabs the path to the currently selected photograph in iPhoto, resizes it and copies it to a folder inside my blog, generated using today's date to avoid duplication. Lastly, it places the location of the image on the clipboard, in the form it's needed.</p>

<p>To use it, I enabled the scripts menu (it's an option in the Applescript editor) and copied the script to the iPhoto scripts folder, which will be something like <code>/Users/&lt;user&gt;/Library/Scripts/Applications/iPhoto</code>. This might be hidden by default, but you can find it via the scripts menu while in iPhoto.</p>

<p>Then, all that is required is to select a photo, trigger the script, and then hit cmd-c in the post I'm writing. Bingo!</p>

<p>After getting this working, I remembered an <a href="http://arstechnica.com/apple/guides/2011/09/tutorial-os-x-automation-with-macruby-and-the-scripting-bridge.ars/2">ArsTecnica article</a> about using <a href="http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/">Ruby</a> in place of Applescript for this purpose, so I converted the script to Ruby as an exercise. This is what I came up with:</p>

<p>{% codeblock blogify.rb lang:ruby %}</p>

<h1>!/usr/local/bin/macruby</h1>

<p>framework "ScriptingBridge"</p>

<p>blog_path = "~/GitHub/octopress/source"
images_path = "/images/blog/"
max_width = 992
convert = "/opt/local/bin/convert"</p>

<p>date_string = Time.now.strftime("%Y/%m/%d")</p>

<p>source_path = SBApplication.applicationWithBundleIdentifier("com.apple.iPhoto").selection[0].imagePath.sub(" ", "\ ")
image_name = source_path.split("/")[-1]
destination_folder = "#{blog_path}#{images_path}#{date_string}".sub(" ", "\ ")
destination_path = "#{destination_folder}/#{image_name}"</p>

<p>ensure_dir_cmd = "mkdir -p #{destination_folder}"
puts ensure_dir_cmd
system ensure_dir_cmd</p>

<p>convert_cmd = "#{convert} #{source_path} -resize #{max_width}x2000 #{destination_path}"
puts convert_cmd
system convert_cmd</p>

<p>IO.popen('pbcopy', 'w').print "#{images_path}#{date_string}/#{image_name}"</p>

<p>{% endcodeblock %}</p>

<p>Ruby is a much more sensible language, and this, to me, is a lot easier to follow. I'm fairly new to Ruby, so this might not actually be the most Ruby-ish way of doing it, mind. It should be noted that it will only work with <a href="http://www.macruby.org/">MacRuby</a>, though. You will also need <a href="http://www.imagemagick.org/script/index.php">ImageMagick</a> installed. I made this executable with a quick <code>chmod +x</code> and moved it to the iPhoto scripts folder as well, where it seems to work just fine. So now I have two options. Hopefully, someone out there finds this useful.</p>

<p>Finally, to prove it works, and because it feels a little strange to not actually have any pictures in this entry: here's a nice shot taken at Kew Gardens (which hopefully I'll talk about more later):</p>

<p>{% header_img center /images/blog/2012/04/14/IMG_0442.JPG %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New (ish) Year, New (ish) Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/03/17/new-ish-year-new-ish-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T11:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/03/17/new-ish-year-new-ish-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2011 was an interesting year for me. A lot changed. I turned 30. After 10 years of residency I moved away from Edinburgh, a city I love dearly, and took a job in London. With <a href="/blog/tags/google">Google</a>. As a result, I no longer work with <a href="/blog/tags/autonomous-underwater-vehicles">Autonomous Underwater Vehicles</a> for a living. Instead I build web services. Quite the change, I'm sure you'll agree. In the early months of the year I finally completed the corrections to my <a href="/blog/tags/phd">PhD</a>, and then in the summer: I graduated. It took 6 years (all together) but I am now Dr. Nick Johnson. I also <a href="/blog/2011/07/18/the-sound-of-one-hand-clapping/">lost my grandmother</a>, a fact which still brings me to tears on occasion.</p>

<p>In this light, the fact that I decided, towards the end of the year, to shift my blog away from <a href="http://wordpress.org">Wordpress</a> and over to its own domain barely even casts a shadow. I did, though, and as a result you're now reading these words on a site built using <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>, which is hosted at harveynick.com. As you may have noticed, all of the old posts from my <a href="http://harveynick.wordpress.com">wordpress site</a> have been ported over, minus the short film reviews, which you'll find <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com">here</a>. I'm not going to go into how I accomplished this, except to say: I did it the same way <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/2011/09/12/blogging-with-octopress/">Matt Gemmel did</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>{% pullquote %}
For the most part, this site is stock Octopress. I've played with the fonts, made the heading and background static and added a little more infrastructure (index pages for tags, embed scripts for YouTube and Vimeo videos and a couple of other bits). {"It's not finished, but it will serve well enough for me to try and start producing actual content again"}. I do want to make it a bit more visual, particularly the front page, and somehow integrate other content I produce into it. I also want to make it work a little better on mobile browsers and, lastly, make it a little bit more my own. The colours will change, and I'll try to find a background which doesn't require such a large file and isn't so closely associated with Apple.
{% endpullquote %}</p>

<p>What will I be writing about though? Well:</p>

<p>I plan to have <a href="/blog/tags/clockwork-aphid">Clockwork Aphid</a> actually doing something of use this year. I'm going to enhance the current Java version up to a point where it can generate interesting landscapes efficiently and in a parallel fashion. I'm then going to then have a crack at porting it to <a href="http://golang.org">Go</a>, which I think may turn out to be an excellent language for writing computer games.</p>

<p>I like films. Perchance you may have noticed. I may chat a bit more in depth about a couple of this year's releases. Just to pick three with a common theme off the top of my head:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>The Amazing Spider-Man</strong>. I went to a preview event for this in Leicester Square a month or two ago and was very impressed with what I saw. I'm hopeful they made a Spider-Man movie in the same way that Christopher Nolan makes Batman movies. Really really.</li>
<li><strong>The Dark Knight Rises</strong>. Speaking of which. This <em>is</em> exciting. It's the last of the trilogy. It's got a lot to live up to, especially since the last film Nolan made was <em>Inception</em>. I wouldn't bet against it, though.</li>
<li><strong>The Avengers</strong>. Now here's a film with some scope. All these characters in one film? With this cast? Written and directed by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joss_Whedon">Joss Mother Fucking* Whedon</a>? Please, please let this film live up to the frankly stupid amount of potential it has.</li>
</ul>


<p>Quite recently, at the aforementioned age of 30, I started playing Dungeons and Dragons with a selection of my colleagues. Well, we're actually playing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pathfinder_Roleplaying_Game">Pathfinder</a>, but let us not quibble about semantics. I'm having a really great time on several different levels. It's an interesting experience for someone who has played computer games for most of their life, but never dabbled in table top RPGs.</p>

<p>I mentioned before that I now have a shiny new PhD, with the letters before and after my name to prove it. I'm of the opinion that the work which led to this is quite interesting (but then I would be). It's also not completely divorced from my Clockwork Aphid project. I'm of a mind to try talking about this some, also.</p>

<p>See you when we get there.</p>

<p>* I think these are his actual middle names.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Kaiser Chiefs Do NOT Get to Say They Called This...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/14/the-kaiser-chiefs-do-not-get-to-say-they-called-this/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-14T23:32:12+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/14/the-kaiser-chiefs-do-not-get-to-say-they-called-this</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well. These are certainly interesting times to be living in London. Interesting times to be living in England full stop, in fact. In particular, I definitely picked an ideal time to move to Clapham.</p>

<p>I have a bad habit of being more or less completely oblivious to what's going on in the world, unless it happens in either the tech or movie industries. I subscribe to those blogs and news sites, but I rarely read the paper or turn on the news, so something has to land with quite a thud, more or less in my lap, for me to notice it much of the time. When a waitress walks into the restaurant in which I'm eating and announces that riots have kicked off just outside the station I arrived via around twenty minutes earlier, though, <em>that</em> is something I notice. Likewise, when I can hear the sirens from my bedroom window and see the helicopters flying overhead, I pay attention.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Politics is something I don't really talk about on this blog, and often avoid discussing in real life. Here, my passion far out ways my knowledge, and this combination amounts to quite the metaphorical JCB when it comes to digging oneself metaphorical hole. That said: I feel recent events merit some comment. Others have already done so, and with eloquence which exceeds my own. <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/uk/2011/aug/11/london-riots-davidcameron">Russell Brand</a> (yes, that Russell Brand; whom I continue to find myself impressed with as a writer, scarily enough) and <a href="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/peteroborne/100100708/the-moral-decay-of-our-society-is-as-bad-at-the-top-as-the-bottom/">Peter Oborne</a> being two who've stood out to me. Fair warning: I've read these articles and the writers' opinions have informed my own.</p>

<p>Frankly: something stinks in British society right now, and it has been ripe for quite some time. It's only that this summer has finally circulated the odour more fully. The particular element of this bouquet which stands out to me the most is entitlement. We have a whole lot of people in Britain right now who think you receive things because you're entitled to them. That you become a musician or a celebrity by appearing on a reality television show. That the world owes you and if you're not receiving then it's okay to just reach out and take. That where possible you should cheat the system and ring out every last drop that you can. Ask not what you can do for your country, but what your country can do for you.</p>

<p>Now, I've never really known hardship. Not true hardship which my grandparents would recognise it as such. I once had calluses upon my hands, but now they're soft and if I want to use the phrase "I work wi' me 'ands" I have to add "on a keyboard," sotto voce. I've been close to personally destitute more than once, but I could always have solved the problem with a phone call and an ingestion of pride. Realistically, I have no <em>real</em> first hand knowledge of just how bad it can get. Those who rioted last week, were not, for the most part, stealing food, though. They were stealing Nike trainers and 42" televisions.</p>

<p>42 inches. That's a big television. It fired off a question in my head: What is the difference between a looter who steals (say) £800 worth of television during a riot, and a <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/newstopics/mps-expenses/5330816/Sir-Gerald-Kaufmans-1800-rug-and-an-8865-claim-for-a-television-MPs-expenses.html">politician</a> who bills the state for an £8000 Bang &amp; Olufsen television?</p>

<p>I think the main difference is that the politician doesn't make you worried about your own physical safety. If you were to choose which of these two people you wished to encounter in a dark alley, you would probably choose the second. It's one hell of a lot easier to look down upon the former too, isn't it? To see their act as that of a barbarian, rather than a scampish little white collar criminal. I put it to you, though, that while there may be many deep differences between the individuals, the differences between the two specific acts in question are mostly superficial. In both cases the individual decided they were entitled to something which they had not earned, and then obtained it through the most expedient means available to them.</p>

<p>I'm not trying to excuse those who rioted or looted in any way. I don't deny that many of them may have had legitimate grounds for protest, but you kind of loose the high ground when you knock over The Car Phone Warehouse and run off with a crate of iPhones. What I'm saying is this: what we saw this month was a symptom, and what scares me the most is that I don't think we're even close to a diagnoses of the actual disease, let alone any real notion of what the cure might be.</p>

<p>One last point, and I think this is important. I think Peter Oborne got something dead wrong in the article I linked to above. Specifically, in the tittle: "The moral decay of our society is as bad at the top as the bottom," and more specifically in his use of the words "top" and "bottom".</p>

<p>"Bottom" is a dangerous word to use here. A divisive word, and the divides in our society are almost certainly part of the problem. We really need a lot more "us" and a lot less "them".</p>

<p>"Top", though, is just plain the wrong word. Britain is, on paper, a monarchy. Functionally, though, we're a parliamentary democracy. This means that our politicians are <em>not</em> above us. They are not a ruling aristocracy, regardless of what the Tories would prefer. They work for us. They are, at most, our equals.</p>

<p>If you have a comment to make, regardless of whether you agree of disagree, I encourage you to leave it below. If it's uncivil I am going to either delete it or make fun of you, though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sound of One Hand Clapping...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/07/18/the-sound-of-one-hand-clapping/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-18T20:29:21+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/07/18/the-sound-of-one-hand-clapping</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>...would make significantly more noise than I have on this blog, as of late.</p>

<p>There are a couple of reasons for this. The main one is that I don't actually have the internet in my new flat yet, and won't for another 9 days. Bloody Virgin Media. Serves me right for not going with media which has a bit more experience, I suppose. I'm writing this at work, which is something I really don't like to do, but it's very much the end of the day and I'm in late because I started late. I figure: a quick post can't hurt.</p>

<p>Another reason is that my life has been incredibly complicated for the last couple of weeks. I have been bounced around all over the place. I also missed a flight, an expensive mistake I may devote a blog entry to at some point, now that my (partially self directed) rage has subsided, since it has some comedy value.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>More importantly: my paternal grandmother died. There's really no way to sugar coat that fact. To head off inevitable questions:</p>

<p>Yes, we were close. In point of fact she basically raised me. I probably loved her more than anyone else in the entire world. I was also her only grandchild.</p>

<p>Yes, I am okay. I will be okay. I knew that day was coming. She had been ill in one form or another for basically my entire life and the years were being increasingly unkind.</p>

<p>No, that did not make it any easier. I cried for more or less the entire funeral, and I have no qualms (zero!) about broadcasting that fact over the internet. I was very glad to have my family and some close friends who knew my Nan there with me.</p>

<p>It is not my intention for this post to be macabre, though. For one thing my grandmother would not have wanted that. I mainly wanted to just check-in and indicate that this blog is still around, and more posts will be forthcoming. Especially now that: a) I have my computer back, and b) <a href="http://www.shamusyoung.com/twentysidedtale/?p=11874">Shamus Young</a> and <a href="http://www.sea-of-memes.com/">Michael Goodfellow</a> are making significantly more progress than I on their procedural generation projects. I am jealous of this.</p>

<p>I'll be back with more to say soon. Future topics of conversation will include: why I hate RyanAir, donuts, and dog food. Yes, dog food.</p>

<p>RIP Cath / Kath Johnson*</p>

<p>* Funny story about my Nan: no one is 100% sure of what her first name actually was.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
