<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Work | HarveyNick]]></title>
  <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/categories/work/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-01T14:33:09+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://harveynick.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Yvan Petillot]]></title>
    <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/09/16/being-yvan-petillot/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-16T22:19:27+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/09/16/being-yvan-petillot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So.</p>

<p>There I was, sitting across from a senior manager from Thales and two Professors, one each from Cambridge and Robert Gordon's Universities, discussing the precise definition of the term “emergent behaviour”...</p>

<p>Wait.</p>

<p>No.</p>

<p>Rewind.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Thanks to my current uncharacteristically basy schedule, I arrived late to the Forum on Unmanned Systems and Artificial Intelligence, an event designed to facilitate a high level discussion of these areas, and create the beginnings of a coherent plan for their future. In order to do this it brought together the foremost expects in the relevant fields, from both industry and academia.</p>

<p>And me.</p>

<p>Ah. No. See, there's a serious failure in continuity and a complete lack of explanation here. I am a terrible narrator (and worse still, I'm stealing Shane Black's material). Rewind <em>again</em>.</p>

<p>Actually invited to this forum were exhibits A, B and C. Namely: Doctors Yvan Petillot (Head of the Vision and Robotics course at Heriot-Watt University and SeeByte Chief Technical Officer) and Jonathan Evans (Former Head of Research a the Ocean Systems Laboratory and SeeByte Head of Engineering), and Professor David Lane (Head of Ocean Systems Laboratory and SeeByte Chief <em>Executive</em> Officer and Board Chairman).</p>

<p>Enter stage left: Exhibit D, yon plucky PhD student and sometime SeeByte “Development Engineer”, myself. Exhibits A, B and C were unable to attend for various reasons, and so Exhibit A (that's Dr Petillot for those of you not keeping track) asked me to attend in his stead, get a feel for what was going on, and fly the respective SeeByte and OSL flags. This suggestion was redoubled by Exhibit B, but never actually discussed with Exhibit C, who's inclusion in the program suggests the organisers were in some doubt regarding his attendance, or the lack thereof. This is not unusual.</p>

<p>And so, a mere 12 hours after arriving back in my beloved Edinburgh, fresh from my jaunt to Iceland (which I will write about in due course, once I can trust myself not to gush too unabashedly), I caught a plane to Bristol (it has a very impressive bridge, you know) and subsequently found myself in a room surrounded by people considerably more qualified and important than I. I'll leave it to you to make a judgement as to where on the scale between “high opinion of me” and “low opinion of this forum” the exact mark which led to this eventuality lies.</p>

<p>But what of it? I strongly suspect that I shouldn't go into much (or indeed any) detail yet, and the detail might in fact be supremely boring to the vast majority of readers. Suffice to say that it was an interesting experience, if frustrating reminiscent of the episode of The Simpsons in which the MENSA members take control of Springfield for much of its second day.</p>

<p>I found Bristol quite depressing, but for the reasoning behind that you'll have to wait until I've talked about Iceland some. For context, you see.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Well... Here I am...]]></title>
    <link href="http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/09/02/well-here-i-am/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-02T20:42:40+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://harveynick.github.com/blog/2008/09/02/well-here-i-am</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>...In Iceland!</p>

<p>I wanted to come here for a long time (this is no secret), and as the result of a highly unsubtle campaign of strategic hint dropping, here I find myself. It's not under ideal circumstances, though. I'm here for work and so I'll be spending most of my time working 12 hour days, doing fiddly embedded computer programming and ridding about in boats waiting for robots to do their thing. I'm also here with my boss (or someone far higher up the chain of command than myself, at least), and though he's a really nice guy there's always going to be a significant disconnect. He's not my first choice(s)* to share this experience with. I'd rather be here with my friends. My friends are awesome, you see.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>A particular subset of my awesome friends, appropriately: the Icelandic ones, have furnished me with a list of things I might like to see, do and eat while I'm here. It's not a challenge on the scale of "cook every single recipe in a recipe book", but it's a fun list all the same and one I plan on making an impression on. I've found a guide to Icelandic punctuation online and am even working up to actually asking for some of the foodstuffs on the list, rather than simply writing them down, pointing at them and smiling hopefully. We'll see how it goes. Hopefully it won't be a repeat of the Turkish "thank you" debacle**.</p>

<p>So far I like it here. It's pleasantly calm and quiet (except for the boy racers who just went screaming past the office). We went for Italian food last night (not my choice), but I'm hoping for something a little more geographically appropriate tonight. Perhaps I'll try puffin, it's always good to try new things. More news as I get it.</p>

<p>It might amuse some of you to know that I've typed this while my boss was out of the room, launching into a long explanation of... something.</p>

<p>More news as I get it.</p>

<p>* Why is there no legitimate plural for "first choice"? That's a linguistic deficiency, right there...</p>

<p>** It's about 20 syllables long and never elicited anything more than a blank stare from anyone we said it to.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
