<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Watch | HarveyNick]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/watch/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-10T23:38:49+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trailer Trash]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/03/15/trailer-trash/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-15T22:30:08+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/03/15/trailer-trash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every once in a while, a film trailer comes along that I can’t seem to stop myself watching repeatedly. I like trailers in general, which is definitely part of the problem, but some of them really grab hold of me. Two good examples of this are the final theatrical trailer for the recent <a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/paramount/startrek/">Star Trek reboot</a>, and one of the trailers for <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c9tnZRs4tNE">The Two Towers</a> (the one with the orchestral version of he awesome theme song from Requiem for a Dream, and words cannot express how disappointed I was when that music wasn’t in the actual film).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>You might be noticing a dramatic music related theme here, but visuals and dialogue are important too. It all has to click together. You’ve heard it said, I’m sure, that part (or even half) of the the pleasure of a present is in the unwrapping. Same thing, right here. Which brings me back to the latest object of desire I’m metaphorically tugging at the ribbon of. It’s the shiny new trailer for <a href="http://trailers.apple.com/trailers/disney/tronlegacy/">Tron Legacy</a>, long awaited sequel to the 1982 cyber cult classic. I have something of a weakness for stories which which turn computer programmers* into heroes anyway (I’m sure you couldn’t possibly imagine why), but everything in this trailer works for me. There <em>was</em> an initial warning sign, to wit: one of the principle protagonists would appear to be the son of the original hero.</p>

<p>Shit. Where have I seen that recently?</p>

<p>But wait... Maybe he’s <em>not</em> a complete tool of a character, because I absolutely love the delivery of the one line line he really gets in the trailer. Bruce Boxleitner too, returning from the original, but then I already knew he could handle a bit of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Sheridan_(Babylon_5)">gravitas</a>. After a bit of initial set up, the trailer is basically all about the visuals, and what visuals they are. For a start, one of them is a visual of the gorgeous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olivia_Wilde">Olivia Wilde</a> (13 from House). It all looks very cool and it all makes me very curious indeed. For some reason, I especially love the way the music distorts as the main title is revealed. In case you hadn’t guessed: I’m quiet excited about this one. Let me know what <em>you</em> think.</p>

<p>* Apparently, “software engineer” is the more politically correct term, but screw you, I know what I am. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
