<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Audiophile | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/audiophile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-27T15:27:48+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mercury Rising]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/09/20/mercury-rising/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-20T10:00:44+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/09/20/mercury-rising</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Monday the 5th of September was Freddie Mercury day. The day he would have turned 65, had he lived. This makes me feel a little old, but that&rsquo;s not the point. The day&rsquo;s <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KX2BQM0D01M">Google doodle</a> (pointed out to me with furious glee by one of my coworkers) led me to YouTube and numerous videos of Queen performing live. As I often do, I&rsquo;d forgotten just how good they were. I spent much of the day fighting the urge to pump my fist and throw shapes at my desk*. Since I had so much fun with this, I&rsquo;m going to pepper this post with some of the videos I found the most fun. Anything under the videos and written in italics is a comment on the video itself, and not strictly related to the rest of this post.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/LncAQR47eZo" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><em>If you have to start somewhere, you might as well start here. File under: moments which made history.</em></p>

<p>As I was walking to the cinema yesterday to see <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com/post/10360864080/tinker-tailor-soldier-spy">Tinker Tailer Soldier Spy</a>, I found myself thinking back to the Queen videos, but also to the <a href="/blog/2011/08/07/film-related-blog-post/">post</a> I previously wrote about how much I hated the last two Transformers films, and how much I adored Fast 5. I started wondering if a person&rsquo;s taste in music might be reflected in their taste in film. I have fairly eclectic fast in music. I like a bit of <em>Dido</em>, a bit of <em>Bjork</em>. I love me some <em>Avenged Sevenfold</em> and some <em>In Flames</em>. I&rsquo;m as likely to throw on a bit of <em>Massive Attack</em> as I am a bit of <em>Linkin Park</em>. Today I might be listening to <em>At The Drive-In</em>, where as on my walk yesterday my choice of backdrop was <em>Spiritual Beggars</em>. Like my mother before me, I&rsquo;m also a bit of a Queen fan.</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/oozJH6jSr2U" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><em>Obviously I have to include this one. Queen at their operatic best.</em></p>

<p>When challenged to name my favourite films, I&rsquo;ve been picking the same five for quite some time (in no particular order):</p>

<ul>
<li>Fight Club;</li>
<li>American Beauty;</li>
<li>Donnie Darko;</li>
<li>Amelie;</li>
<li>The Matrix.</li>
</ul>


<p>I might also offer up three others I really love:</p>

<ul>
<li>Out of Sight;</li>
<li>Pitch Black;</li>
<li>X-Men**.</li>
</ul>


<p>Perhaps I might also add the first <em>Pirates of the Caribbean</em> film (or maybe <em>Zoolander</em>) to that list. Be that as it may, I&rsquo;d say the list is reasonably eclectic. Not entirely evident in this list is my love of a really good action movie. <em>Bad Boys</em>. <em>The Transporter. Rambo (2008). Fast 5. Demolition Man. Army of Darkness. Welcome to the Jungle. The Long Kiss Goodnight. Die Hard.</em> I&rsquo;m not going to try and match items from my musical taste to each of the films I&rsquo;ve named here, because I don&rsquo;t think the analogy is that exact, but I think Queen serves as an excellent peer to these action films.</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/kXOOwNS2qk0" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><em>I love this intro. That is how you work a crowd.</em></p>

<p>Freddie Mercury did not so much walk around the stage as stay perfectly still at the centre of everyone&rsquo;s vision while the stage moved around him. He worked the crowd like a master while knocking every single note right out of the stadium. It wasn&rsquo;t just about him, though. The band behind him was as tight as a gnat&rsquo;s arse. Everything clicked together like the internals of a cuckoo clock. Queen songs were not generally high art, but they flowed brilliantly and they just <em>took hold</em> of you.</p>

<p>This is how a good action film should be. I want the characters to chew the scenery and have it feel right. I want the characters to be fleshed out enough to feel worthwhile. They don&rsquo;t have to be Lester Burnham or Jack Foley, but I do need to give a shit about what happens to them. The plot should feel, if not possible, then plausible. If something doesn&rsquo;t quite make sense then it should be okay because I&rsquo;m having too much fun to care. I want to laugh joyously at the outrageousness of it. I want to feel like pumping my fist along with the protagonists' success and then leave the cinema with a huge smile on my face. I&rsquo;ll listen to some Emilíana Torrini soon, there&rsquo;ll be time enough for that later. Right now, <em>we are the champions</em>, baby!</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/pCA6b36pCro" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><em>A beautiful, melancholic and very appropriate song. Seems like a good place to stop.</em></p>

<p>* For the record: conversation with my coworkers has revealed to me that had I done so, I could simply have told them I was listening to a bit of Queen and this otherwise odd behaviour would have become at least marginally understandable.</p>

<p>** Yes, the first one. It has a wonderful lightness of touch and flow, which, though it doesn&rsquo;t excuse the film&rsquo;s complete lack of a third act, does make it very dear to me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Epic Googleyep and Other Stories]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/17/epic-googleyep-and-other-stories/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-17T14:52:53+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/10/17/epic-googleyep-and-other-stories</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m currently doing some tests on a couple of different data structure implementations for Clockwork Aphid, so while they&rsquo;re running I thought I&rsquo;d a bit of time to write a music related post, since I haven&rsquo;t done one in a while. So, contained within are three music related mini posts for your viewing pleasure.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Epic Googleyep</h2>

<p>As you may or may not be aware, I spent a reasonable percentage of this year (about ten weeks) working in Australia. Some of that time was spent working offshore in <a href="http://maps.google.com.au/?ie=UTF8&amp;ll=-20.430874,116.702271&amp;spn=1.429723,1.814117&amp;z=10">this general area</a>. I spent the latter offshore time on a boat called the Unlimited (fun fact: the company which owns this boat has two others: The No Limits&hellip; and The Limitless), a 24m catamaran, whitch for much of my trip had its full crew complement of twelve. For those of you counting at home, that&rsquo;s two metres each. It was&hellip; a little cramped. It did have a reasonable common area, however, with a great big flat screen TV. Outside the harbor, TV reception was less than good, and it was fairly common that the TV would be left on in an area of good reception, only to have us drift (or actively move) into a much crappier area.</p>

<p>Such was it that I wondered into the mess when a certain music video was trying to come through from the other side. At least 50% of it was static, but what I did hear I quite liked. Much of what I actually saw consisted of a slightly emo looking guy walking through a forest towards the camera, backed by two strikingly attractive and very similar looking ladies (at the time I thought it might have been the same girl twice) in evening dresses, one black and one white. I wanted to know more, but the signal gave out completely before the song finished.</p>

<p>I did not have a lot to go on, so the next time the internet was functional, I fired up Google and brazenly typed in &ldquo;music video black dress white dress,&rdquo; and&hellip; win! I love it when that happens. Here&rsquo;s the video:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/OOfBwSYvIic" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>

<h2>You Are Speaking My Language!</h2>

<p>The title of my previous series of programming language related posts was, in case you hadn&rsquo;t guessed, a reference to this:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/srIKcXWN6F0" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Now, I love Juliette &amp; The Licks, but this really isn&rsquo;t their best song. In actual fact I find this entire album extremely disappointing (with the exception of &ldquo;I never got to tell you what I wanted to&rdquo;), where as the other two albums don&rsquo;t really have a bad song on them. The song title fit the posts quite well, however, so I didn&rsquo;t feel I could leave it out. I spent some time on YouTube trying to work out which other song of theirs I should post as well, and ended up coming to the conclusion that this was a safe bet:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/2WDcCT3YeM" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a good song and I love the video. I&rsquo;ve also seen plenty of girls walking through Edinburgh at 11am on a Saturday who looked like they might break into this at any moment.</p>

<p>As an additional note here: Juliette Lewis herself confuses the hell out of me. I don&rsquo;t find her attractive no matter how hard I try, but I do find her extremely sexy no matter how hard I try not to.</p>

<h2>Gaga For Gaga</h2>

<p>It&rsquo;s another Lady Gaga cover and I love it!</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/2ga_pr0vuHA" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>This is clearly still Lady Gaga&rsquo;s &ldquo;Bad Romance,&rdquo; but with a rock opera feel on top, which I feel works very, very well. I can imagine this version of the song sounding amazing sung by Freddie Mercury, but then I suspect that might be the case for most Lady Gaga songs (not coincidentally).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Musical Arithmetic]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/15/musical-arithmetic/"/>
    <updated>2010-08-15T12:40:46+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2010/08/15/musical-arithmetic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so here&rsquo;s the formula:</p>

<pre><code>(A - B) + C = D
</code></pre>

<p>And here are the variables:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>A = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/UZjf9C6atT4" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Evanescence. More specifically: the original line up (as far as most of the world is concerned). I like Evanescence quite a bit, but that&rsquo;s about 74.2% Amy Lee&rsquo;s voice. The girl has one hell of a pair of lungs on her. I picked this particular song from the first album for reason which may become obvious later. For what it&rsquo;s worth, I think Everybody&rsquo;s Fool and Imaginary are a much better songs.</p>

<p>B = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/bP5wmtOXCQ" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Evanescence again? No. Well&hellip; yes, but the current line up. Specifically: Amy Lee herself. I picked this song from the second album (which is much better than the first) because it seems to have the most Amy Lee-ness in it. It doesn&rsquo;t have an actual video, though, so alternatively:</p>

<p>B = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Hqd2FJF8-h8" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>I figure having a deficit of Seether won&rsquo;t affect the sum either way, so this works too.</p>

<p>C = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/dUyMvaJwACc" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Former Irish American Idol contestant* Carly Smithson. Once again: A hell of a pair of lungs. Not an entirely dissimilar look, but quite a different vocal style, it would appear. Carly&rsquo;s voice has a bit more blues in it, a bit more sultriness.</p>

<p>D = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/zzTZeeMCUBk" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><a href="http://www.wearethefallen.com/">We are the Fallen</a>, the new band from Ben Moody, two other former members of Evanescence and Carly Smithson. Can you seen why I picked that particular Evanescence song? That&rsquo;s more than a passing resemblance, style wise. There is a second reason I picked it, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kdYa0oeMLfI&amp;feature=related">however</a>. Carly has a less operatic voice, though, and a bit more range in terms of singing style. I love me some female fronted metal, so I&rsquo;ll be keeping an eye on this band.</p>

<p>Okay, here&rsquo;s another one which plays a bit better to her frankly spectacular voice:</p>

<p>D = <iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/u24NXTBHLYU" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>* That is: she&rsquo;s Irish and was a contestant on &ldquo;American Idol.&rdquo; There is no such show as &ldquo;Irish American Idol,&rdquo; so far as I&rsquo;m aware.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Serendipitous Nostalgia]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/13/serendipitous-nostalgia/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-13T23:31:13+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/01/13/serendipitous-nostalgia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I was walking home from work and absent-mindedly listening to music, when I noticed that that my supposedly shuffled iPod was displaying a definite preference for one band in particular. A band I haven&rsquo;t really spared a seconds thought in some years. As I walked I hatched a plot a write a blog post regarding the nostalgia this inspired. So I arrived home and thought to have a look on youTube for some reference material to post&hellip;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There is a reason I have a marked preference for the combination of a heavy rock music and female vocals, and her name is Aimee Echo. In the late nineties she fronted a band called Human Waste Project with vocals which managed to be both sugary sweet and ragged at the same time. My youthful self took notice. My youthful self also attended a festival called the &ldquo;Ozzfest&rdquo; with his friend Rich and said friend&rsquo;s father, where he found Human Waste Project to be a late addition to the bill. My youthful self promptly had the back of head damn near blown off by one of the best live shows he had (or was ever to) see.</p>

<p>As it turned out, that was to be their second to last show. Aimee Echo left the band, who sounded like this:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/xGLglF2MuEo" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>and formed a new one, called at first Hero and then theSTART, who sounded more like this:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/J-K64wVAn5U" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Though I like this second song, I find that the raw edge is missing from her voice. This is probably due to the more electronic sound of the new band and thus the requisite multi-tracking of a voice I don&rsquo;t feel requires it. The point is I don&rsquo;t like the second band as much, not least because this is the only song of there&rsquo;s I found which has much of a chorus.</p>

<p>So where was I&hellip; ah yes, I was searching youTube for content to post. What I found was a lot of presumably live videos. I saw one for &ldquo;Dog&rdquo;, thought &ldquo;sweet!&rdquo; and clicked. The video loaded. Aimee Echo was talking into the mike. &ldquo;So a long time ago&hellip; there was a band in the nineties&hellip; called Human Waste Project&hellip; and we are them&hellip;&rdquo;</p>

<p>Hang on&hellip; this is a new video&hellip; and then the opening riff gave me goose bumps&hellip;</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m aware the sound quality is <em>awful</em> on the video, but here it is:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/V-fFg3b76j0" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>A bit of frantic web searching promptly revealed that yes, gloriously, the band were back to together. At least to some extent. They&rsquo;d played two shows in 2008 (well&hellip; more like one and a half, since the first one was actually the encore from a theSTART show) and were rehearsing for a reunion tour.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s when things like this come together that I&rsquo;m given to smile inwardly and think that perhaps there is someone &ldquo;up there&rdquo; who likes me.</p>

<p>For what it&rsquo;s worth, another lady who had an (arguably stronger) effect on my musical taste is Sandra Nasic. So, for the sake of completeness, here&rsquo;s a couple of videos of her singing with her (now defunct) band, &ldquo;Guano Apes&rdquo;, and another of her providing guest vocals on an Apocalyptica song.</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ifASH53DNXQ" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XvfYrKo1KGs" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/wCeMJR33fkg" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Apocalyptica, in case you were wondering, are a group of Finnish &lsquo;cello players, who once exclusively played Metalica covers, but now play original material. Here&rsquo;s another one, this time with Corey Taylor:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/OCqUR_iActA" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>I think that's enough music for now. Tootles.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Flip Side]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/30/flip-side/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-30T20:54:06+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/09/30/flip-side</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two updates in one day shocker!</p>

<p>The last one was a little downcast, though, and I felt a need to pass on something awesome by way of balance. Here it is:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sxNmeMklFk8">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sxNmeMklFk8</a>" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>Perhaps you&rsquo;re thinking &ldquo;Huh? Who&rsquo;s this guy?&rdquo; or &ldquo;What&rsquo;s with the cake?&rdquo;. You&rsquo;ve been missing out if that&rsquo;s the case. Jonathan Coulton (for that is the man&rsquo;s name) is a computer programmer turned unlikely rock star (You scoff? He has a song in Rock Band. I&rsquo;m having trouble thinking of a better benchmark), who&rsquo;s become something of a geek standard thanks to the somewhat unlikely nature of his subject matter (one song has Pluto&rsquo;s moon singing its condolences regarding its loss of planet status).</p>

<p>The song itself is the song over the closing credits of the game Portal, which is, quite frankly, an absolute fucking work of art. You probably know that I&rsquo;m several different flavours of nerd and so JC&rsquo;s* stuff appeals to me on a fairly base level , but I&rsquo;m not a hardcore gamer. I have above average social skills, leave the house regularly and I prefer making love to playing computer games. There. I said it, and with a completely straight face. But that game is complete genius, through and through. I think Valve do amazing work in everything they do, and the fact they got JC* to write the song for the closing credits of one of their games makes me grin from ear to ear.</p>

<p>Check out some more of his stuff, it might make you smile. If you do and it does, leave a comment telling me about it, because that would make me smile**.</p>

<p>Update: His website is here <a href="http://www.jonathancoulton.com">http://www.jonathancoulton.com</a> And you can buy (and download for free) all his music there.<br/>
That is all.</p>

<p>* No, not <em>that</em> JC<br/>
** At the risk of me smiling so widely that the top of my head falls off.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
