<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Bibliophile | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/bibliophile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-02-18T18:21:16+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book Related Blog Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/23/book-related-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-23T10:00:02+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/23/book-related-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finally broke.</p>

<p>I’ve been saying for some time that if the Kindle, or a similarly capable eReader, went under the £100 mark I would splash out and buy one. Until quite recently I had been quite tempted, but this condition was never satisfied. Had I seen one for sale in a bricks and mortar store while I was over in the US of A, I think I probably would have just snapped it up, dollar to stirling exchange rates and relative prices being what they are. But I didn’t, so I didn’t.</p>

<p>Then, suddenly, out of the blue, I just happened to be on the Amazon Kindle page by shear chance, in no way fighting the urge to just say “sod it” and bloody well buy one, when I noticed the word “refurbished” in the pricing options. More interesting to me were the numerals to the right of the word. Eighty of your British pounds.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Snap.</p>

<p>To cut a fairly short story down to the bare minimum: I have a Kindle now. The fact that it’s refurbished doesn’t bother me in the slightest. In actual fact this would tend to mean that it has passed a more rigorous set of tests, and still has the full guarantee. Also, it was cheaper. Did I mention that?</p>

<p>So what do I think of this bit of kit? It’s very pleasing indeed, and plays very nicely with my tendency to read books which might more accurately be called “tomes”. Right now that’s George R. R. Martins long and impatiently awaited “A Dance With Dragons”, a book which, if you fell asleep whilst holding it above your face, might conceivably knock you into some sort of Inception esque deeper dream. The kindle, however, has about the size and weight of a molskine journal, making it small enough to fit into some pockets, and light enough to be carried comfortably in the hand or slung in a bag.</p>

<p>It has that slightly strange blinky page turn which is common to the current generation of eInk displays, but that doesn’t really bother me at all. At times it reminds me of shifting black and white sand, particularly when changing to and from the screen savers, which I actually find quite pleasing. I’d like it if they play this up in future versions, rather than just making the page turn quicker, but I suspect that would be a bit of a waste of resou… I mean… er… valuable functionality indicative of a mature company sure of its own capabilities and comfortable with its place in the world. It seems only right that such a company should furnish us with an eReader which acts like something straight out of the <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Diamond-Age-Neal-Stephenson/dp/0241953197/ref=ntt_at_ep_dpt_12">Diamond Age</a>, no?</p>

<p>It’s not all sweetness and light, though. I do have two significant complaints. Firstly, when you turn the device off it shifts into a randomly selected screen saver image from a pool which is preloaded on the device. This is not what I want it to do. I want it to show the cover of the book which I’m actually reading. At this point you may have figured out that my complaints are not, in fact, all that significant at all. This one does annoy me a disproportionate amount though. It just seems so obvious.</p>

<p>The second, equally earth shaking, complaint relates to the progress information along the bottom of the screen. This gives the percentage progress through the book together with a progress bar. I’m told the dots on the progress bar represent chapters, but when the book you’re reading is about a bazillion pages long this is less than helpful. Something iBooks does which I really like is tell you how many pages remain of the current chapter. If I’m reading in bed, for instance, then this is  exactly the information I’m looking for. I suspect there is a way of showing more information here, but I haven’t found it yet.</p>

<p>Something else which pushed me towards the purchase of this particular object of desire was the imminent release of new books by three of my favourite authors.</p>

<p>The first is "<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Reamde-Neal-Stephenson/dp/1848874480/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1314052707&amp;sr=8-1">Reamde</a>" by Neal Stephenson. I usually love Stephenson, and the synopsis really makes it sound as though he might be firing on all cylinders:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Across the globe, millions of computer screens flicker with the artfully coded world of T'Rain - an addictive internet role-playing game of fantasy and adventure. But backstreet hackers in China have just unleashed a contagious virus called Reamde, and as it rampages through the gaming world spreading from player to player - holding hard drives hostage in the process - the computer of one powerful and dangerous man is infected, causing the carefully mediated violence of the on-line world to spill over into reality. A fast-talking, internet-addicted mafia accountant is brutally silenced by his Russian employers, and Zula - a talented young T'Rain computer programmer - is abducted and bundled on to a private jet. As she is flown across the skies in the company of the terrified boyfriend she broke up with hours before, and a brilliant Hungarian hacker who may be her only hope, she finds herself sucked into a whirl of Chinese Secret Service agents and gun-toting American Survivalists; the Russian criminal underground and an al-Qaeda cell led by a charismatic Welshman; each a strand of a connected world that devastatingly converges in T'Rain.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Sounds insane, right? This is another monster of a book, but right now there is no Kindle edition listed, disappointingly. Still, I have my fingers crossed. The next is Terry Pratchett's latest. I hate to say it, but Pratchett's last couple of books haven't really been up to his usual standard, in my opinion. "<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Snuff-Discworld-Sir-Terry-Pratchett/dp/038561926X/ref=pd_sim_b_6">Snuff</a>" is a Vimes book, though, so I have high hopes:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>It is a truth universally acknowledged that a policeman taking a holiday would barely have had time to open his suitcase before he finds his first corpse.</p></p><p><p>And Commander Sam Vimes of the Ankh-Morpork City Watch is on holiday in the pleasant and innocent countryside, but not for him a mere body in the wardrobe. There are many, many bodies and an ancient crime more terrible than murder.</p></p><p><p>He is out of his jurisdiction, out of his depth, out of bacon sandwiches, and occasionally snookered and out of his mind, but never out of guile. Where there is a crime there must be a finding, there must be a chase and there must be a punishment.</p></p><p><p>They say that in the end all sins are forgiven.</p></p><p><p>But not quite all...</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Finally, we have "<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Manhattan-Reverse-Peter-F-Hamilton/dp/0230750303/ref=pd_sim_b_1">Manhattan in Reverse</a>", a book of short stories by Peter F. Hamilton. No one does overblown space opera quite so well as Hamilton, in my opinion, but his short stories can be a little spotty. I have no complaints about getting a bit more Paula Mayo, though, so count me in.<br/>
The fun thing, though, is that I found the second two books on the suggestions list for the first. Amazon, methinks you have a little too much the measure of me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For Boobs, Mikael?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/09/for-boobs-mikael/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T02:22:45+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/09/for-boobs-mikael</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Warning: this post contains a picture which includes boobs. Be prepared for that. If your manager is looking over your shoulder, don't click; or at least have an excuse ready. If you're offended by the sight of boobs... well... I'm sorry. But I probably don't know how to talk to you in that case, anyway. Lastly: if you're American, you're not supposed to see this, <a href="http://www.aintitcool.com/node/49952">for some reason</a>.</p>

<p>Please, use your desecration. Oh yes, and think of the children. But not while looking at the boobs. That would be strange.</p>

<p>Anyway.</p>

<p>Ready?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It's the new teaser poster for David Fincher's adaptation of Stieg Larsson's fantastic <em>The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo</em>:</p>

<p><a href="http://dragontattoo.com/"><img class="center" src="http://geektyrant.com/storage/post-images-2011/girlwithadragonTatnsfw.jpeg"></a></p>

<p>Note: I've nabbed this picture from WikiPedia. It's small so that it counts as fair use (apparently). If you click it, you'll be taken to the films official website, where you can see a bigger version, though you might have to pinky swear that you're old enough to see it. The site also has the teaser trailer, but I'll get to that.</p>

<p>Update: It seems they've taken it off the official site. You can find it at the Total Film website <a href="http://www.totalfilm.com/news/rooney-mara-goes-topless-in-girl-with-a-dragon-tattoo-poster">here</a>.</p>

<p>I like this poster quite a bit, though I am slightly confused as to whether the tag line is supposed to be:</p>

<blockquote><p>Evil shall with evil be expelled.</p></blockquote>

<p>Which kind of feels as though it needs a comma to me (though I'm not 100% certain where), or:</p>

<blockquote><p>Evil shall be expelled with evil.</p></blockquote>

<p>Which perhaps scans slightly better, but is definitely not how you would normally reads words written in that arrangement. In some ways I think I prefer the slightly more archaic feel of the first one.</p>

<p>Update 2: The version of the trailer on the official site has been updated. It's definitely the first one.</p>

<p>I <a href="http://harveynick.wordpress.com/2009/09/20/just-cant-recommend-highly-enough/">outright love</a> the book this is based on (and was confused as all hell when <a href="http://www.dougalstanton.net/blog/index.php/2010/09/02/three-books-swedish-crime-allegorical-tales-and-first-person-shooters/">Dougal didn't</a>). I did really enjoyed the original Swedish adaptation, but I have high hopes for any David Fincher film and this is no exception. I'm not thinking of it as a remake, more a reinterpretation.</p>

<p>I think Daniel Craig is really good casting for Mikael Blomkvist, and I'm pretty impressed with the way Rooney Mara is looking as Lisbeth Salander. In the books, at least, the point is made that Lisbeth would be incredibly attractive if she wasn't far, far too thin. Mission accomplished. I can't wait to hear them speaking, though it is going to be strange without the Swedish accent. Craig is uniformly fantastic, and Mara definitely held her own, and even stood out, in <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com/post/9851518911/the-social-network">The Social Network</a>.</p>

<p>What was also released recently was the teaser trailer, which looks a little bit like this:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/QrQ433ChAQM" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>This is definitely a trailer for people who've read the book, I think. I saw it in the cinema with <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com/post/9851924500/x-men-first-class">X-Men First Class</a>, and the guy sat next to me had a fairly strong negative reaction of the "what the hell was that?" variety. To me, though, it looks great. Fincher's artistry is legendary and I think this film is going to have a lot of impact. It's going to be dark, and <em>very</em> difficult to watch in places. This is a story about incredibly complex and compelling characters. This does not mean that they are nice people, and their story is a difficult one. If I had to pick a word to describe what I think this film will be like, it would be: <em>uncompromising</em>.</p>

<p>I look forward to taking my double espresso with a teaspoon of milk this Christmas, even if I do feel as though I need to take a bath afterwards.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's the Downside?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/26/whats-the-downside/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-26T21:44:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/26/whats-the-downside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm reading a Peter F Hamilton book right now. His work isn't perfect, but I like it. He achieves a fairly staggering level of scale, whilst corralling a considerable number of characters who are worth your time* and develop naturally, if exceptionally. His books are, however, frikkin' gigantic. This one is 725 pages long, and is shorter than a lot of his other work. It's not ideal for reading on journeys, and you wouldn't want to pack more than one of them for a long trip. It's also not like PFH is the only long winded author I read. See also Robyn Hobb, Neal Stephenson and Brandon Sanderson. I don't <em>only</em> read huge Sci-Fi/Fantasy epics, but I do <em>often</em> read them.</p>

<p>Additionally, I have stacks and stacks of books, even taking into account that I divested myself of a lot before leaving Edinburgh. When I move into my new flat**, I'm not sure I'm going to have space for them. If I could stop that collection growing too much, that would be ideal, but I have no plans to stop reading or buying new reading material.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>On the surface, to me at least, the ideal solution to this would be a kindle (or, I suppose, some other eBook reader). All of a sudden, Pandora's Star is now the same Size as Cat's Cradle. Crytonomicon is the same size as Memoirs of a Geisha. Plus, it doesn't matter how far I'm traveling or how little space I have, i can basically pack as many books as I'd like. Likewise, the book collections would not (physically) expand in size.</p>

<p>But what about the books I have already? Do I just keep them, rammed onto the shelf space I have? Do I instead charity shop*** them? Do I replace / duplicate some or all of them with the eBook version? There's no ideal solution here.</p>

<p>The publisher is never going to give you the eBook just because because you own the paper copy, and likewise I suspect the majority of people of aren't going to want to pay full price for an eBook they already own. Plus, books are not quite so easy to format shift as CDs.<br/>
So, here's what I propose: you take your book to a shop and pay them a nominal fee (say £1). They then give you the eBook version of your book, in the format of your choice. The book itself gets recycled. The shop and the publisher then split both the cash and the revenue from the recycling. You've format shifted your book, with only a small outlay. The publisher has benefited from this transaction. No new copies of the book have been magicked into existence (also good for the publisher). Lastly, raw material for recycled paper has been obtained. What's the downside?</p>

<p>* Well, he  does now, anyway. Much as I loved the Night's Dawn trilogy, Joshua was <em>way</em> more interesting than either the sum or the product of the rest of the characters.<br/>
** Which is in Clapham, for those of you who are playing at home. The Richmond flat was gorgeous, but size / price ratio was just too small.<br/>
*** I see no reason not to use that as a verb.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brave New Worlds]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/03/14/brave-new-worlds/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-14T22:48:18+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/03/14/brave-new-worlds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you were writing a taxonomy of stories you might choose books as a good place to start. Flicking your way through the world's libraries, time and the Dewey Decimal System would eventually bring you to the fantasy genre. There is a lot of fantasy writing out there, and you might choose to subdivide it further. A one potential way of cutting it neatly in twain is like so:</p>

<ol>
<li>Stories set in our world;</li>
<li>Stories not set in our world.</li>
</ol>


<p>Simple. Harry Potter, for instance is set in our world. That's a big part of the appeal. Likewise so are <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Neverwhere-Authors-Preferred-Neil-Gaiman/dp/0755322800/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1300142138&amp;sr=8-1">Neverwhere</a>, <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Kraken-China-Mieville/dp/0330492322/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1300142157&amp;sr=1-1">Kracken</a> (if you like'd Neverwhere, you'll want to read this), and most of Stephen King's work. Lord of the Rings is not set in our world. Simple. There are other options, of course. What about the  Chronicles of Narnia, for example (which is set in a world beyond our own)? Or Magic Bites* (which is set in an alternate version of our world)? Clearly we're looking at some shades of grey here as well, but I'm sticking the with the original idea while it still serves my purpose.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>What is my purpose here, though? Why the ramblings on this most nerdy or genres? Well, I'm thinking about procedurally generated landscapes again, you see. Clearly, if you're generating your landscape procedurally, it's going to be entirely of this world. Existing fantasy landscapes are a good place to look for ideas, then, particularly because they were designed specifically for the purpose of telling stories in.</p>

<p>The quintessential fantasy landscape is, of course, Tolkien's Middle Earth, which looks a lot like this:</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Middle-earth"><img class="center" src="http://www.alligatorstorage.co.uk/resources/Image_2<em>-</em>Map_of_Middle_Earth.jpg"></a></p>

<p>That should look vaguely familiar to anyone who's read the films or seen the books (or words to that effect). There's a definite feeling of size there. Clearly we're looking at a chunk of a continent, split into something not unlike countries. It always bothers me on maps like this, though: what about the rest of it?<br/>
There are a couple of well known knock offs of Tolkien's work out there, so why don't we consider a few of those as well? One which used to be close to my heart in my adolescent years is Games Workshop's Warhammer:</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Warhammer_Fantasy_(setting"><img class="center" src="http://www.scenicreflections.com/files/Warhammer_Map_of_the_World_Wallpaper_0495o.jpg"></a>)</p>

<p>Now, it should be quite obvious that the good chaps at GW are knocking off more than just Tolkien here. The Big G / the anthropic principle (depending on your world view) could probably claim some royalties here, because the shape of some of those continents looks very familiar. Grand Cathay, indeed. Now we appear to be looking at close to an entire planet, though, unwrapped using something not unlike the good old Mercator projection (or possibly something more politically correct). I assume so, anyway. It's entirely possible that the Warhammer world is flat.</p>

<p>Another world with more than a bit of Tolkien about it it the World of Warcraft:</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_of_Warcraft"><img class="center" src="http://world-of-warcraft-gold.com/images/worldofwarcraftmap.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Blizzard have taken no chances, though. This is a world you can actually go wandering about on, virtually speaking. They've made sure there aren't any inviting edges for you to go wandering off. If this isn't the entire of the world, it is at least self contained. That doesn't stop Blizzard causing new continents to pop to surface whenever they need to make new content, of course.</p>

<p>Okay, I'm only going to show one more, then I'll get to the actual point. This is a big one, though, so take a deep breath:</p>

<p><a href="http://shaghaghi.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/WesterosMap1.jpg"><img class="center" src="http://shaghaghi.net/wp-content/uploads/2010/11/WesterosMap1.jpg"></a></p>

<p>This is also one you might be less familiar with. If you haven't already, I heartily suggest you take a look at George R R Martin's "A Song of Fire and Ice" series, which starts with "<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Game-Thrones-Song-Fire-Book/dp/000647988X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1300142459&amp;sr=8-1">A Game of Thrones</a>," which is not coincidentally the name of the TV adaption of the books which starts on HBO quite soon. This is probably the best of the four maps I've posted here, thanks to a fairly stupid amount of detail (click on it, I dare you). This detail is evident in the books themselves (which I have to confess are not for the faint of heart) as well. This giant map actually represents only a smallish portion of the world these books are set in. It makes a good illustration though. We have mountain ranges, plains, rivers, cities, castles and so on.</p>

<p>If I'm going to procedurally generate a landscapes to tell stories in, they need to have at least a percentage of this amount of detail. Take "The Neck," the narrow portion of land around halfway up, for example. The fact that the land perceptively narrows here feeds heavily into the plot at several points in the books. This is a choke point which cuts the continent in half. Likewise, "The Eyrie" (<em>shudder</em>) is a fort sitting at the peak of a mountain range. Towns are in places that towns would be placed: bridging point on rivers, sheltered harbors, and so on.</p>

<p>The point is this: my procedurally generated landscapes will need variety, but the right kind of variety. They will need "features." That's the first major problem I'm going to need to work on once the basic engine is in place, but first I need to make a decision: should this be done top down, or bottom up? Or some combination of the two?<br/>
First, though, I need some terrain simplification and some unit tests. The unit tests I'm actually quite looking forward to doing (oddly), since I'm going to try doing them in Groovy.</p>

<p>PS I wanted to include the world from Brandon Sanderson's utterly spectacular "Mistborn" series here as well, but I couldn't find a good map online. These books are truly awesome, though. As well as been part of a series, each actually stands alone and completes it's own story, unlike the fast majority series in the fantasy genre. Seriously. <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Final-Empire-Mistborn-Book-One/dp/0575089911/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1300142644&amp;sr=1-1">Read them</a>.</p>

<p>* Confession: I enjoyed this book, even if there is a gramatical error in the first sentence. The very first sentence.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Can't Recommend Highly Enough]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/09/20/just-cant-recommend-highly-enough/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-20T18:25:45+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2009/09/20/just-cant-recommend-highly-enough</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I finished "The Girl Who Played With Fire", translated by Reg Keeland from the swedish book of the same name by Stieg Larsson. It's the sequel to 'The Girl With the Dragon Tattoo" (which is called "Men Who Hate Women" in the original swedish), and I really can't recommend the pair of them highly enough (as you might have guessed from the title of this blog post).</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I picked the first book up as the combination of the titular character being described as "an expert computer hacker" and the synopsis on the back cover put me in mind of Neil Stephenson's "Cryptonomicon", not only one of my favourite books but also an outright work of genius, in my opinion. I would describe "Cryptonomicon" as recommended reading if you're the sort of person who breaths oxygen and walks upright, if you work with computers I'd say it verges on being <em>required</em> reading. Since Stephenson lost the plot more recently (in my opinion, that is; I didn't make it more than half way through "Quicksilver" before giving up in pained frustration) there has been a rather large cyber-fiction based hole in my world. "...Dragon Tattoo" seems as though it might be poised to fill it.</p>

<p>In fact it did not. It's a different beast all together. A slow burning and wonderful one, written (and translated) with great skill and care. Both books are very powerful reads, laced with a hatred of misogyny and criticism of a system which doesn't do nearly enough to prevent it. It's also a ripping great yarn of a mystery, full of strong male <em>and</em> female characters. Nominally, the books are the first two parts of a trilogy. In fact Larsson planned ten books and left an unfinished fourth manuscript together with outlines for books five and six when he died. I'm waiting with bated breath for the release of the third book. I just hope it ties things up reasonably well and so won't leave me too curious about the contents of book I'll never be able to read.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
