<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Bibliophile | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/categories/bibliophile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-27T15:27:48+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Some Thoughts on Gamification]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/09/14/am-i-winning/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-14T16:01:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/09/14/am-i-winning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you&rsquo;re playing any sort of a game, the question &ldquo;Am I winning?&rdquo; is usually quite easy to answer. &ldquo;Is my score higher than the other guy?&rdquo; usually covers it (though if you&rsquo;re playing something like chess it might be a little more complicated than that). If you&rsquo;re playing a computer game the fact that your character is still alive may well be enough to settle this question in your favour.</p>

<p>In life, though, it is a much harder question to answer. It may well be true that, to the healthy mind, it&rsquo;s not something which should ever really matter, but <a href="http://harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/06/do-you-even-lift/">as noted before</a>, gamification works really (embarrassingly) well for me.</p>

<p>I suspect that deep down most people have their own ways of keeping score. Their bank balance. Their air miles account. How far they ran today. More abstract things, such as their perceived quality of the of the photos they took this weekend, leaning to less abstract things, actual scores, such as might be gleaned from <a href="https://www.fitocracy.com/">Fitocracy</a> or <a href="https://foursquare.com">Foursquare</a>.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>Life is not a computer game, but even so it&rsquo;s nice to have a way of tracking your progress. I&rsquo;ll say it again: gamification works really well for me. As a result, I found myself looking to games directly for inspiration. If you haven&rsquo;t picked up on this already: this is going to be quite the nerdy blog post. You have been warned.</p>

<p>In a certain kind of game, it&rsquo;s quite common to not only have a single main score (usually called something like &ldquo;experience points&rdquo;), but also a set of attributes which describe the capabilities of your character.</p>

<p>If we go right back the main influence for a lot of these sort of games (Dungeons and Dragons, though I&rsquo;ll be drawing from <a href="http://paizo.com/pathfinder">Pathfinder</a>, a alternative modern implementation) we find six main attributes:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Strength</em> measures muscle and physical power;</li>
<li><em>Dexterity</em> measures agility, reflexes, and balance;</li>
<li><em>Constitution</em> represents your character&rsquo;s health and stamina;</li>
<li><em>Intelligence</em>  determines how well your character learns and reasons;</li>
<li><em>Wisdom</em> describes a character&rsquo;s willpower, common sense, awareness, and intuition;</li>
<li><em>Charisma</em> measures a character&rsquo;s personality, personal magnetism, ability to lead, and appearance.</li>
</ul>


<p>In Pathfinder you have a score for each of these values, with a (theoretical) maximum of 18, though anything less than 10 is considered very bad. For all intents and purposes your character is born with these scores, chosen semi-randomly using dice, and has very little in the way of opportunity for improving them directly.</p>

<p>Tangent: that last part has always annoyed me. In <em>D&amp;D</em> and <em>Pathfinder</em>, doing (for example) strength based activities has no effect on your strength score, and increases in strength have no connection to strength based activities your character may have performed.</p>

<p>That aside, I think these are actually quite good metrics for a person to use when measuring their personal development (or less marketing speak-ey words to that effect). Here are some more buzz words for you (and the Google crawlers): personal analytics, the quantified self. The question then becomes one of measurement.</p>

<h3>Strength</h3>

<p>Strength would appear to be the easier to measure directly (and the ones which ties in most easily with many of my other posts). Basically: how much can you lift? We&rsquo;re looking for a single normalised value here, though, not a collection of eight absolute ones (4 &ldquo;primary&rdquo; barbell lifts * 2 (weight + repetitions)).</p>

<p>We can transform the eight values into four quite simply using a technique similar to that employed by <a href="http://www.strstd.com/">Strength Standards</a> to turn a weight and number of reps into a single theoretical &ldquo;one rep max&rdquo;. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One-repetition_maximum#Calculating_approximate_1RM">Wikipedia provides</a> a wealth of formulas for calculating this.</p>

<p>So far so good, but we still have four numbers when we need one. Adding them together won&rsquo;t help, since this doesn&rsquo;t take the weight of the individual performing the lifts into account and also assumes that all four values have the same scale. This is categorically not the case. My dead lift max is almost three times that of my shoulder press, but the latter is no less important than the former. Normalisation is required.</p>

<p>The other trick Strength Standards performs is to plot your theoretical one rep max on a scale which starts at &ldquo;untrained&rdquo; and tops out at &ldquo;elite&rdquo; (which roughly translates to &ldquo;Olympic Athlete&rdquo;), with values selected by weight. These also happen to be not unlike those (reluctantly) <a href="http://startingstrength.com/files/standards.pdf">laid out by Mark Riptoe</a>.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s the key here, I think. If we make &ldquo;untrained&rdquo;/&ldquo;Cat. I&rdquo; a 10 and &ldquo;elite&rdquo;/&ldquo;Cat. V&rdquo; an 18 we end up with four normalised values. Average these and: boom. We have our score for strength, I think.</p>

<p>This doesn&rsquo;t completely prevent a decent squat from compensating for a terrible bench press (like in my case), but it does mitigate the effect somewhat. That said: I am prepared to admit that a more fair measure might cap the total at some value measured from the weakest of the four. We&rsquo;ll see. Also, the rate at which this should decay presents an additional complication here, for reasons I&rsquo;m not going to go into, but might in another post.</p>

<p>The other five values are not as easy as all that. Rather than actually get into the nitty gritty of those here, I&rsquo;ll instead discuss what I think if the right approach and possibly revisit them later.</p>

<h3>Dexterity</h3>

<p>Dexterity, I have to confess, has me almost completely flummoxed. How do you measure agility or aim in a way which can actually be reflected in everyday life? If you&rsquo;re a member of a gun or archery club, then problem solved. Maybe. Otherwise I&rsquo;m not so sure. Likewise, if you study a martial art I think that probably counts as &ldquo;Dexterity"… but how do you compare <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kendo">Kendo</a> to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Krav_Maga">Krav Maga</a>?</p>

<h3>Constitution</h3>

<p>Constitution would appear to be a little more straightforward. This is a measure of what your body can take. Have far can you run, cycle or swim? How long does it take you? How many press/chin/pull ups can you do (maybe)? Perhaps even steps taken (I&rsquo;m looking at you <a href="http://www.fitbit.com/uk">Fitbit</a> / <a href="https://jawbone.com/up">Jawbone Up</a> / <a href="http://www.nike.com/cdp/fuelband/us/en_us/">Nike+ Fuelband</a> / <a href="http://www.withings.com/en/pulse">Withings Pulse</a>)? What I don&rsquo;t have yet is the metric to fuse this all together.</p>

<h3>Intelligence</h3>

<p>There is, of course, a fairly standard method of measuring intelligence. Dropping in &ldquo;IQ test&rdquo; here and saying &ldquo;job done,&rdquo; would definitely be the simplest solution. For an alternative proposal, though, I will defer to a good friend of mine. Tyrion Lannister.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>“My brother has his sword, King Robert has his warhammer and I have my mind… and a mind needs books as a sword needs a whetstone if it is to keep its edge.”</p><footer><strong>Tyrion Lannister</strong> <cite>George R.R. Martin&rsquo;s a Game of Thrones</cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>So then, perhaps this measure could actually relate to rate of reading. Whether this should be measured in terms of books, pages or words I&rsquo;m not sure yet. These get increasingly accurate… and increasingly faffy* to measure. Another thing to consider is whether all books are created equal. I don&rsquo;t want to get (too) pretentious here, but I&rsquo;m inclined to consider some books… more beneficial to improving one&rsquo;s mind than others. Yes, I enjoyed the hell out of the Da Vinci Code, and I don&rsquo;t care who knows it, but I was (if anything) less intelligent after I finished reading it.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s also not clear to me whether this category should include consumption of movies. What about plays? Magazines? Articles on the Web? Perhaps even TV shows (Breaking Bad <em>yes</em>, X Factor <em>no</em>)?</p>

<h3>Wisdom</h3>

<p>Wisdom is quite nebulous as presented here. The willpower part of it would tend suggest some sort of measure of personal discipline. How well you keep to your diet, how consistently you exercise (perhaps this category is where the step trackers fit).</p>

<p>For me, though, wisdom suggests experience and I&rsquo;m inclined to connect that to travel. On the wall of my flat is a map with pins pushed in for each of the countries (or cities in the case of the big ones) I&rsquo;ve visited. This is the sort of thing I&rsquo;m thinking of. Pins on a map. Stamps in a passport. These are a bit on the analogue side though, and this is the digital age, baby. Besides, EU countries don&rsquo;t stamp my bloody passport anymore. I&rsquo;m inclined to point towards services such as <a href="https://foursquare.com">Foursquare</a> and <a href="http://en.fogofworld.com/">Fog of World</a> when it comes to measuring things like this.</p>

<p>The former divvies everything up nicely and gives you lots of other ways of measuring experience (&ldquo;Your first Korean Restaurant!&rdquo;), while the latter gives you an actual percentage of the world which you&rsquo;ve explored. Obviously this only works if you keep the app running (so say goodbye to your battery life) or manually input tracks from an external GPS (faff!), and is also guaranteed to be a distressingly small number which grows at an almost imperceptible rate.</p>

<p>Again, there is a ghost of the potential for a metric here.</p>

<h3>Charisma</h3>

<p>Charisma is similarly nebulous. I refuse to declare this a measure of how sexy a person is. A don&rsquo;t even know how we would go about measuring that anyway (selfies placed on Hot or Not?** Maybe not…). Instead I&rsquo;d be inclined to make it a counterpart to intelligence, in a similar way that strength is essentially a counterpart to constitution: The first a measure of what you put out, the second a measure of what you take in… and my suggestion for intelligence was a measure of the creative work a person takes in.</p>

<p>So then: I suggest a measure of charisma related to a person&rsquo;s creative output. Words written. Content produced and published. This could be in terms of your blog, the novel you&rsquo;ve been working on or that personal coding project. An additional measure for this could be how much others actually engage with the content you produce. In the case of anything web based <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google Analytics</a> (and similar) make a good way of measuring this, I think. The others would be somewhat harder to measure directly.</p>

<h3>Lastly</h3>

<p>Something you might have noticed here: that first one was quite easy to map onto the Dungeons and Dragons 0-18 scale; the others  not so much. They&rsquo;re much harder to calibrate and, in some cases, quantify. Some might only work as qualitative measures, in fact.</p>

<p>But then, as you might have guessed, I&rsquo;m really thinking out loud here. These ideas are only half baked, but who doesn&rsquo;t love the smell of half finished baking?</p>

<br/>


<p>* Perhaps you need to Google this word. Know this: <a href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=faffy">Urban Dictionary</a> is wrong on every count, at least for the meaning I&rsquo;m assigning to it. <a href="http://www.collinsdictionary.com/submission/2/faffy">Collins Online Dictionary</a> gets it spot on.</p>

<p>** News Flash! <a href="http://hotornot.com/">Hot or Not</a> is still a thing!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Wheel Weaves as the Wheel Wills]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/05/the-wheel-weaves-as-the-wheel-wills/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-05T15:53:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2013/05/05/the-wheel-weaves-as-the-wheel-wills</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On what was, all things considered, otherwise a fairly shitty day, I finished reading A Memory of Light, the final volume of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wheel_of_Time">The Wheel of Time</a>. This is, if you don&rsquo;t know, a fourteen book epic fantasy series whose author died prior to its completion. Each of these books is, by itself, around the size of the entire Lord of the Rings trilogy. One or two of them are really very dry, and finishing them comes dangerously close to feeling like work.</p>

<p>So do I recommend that you set out on this 12 thousand page, 4 million word journey? Emphatically yes.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>I should probably admit up front that I only really set out to read the series because knew it was being completed, after Robert Jordan&rsquo;s death, by Brandon Sanderson, whom I think I may have mentioned being <a href="blog/2011/03/14/brave-new-worlds/">a bit of a fan of</a> in the past. The books are quite intimidating, to say the least, and do have a (well deserved) reputation for being quite meandering and (in places) slow.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/0/00/WoT01_TheEyeOfTheWorld.jpg">http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/0/00/WoT01_TheEyeOfTheWorld.jpg</a>"></p>

<p>What they also have, though, is a truly excellent set of characters and an incredibly detailed and epic world. This is, essentially, the story of five country bumpkins who leave their small village in fear of their lives, and slowly accept the mantle of legendary heroes which is placed upon their unwilling shoulders. There are many, many other characters, but everything for the most part revolves around these five. A don&rsquo;t want to say too much about them specifically, because I don&rsquo;t want to spoil anything, but I will say this: the character I started off liking the least ended up being my absolute favourite. There are some excellent character arcs here.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s also the story of a world which was once a utopia, but was (literally) broken due to the actions of those striving for more power. A world filled with magic and wonder… but also bone chilling evil. A world on the brink of destruction, where magic is a path to madness and death for any man who wields it, while female magic users (channellers) are both feared and respected.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s not a perfect series by any means. A couple of the books towards the middle are particularly slow and uneventful. It&rsquo;s also not a series which coddles you. The actual events of the prologue, which begins just as the greatest hero of the last age has succumbed to his madness* and unwittingly killed everyone he loves, are not fully illuminated until something like the sixth book. It&rsquo;s also quite jarring when Brandon Sanderson takes over the reins of the series in book 12. The voice of the characters changes subtly, but noticeably.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/0/06/TheGatheringStormUSCover.jpg">http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/0/06/TheGatheringStormUSCover.jpg</a>" title="center" ></p>

<p>When one side of the seesaw goes down, the other rises, however. Sanderson writes action better than just about any other author I&rsquo;ve ever read and the finale <em>really</em> doesn&rsquo;t disappoint. A lot of plot threads are woven together and the series many, many characters are mostly given satisfying conclusions (even if that conclusion is sometimes &ldquo;No! Why did they have to die!?&rdquo;). Sanderson also understands &ldquo;awesome moments&rdquo;, and there was much in the last three books which left me grinning from ear to ear.</p>

<p>Actually that&rsquo;s not entirely true, one thing does disappoint: I want more. I want to know what happens to these characters next, and there aren&rsquo;t too many higher recommendations than that. I&rsquo;m very glad I took the time to read this series, and would do so again.</p>

<center>
<img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/2/27/A_Memory_of_Light_cover.jpg"><!-- header_img http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/2/27/A_Memory_of_Light_cover.jpg -->
</center>


<p>* Possibly a minor spoiler: The madness is a result of his own actions. He saved the world, but imperfectly, and in the process damned all male magic users, including himself, to this fate. He&rsquo;s an incredibly tragic character, is Lews Therin Telamon. The once saviour of the world, but one who has been remembered for thousands of years only as &ldquo;Lews Therin Kin Slayer&rdquo;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book Related Blog Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/23/book-related-blog-post/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-23T10:00:02+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/08/23/book-related-blog-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finally broke.</p>

<p>I’ve been saying for some time that if the Kindle, or a similarly capable eReader, went under the £100 mark I would splash out and buy one. Until quite recently I had been quite tempted, but this condition was never satisfied. Had I seen one for sale in a bricks and mortar store while I was over in the US of A, I think I probably would have just snapped it up, dollar to stirling exchange rates and relative prices being what they are. But I didn’t, so I didn’t.</p>

<p>Then, suddenly, out of the blue, I just happened to be on the Amazon Kindle page by shear chance, in no way fighting the urge to just say “sod it” and bloody well buy one, when I noticed the word “refurbished” in the pricing options. More interesting to me were the numerals to the right of the word. Eighty of your British pounds.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Snap.</p>

<p>To cut a fairly short story down to the bare minimum: I have a Kindle now. The fact that it’s refurbished doesn’t bother me in the slightest. In actual fact this would tend to mean that it has passed a more rigorous set of tests, and still has the full guarantee. Also, it was cheaper. Did I mention that?</p>

<p>So what do I think of this bit of kit? It’s very pleasing indeed, and plays very nicely with my tendency to read books which might more accurately be called “tomes”. Right now that’s George R. R. Martins long and impatiently awaited “A Dance With Dragons”, a book which, if you fell asleep whilst holding it above your face, might conceivably knock you into some sort of Inception esque deeper dream. The kindle, however, has about the size and weight of a molskine journal, making it small enough to fit into some pockets, and light enough to be carried comfortably in the hand or slung in a bag.</p>

<p>It has that slightly strange blinky page turn which is common to the current generation of eInk displays, but that doesn’t really bother me at all. At times it reminds me of shifting black and white sand, particularly when changing to and from the screen savers, which I actually find quite pleasing. I’d like it if they play this up in future versions, rather than just making the page turn quicker, but I suspect that would be a bit of a waste of resou… I mean… er… valuable functionality indicative of a mature company sure of its own capabilities and comfortable with its place in the world. It seems only right that such a company should furnish us with an eReader which acts like something straight out of the <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Diamond-Age-Neal-Stephenson/dp/0241953197/ref=ntt_at_ep_dpt_12">Diamond Age</a>, no?</p>

<p>It’s not all sweetness and light, though. I do have two significant complaints. Firstly, when you turn the device off it shifts into a randomly selected screen saver image from a pool which is preloaded on the device. This is not what I want it to do. I want it to show the cover of the book which I’m actually reading. At this point you may have figured out that my complaints are not, in fact, all that significant at all. This one does annoy me a disproportionate amount though. It just seems so obvious.</p>

<p>The second, equally earth shaking, complaint relates to the progress information along the bottom of the screen. This gives the percentage progress through the book together with a progress bar. I’m told the dots on the progress bar represent chapters, but when the book you’re reading is about a bazillion pages long this is less than helpful. Something iBooks does which I really like is tell you how many pages remain of the current chapter. If I’m reading in bed, for instance, then this is  exactly the information I’m looking for. I suspect there is a way of showing more information here, but I haven’t found it yet.</p>

<p>Something else which pushed me towards the purchase of this particular object of desire was the imminent release of new books by three of my favourite authors.</p>

<p>The first is &ldquo;<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Reamde-Neal-Stephenson/dp/1848874480/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1314052707&amp;sr=8-1">Reamde</a>&rdquo; by Neal Stephenson. I usually love Stephenson, and the synopsis really makes it sound as though he might be firing on all cylinders:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Across the globe, millions of computer screens flicker with the artfully coded world of T'Rain &ndash; an addictive internet role-playing game of fantasy and adventure. But backstreet hackers in China have just unleashed a contagious virus called Reamde, and as it rampages through the gaming world spreading from player to player &ndash; holding hard drives hostage in the process &ndash; the computer of one powerful and dangerous man is infected, causing the carefully mediated violence of the on-line world to spill over into reality. A fast-talking, internet-addicted mafia accountant is brutally silenced by his Russian employers, and Zula &ndash; a talented young T'Rain computer programmer &ndash; is abducted and bundled on to a private jet. As she is flown across the skies in the company of the terrified boyfriend she broke up with hours before, and a brilliant Hungarian hacker who may be her only hope, she finds herself sucked into a whirl of Chinese Secret Service agents and gun-toting American Survivalists; the Russian criminal underground and an al-Qaeda cell led by a charismatic Welshman; each a strand of a connected world that devastatingly converges in T'Rain.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Sounds insane, right? This is another monster of a book, but right now there is no Kindle edition listed, disappointingly. Still, I have my fingers crossed. The next is Terry Pratchett&rsquo;s latest. I hate to say it, but Pratchett&rsquo;s last couple of books haven&rsquo;t really been up to his usual standard, in my opinion. &ldquo;<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Snuff-Discworld-Sir-Terry-Pratchett/dp/038561926X/ref=pd_sim_b_6">Snuff</a>&rdquo; is a Vimes book, though, so I have high hopes:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>It is a truth universally acknowledged that a policeman taking a holiday would barely have had time to open his suitcase before he finds his first corpse.</p></p><p><p>And Commander Sam Vimes of the Ankh-Morpork City Watch is on holiday in the pleasant and innocent countryside, but not for him a mere body in the wardrobe. There are many, many bodies and an ancient crime more terrible than murder.</p></p><p><p>He is out of his jurisdiction, out of his depth, out of bacon sandwiches, and occasionally snookered and out of his mind, but never out of guile. Where there is a crime there must be a finding, there must be a chase and there must be a punishment.</p></p><p><p>They say that in the end all sins are forgiven.</p></p><p><p>But not quite all&hellip;</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Finally, we have &ldquo;<a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Manhattan-Reverse-Peter-F-Hamilton/dp/0230750303/ref=pd_sim_b_1">Manhattan in Reverse</a>&rdquo;, a book of short stories by Peter F. Hamilton. No one does overblown space opera quite so well as Hamilton, in my opinion, but his short stories can be a little spotty. I have no complaints about getting a bit more Paula Mayo, though, so count me in.<br/>
The fun thing, though, is that I found the second two books on the suggestions list for the first. Amazon, methinks you have a little too much the measure of me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For Boobs, Mikael?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/09/for-boobs-mikael/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-09T02:22:45+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/06/09/for-boobs-mikael</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Warning: this post contains a picture which includes boobs. Be prepared for that. If your manager is looking over your shoulder, don&rsquo;t click; or at least have an excuse ready. If you&rsquo;re offended by the sight of boobs&hellip; well&hellip; I&rsquo;m sorry. But I probably don&rsquo;t know how to talk to you in that case, anyway. Lastly: if you&rsquo;re American, you&rsquo;re not supposed to see this, <a href="http://www.aintitcool.com/node/49952">for some reason</a>.</p>

<p>Please, use your desecration. Oh yes, and think of the children. But not while looking at the boobs. That would be strange.</p>

<p>Anyway.</p>

<p>Ready?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It&rsquo;s the new teaser poster for David Fincher&rsquo;s adaptation of Stieg Larsson&rsquo;s fantastic <em>The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo</em>:</p>

<p><a href="http://dragontattoo.com/"><img class="center" src="http://geektyrant.com/storage/post-images-2011/girlwithadragonTatnsfw.jpeg"></a></p>

<p>Note: I&rsquo;ve nabbed this picture from WikiPedia. It&rsquo;s small so that it counts as fair use (apparently). If you click it, you&rsquo;ll be taken to the films official website, where you can see a bigger version, though you might have to pinky swear that you&rsquo;re old enough to see it. The site also has the teaser trailer, but I&rsquo;ll get to that.</p>

<p>Update: It seems they&rsquo;ve taken it off the official site. You can find it at the Total Film website <a href="http://www.totalfilm.com/news/rooney-mara-goes-topless-in-girl-with-a-dragon-tattoo-poster">here</a>.</p>

<p>I like this poster quite a bit, though I am slightly confused as to whether the tag line is supposed to be:</p>

<blockquote><p>Evil shall with evil be expelled.</p></blockquote>

<p>Which kind of feels as though it needs a comma to me (though I&rsquo;m not 100% certain where), or:</p>

<blockquote><p>Evil shall be expelled with evil.</p></blockquote>

<p>Which perhaps scans slightly better, but is definitely not how you would normally reads words written in that arrangement. In some ways I think I prefer the slightly more archaic feel of the first one.</p>

<p>Update 2: The version of the trailer on the official site has been updated. It&rsquo;s definitely the first one.</p>

<p>I <a href="http://harveynick.wordpress.com/2009/09/20/just-cant-recommend-highly-enough/">outright love</a> the book this is based on (and was confused as all hell when <a href="http://www.dougalstanton.net/blog/index.php/2010/09/02/three-books-swedish-crime-allegorical-tales-and-first-person-shooters/">Dougal didn&rsquo;t</a>). I did really enjoyed the original Swedish adaptation, but I have high hopes for any David Fincher film and this is no exception. I&rsquo;m not thinking of it as a remake, more a reinterpretation.</p>

<p>I think Daniel Craig is really good casting for Mikael Blomkvist, and I&rsquo;m pretty impressed with the way Rooney Mara is looking as Lisbeth Salander. In the books, at least, the point is made that Lisbeth would be incredibly attractive if she wasn&rsquo;t far, far too thin. Mission accomplished. I can&rsquo;t wait to hear them speaking, though it is going to be strange without the Swedish accent. Craig is uniformly fantastic, and Mara definitely held her own, and even stood out, in <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com/post/9851518911/the-social-network">The Social Network</a>.</p>

<p>What was also released recently was the teaser trailer, which looks a little bit like this:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/QrQ433ChAQM" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>This is definitely a trailer for people who&rsquo;ve read the book, I think. I saw it in the cinema with <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com/post/9851924500/x-men-first-class">X-Men First Class</a>, and the guy sat next to me had a fairly strong negative reaction of the &ldquo;what the hell was that?&rdquo; variety. To me, though, it looks great. Fincher&rsquo;s artistry is legendary and I think this film is going to have a lot of impact. It&rsquo;s going to be dark, and <em>very</em> difficult to watch in places. This is a story about incredibly complex and compelling characters. This does not mean that they are nice people, and their story is a difficult one. If I had to pick a word to describe what I think this film will be like, it would be: <em>uncompromising</em>.</p>

<p>I look forward to taking my double espresso with a teaspoon of milk this Christmas, even if I do feel as though I need to take a bath afterwards.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's the Downside?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/26/whats-the-downside/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-26T21:44:42+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/05/26/whats-the-downside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m reading a Peter F Hamilton book right now. His work isn&rsquo;t perfect, but I like it. He achieves a fairly staggering level of scale, whilst corralling a considerable number of characters who are worth your time* and develop naturally, if exceptionally. His books are, however, frikkin' gigantic. This one is 725 pages long, and is shorter than a lot of his other work. It&rsquo;s not ideal for reading on journeys, and you wouldn&rsquo;t want to pack more than one of them for a long trip. It&rsquo;s also not like PFH is the only long winded author I read. See also Robyn Hobb, Neal Stephenson and Brandon Sanderson. I don't <em>only</em> read huge Sci-Fi/Fantasy epics, but I do <em>often</em> read them.</p>

<p>Additionally, I have stacks and stacks of books, even taking into account that I divested myself of a lot before leaving Edinburgh. When I move into my new flat**, I&rsquo;m not sure I&rsquo;m going to have space for them. If I could stop that collection growing too much, that would be ideal, but I have no plans to stop reading or buying new reading material.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>On the surface, to me at least, the ideal solution to this would be a kindle (or, I suppose, some other eBook reader). All of a sudden, Pandora&rsquo;s Star is now the same Size as Cat&rsquo;s Cradle. Crytonomicon is the same size as Memoirs of a Geisha. Plus, it doesn&rsquo;t matter how far I&rsquo;m traveling or how little space I have, i can basically pack as many books as I&rsquo;d like. Likewise, the book collections would not (physically) expand in size.</p>

<p>But what about the books I have already? Do I just keep them, rammed onto the shelf space I have? Do I instead charity shop*** them? Do I replace / duplicate some or all of them with the eBook version? There&rsquo;s no ideal solution here.</p>

<p>The publisher is never going to give you the eBook just because because you own the paper copy, and likewise I suspect the majority of people of aren&rsquo;t going to want to pay full price for an eBook they already own. Plus, books are not quite so easy to format shift as CDs.<br/>
So, here&rsquo;s what I propose: you take your book to a shop and pay them a nominal fee (say £1). They then give you the eBook version of your book, in the format of your choice. The book itself gets recycled. The shop and the publisher then split both the cash and the revenue from the recycling. You&rsquo;ve format shifted your book, with only a small outlay. The publisher has benefited from this transaction. No new copies of the book have been magicked into existence (also good for the publisher). Lastly, raw material for recycled paper has been obtained. What&rsquo;s the downside?</p>

<p>* Well, he  does now, anyway. Much as I loved the Night&rsquo;s Dawn trilogy, Joshua was <em>way</em> more interesting than either the sum or the product of the rest of the characters.<br/>
** Which is in Clapham, for those of you who are playing at home. The Richmond flat was gorgeous, but size / price ratio was just too small.<br/>
*** I see no reason not to use that as a verb.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
