<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: octopress | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/tags/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-16T18:09:26+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New (ish) Year, New (ish) Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/03/17/new-ish-year-new-ish-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T11:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2012/03/17/new-ish-year-new-ish-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2011 was an interesting year for me. A lot changed. I turned 30. After 10 years of residency I moved away from Edinburgh, a city I love dearly, and took a job in London. With <a href="/blog/tags/google">Google</a>. As a result, I no longer work with <a href="/blog/tags/autonomous-underwater-vehicles">Autonomous Underwater Vehicles</a> for a living. Instead I build web services. Quite the change, I'm sure you'll agree. In the early months of the year I finally completed the corrections to my <a href="/blog/tags/phd">PhD</a>, and then in the summer: I graduated. It took 6 years (all together) but I am now Dr. Nick Johnson. I also <a href="/blog/2011/07/18/the-sound-of-one-hand-clapping/">lost my grandmother</a>, a fact which still brings me to tears on occasion.</p>

<p>In this light, the fact that I decided, towards the end of the year, to shift my blog away from <a href="http://wordpress.org">Wordpress</a> and over to its own domain barely even casts a shadow. I did, though, and as a result you're now reading these words on a site built using <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>, which is hosted at harveynick.com. As you may have noticed, all of the old posts from my <a href="http://harveynick.wordpress.com">wordpress site</a> have been ported over, minus the short film reviews, which you'll find <a href="http://ohsohumbleopinion.tumblr.com">here</a>. I'm not going to go into how I accomplished this, except to say: I did it the same way <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/2011/09/12/blogging-with-octopress/">Matt Gemmel did</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='It&#8217;s not finished, but it will serve well enough for me to try and start producing actual content again'>
For the most part, this site is stock Octopress. I've played with the fonts, made the heading and background static and added a little more infrastructure (index pages for tags, embed scripts for YouTube and Vimeo videos and a couple of other bits). It's not finished, but it will serve well enough for me to try and start producing actual content again. I do want to make it a bit more visual, particularly the front page, and somehow integrate other content I produce into it. I also want to make it work a little better on mobile browsers and, lastly, make it a little bit more my own. The colours will change, and I'll try to find a background which doesn't require such a large file and isn't so closely associated with Apple.
</span></p>

<p>What will I be writing about though? Well:</p>

<p>I plan to have <a href="/blog/tags/clockwork-aphid">Clockwork Aphid</a> actually doing something of use this year. I'm going to enhance the current Java version up to a point where it can generate interesting landscapes efficiently and in a parallel fashion. I'm then going to then have a crack at porting it to <a href="http://golang.org">Go</a>, which I think may turn out to be an excellent language for writing computer games.</p>

<p>I like films. Perchance you may have noticed. I may chat a bit more in depth about a couple of this year's releases. Just to pick three with a common theme off the top of my head:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>The Amazing Spider-Man</strong>. I went to a preview event for this in Leicester Square a month or two ago and was very impressed with what I saw. I'm hopeful they made a Spider-Man movie in the same way that Christopher Nolan makes Batman movies. Really really.</li>
<li><strong>The Dark Knight Rises</strong>. Speaking of which. This <em>is</em> exciting. It's the last of the trilogy. It's got a lot to live up to, especially since the last film Nolan made was <em>Inception</em>. I wouldn't bet against it, though.</li>
<li><strong>The Avengers</strong>. Now here's a film with some scope. All these characters in one film? With this cast? Written and directed by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joss_Whedon">Joss Mother Fucking* Whedon</a>? Please, please let this film live up to the frankly stupid amount of potential it has.</li>
</ul>


<p>Quite recently, at the aforementioned age of 30, I started playing Dungeons and Dragons with a selection of my colleagues. Well, we're actually playing <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pathfinder_Roleplaying_Game">Pathfinder</a>, but let us not quibble about semantics. I'm having a really great time on several different levels. It's an interesting experience for someone who has played computer games for most of their life, but never dabbled in table top RPGs.</p>

<p>I mentioned before that I now have a shiny new PhD, with the letters before and after my name to prove it. I'm of the opinion that the work which led to this is quite interesting (but then I would be). It's also not completely divorced from my Clockwork Aphid project. I'm of a mind to try talking about this some, also.</p>

<p>See you when we get there.</p>

<p>* I think these are his actual middle names.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
