<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: Spider-Man | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/tags/spider-man/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-13T00:10:19+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spins a Webb, any size...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/01/21/spins-a-webb-any-size/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-21T09:15:15+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2011/01/21/spins-a-webb-any-size</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay, so there has been a shameful lack of posts here in recent weeks, and for that I apologise. I've had some stuff going on in both my personal and professional lives, and so this blog has really been put on the back burner. I swear to you that there is more coming, though, and soon. I have a fairly large and media laden post which is mostly written, but not yet bloggified, for instance. In the mean time, how about a small diversion?</p>

<p>Even if you know me in real life, you might not be aware of this small fact, for which I feel no shame whatsoever:</p>

<blockquote><p>Spider-man is my favourite fictional character.</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<p>There are various reasons for this. I love the iconography, I love the visuals, I love the character and the supporting characters. Most of all, though: I love the story, and if I have a couple of drinks in me I may wax lyrical about this at length (that's starting to make sense now, isn't it?). The previous set of films got some things right, but an awful lot wrong. Casting, for instance. I have hope for the currently in production reboot though, and just about everything I read about it or see raises this hope a little higher. Today, for instance, I saw this and it made me very happy indeed:</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/coolproduction/ckeditor_assets/pictures/382/original/spideygarbright.jpg?1295445386"></p>

<p>It's been enhanced in software, which is why the background looks so weird (you can find the original <a href="http://www.aintitcool.com/node/48136">here</a>), but it just looks so <em>right</em>. That's a picture of Peter Parker in the Spidey suit, likely having just had his ass handed to him. He's not stupidly muscled, because Spider-Man is supposed to be wiry, and furthermore: he's played by someone who acts well, looks the part and is actually capable of cracking a joke. What joy. Insert smiley face here.</p>

<p>While we're on the subject, the <a href="http://www.aintitcool.com/node/48139">recent casting</a> for the next Batman film makes me quite happy, as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
