<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: Joojoo | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://harveynick.com/blog/tags/joojoo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-28T17:11:56+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[...And Another Couple Of Things]]></title>
    <link href="http://harveynick.com/blog/2010/02/07/and-another-couple-of-things/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-07T22:16:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://harveynick.com/blog/2010/02/07/and-another-couple-of-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Something I forgot to mention in my last post was my trying to look at the iPad from a developer&rsquo;s perspective. I talked before about a programming side project that I&rsquo;ve had bouncing around in my head for a while. Previously, I mentioned that I wasn&rsquo;t sure if it was a website, an application, or some combination of the two. Then again I could see some use cases in which a laptop might be a bit cumbersome and a smart phone too small and underpowered. In which case neither the application of the website is entirely satisfactory. I&rsquo;m actually now starting to think that the iPad could be the exact right platform for it. Perhaps I should actually start working my way through the Objective-C text book I&rsquo;ve had sitting on my shelf for over a year now&hellip;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I have another couple of side projects, some programmery and some writery that have me giving the thing a more than slightly critical glance.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s not the point of this post, though. The fact of the matter is that, although it might sometimes seem that way, Apple does not have a monopoly on multi touch user interfaces. If you want to see a particularly impressive example that neither you nor I (nor the governments of some small countries, I suspect) can afford, look no further than the <a href="http://www.perceptivepixel.com/index.html">Perceptive Pixel</a> website. Another cool example showing someone playing with a multi-touch implementation of the Warcraft 3 real time strategy game can be found below:</p>

<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/KtKkOhMqVhY" width="" height="" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s the sort of thing Apple <em>should</em> have shown at their event, in my opinion. There&rsquo;s also another tablet doing the rounds called the &ldquo;Joojoo,&rdquo; which is apparently African for &ldquo;magic.&rdquo; You should be impressed already. I bet you didn&rsquo;t think &ldquo;African&rdquo; was a language, did ya? That was news to me, too. This tablet looks one hell of a lot like the iPad, but is has a 12.1" multitouch screen and features a flash supporting web browser. It costs about the same as the starting price of the iPad, also. Sounds like a better deal, you say? Unfortunately I just listed its entire feature list. Web browsing is all it does and it doesn&rsquo;t seem to have any capability for offline use. It also has a seriously dodgy past and it&rsquo;s makers are being sued as a result. What? You want to see it? Oh. Here:</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://realvision.ae/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/joojoo.jpg">http://realvision.ae/blog/wp-content/uploads/2009/12/joojoo.jpg</a>" title="&ldquo;The JooJoo&rdquo;" ></p>

<p>I think this device is kinda cool, but way too limited. Like the iPad, iPhone, and iPod Touch it features an onscreen soft keyboard&hellip; but now I very good one from what I&rsquo;ve seen. There&rsquo;s a <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2009/12/08/joojoo-tablet-hands-on-video/">video</a> of the company&rsquo;s CEO demonstrating the device and having a bit of trouble working the keyboard. Not a good sign. The hardware looks pretty cool though, the sort of thing a person might be tempted to buy with the intention of hacking. Not me though. I don&rsquo;t like having to act as my own tech support when it comes to the hardware and operating system.</p>

<p>Perhaps I&rsquo;m done talking about the iPad and it&rsquo;s ilk, and I&rsquo;ll soon find something else to prattle on about&hellip; or perhaps I&rsquo;ll be back soon with a bunch of use cases the think will have to fulfil in order for me to consider buying one, perhaps in the context of these side project I seem to refuse to go into any detail about. Alright, here&rsquo;s a clue which might have meaning to about one person reading this: Bad Penny.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
