<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: England | HarveyNick.com]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/tags/england/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-01T22:37:01+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.harveynick.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick Johnson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sasanach]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/10/04/sasanack/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-04T16:10:09+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.harveynick.com/blog/2008/10/04/sasanack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Helen's comment on my previous entry put me in mind of what I've felt as the Scottish attitude towards England and the English more or less ever since I arrived here (seven years ago!). It goes something like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>The English? Bastards! We hate 'em! Oh, but we're not talking about you, of course. Dear me, no. More tea? Scone?</p></blockquote>

<!-- more -->


<p>I am generalising massively here, but it is the case that though I've felt quite a bit of anti-English sentiment here (World Cup, anyone?), I've met seldom few who've had a problem with me because <em>I'm </em>English. The exceptions are a drunk old man out side the Cameo cinema (that encounter proved to be too humerous a story for me to bear him any real ill will) and a couple of drunk guys in a shady night club. The later was two separate events, with both unfolding more or less exactly like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>Him: You're English.<br/>
Me: Yes.<br/>
Him: What the fuck are you doing in Scotland, then?<br/>
Me: I might be English, but I chose to live in Scotland.<br/>
Him: Aye... well... fair play to you, then.</p></blockquote>

<p>Quite a reasonable outcome, I thought. Things might have been different If I'd said "I'm here for the football," or "I've come to have sex with your family," though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
